<?xml version='1.0' encoding='ISO-8859-1'?><!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
  "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">
<!-- $Id: applications.xml,v 1.8 2010-08-12 14:03:47 mg Exp $ -->

<chapter id="application">
<title>Additional applications</title>

<abstract>
<para>
You can install additional application packages to extend the functionality
of the OTRS framework.
You can install packages via the package manager in the adminarea. The package
manager downloads the applications from an online repository and manages package
dependencies. It is also possible to install packages from local files, in case
your OTRS system does not have a direct internet connection.
</para>
</abstract>

<section id="application-calendar">
<title>Calendar</title>

<para>
You can edit and view both private andr public user-based appointments With the web-based calendar.
</para>

<para>
<screenshot>
<screeninfo>Calendar</screeninfo>
<graphic srccredit="Calendar - screenshot" scale="40" fileref="screenshots/calendar.png"></graphic>
</screenshot>
</para>

</section>

<section id="application-contentmanager">
<title>Content manager</title>

<para>
The content manager lets you edit and administrate your web projects
online and via your web browser.
</para>

</section>

<section id="application-filemanager">
<title>File manager</title>

<para>
The file manager makes it possible to access the content of a directory that
is located in the file system of the machine where OTRS is installed. You
can use your web browser to upload, download, delete and view files, browse
and create subdirectories, etc.
</para>

<para>
<screenshot>
<screeninfo>File manager</screeninfo>
<graphic srccredit="Filemanager - screenshot" scale="40" fileref="screenshots/filemanager.png"></graphic>
</screenshot>
</para>

</section>

<section id="application-webmail">
<title>Web mailer</title>

<para>
With the webmailer you can access your mailbox via an IMAP server. It is
possible to compose new messages, answer and forward your mails, etc. simply
with your web browser.
</para>

<para>
<screenshot>
<screeninfo>Web mailer</screeninfo>
<graphic srccredit="Webmail - screenshot" scale="40" fileref="screenshots/webmail.png"></graphic>
</screenshot>
</para>

</section>

<section id="application-faq">
<title>FAQ</title>

<para>
The Knowledge Base component. It supports editing and viewing of FAQ
articles. Articles can be viewed and restricted to agents, customer users or
anonymous users. Articles can be structured in groups and have different
languages.
</para>

</section>

<section id="application-systemstatus">
<title>System status</title>

<para>
With the system status application the OTRS admin can give an overview of
different system tasks. The output of this module is reachable through the
adminarea of OTRS.
</para>

<para>
<screenshot>
<screeninfo>System status</screeninfo>
<graphic srccredit="Systemstatus - screenshot" scale="40" fileref="screenshots/systemstatus.png"></graphic>
</screenshot>
</para>

</section>

</chapter>
