<?xml version='1.0' encoding='ISO-8859-1'?>
<!DOCTYPE book PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
  "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">
<!-- $Id: applications.xml,v 1.2 2005-09-07 13:58:11 cs Exp $ -->

<chapter id="application">
<title>Additional applications</title>

<abstract>
<para>
Since OTRS 2.0 it is possible to install additional applications that can
be used with the central framework. The installation can be done with the
package manager via the adminarea. The package manager downloads the
applications from a online repository and takes care of package
dependencies.
</para>
</abstract>

<sect1 id="application-calendar">
<title>Calendar</title>

<para>
With the webbased calendar you can edit and view userbased appointments that
can be private or public.
</para>

<para>
<screenshot>
<screeninfo>Calendar</screeninfo>
<graphic srccredit="Calendar - screenshot" scale="40" fileref="screenshots/calendar.png"></graphic>
</screenshot>
</para>

</sect1>

<sect1 id="application-contentmanager">
<title>Content manager</title>

<para>
The content manager lets you edit and administrate your web projects
online and via your web browser..
</para>

</sect1>

<sect1 id="application-filemanager">
<title>File manager</title>

<para>
The file manager makes it possible to access the content of a directory that
is located in the file system of the machine where OTRS is installed. You
can use your web browser to upload, download, delete and view files, browse
and create subdirectories, e.g.
</para>

<para>
<screenshot>
<screeninfo>File manager</screeninfo>
<graphic srccredit="Filemanager - screenshot" scale="40" fileref="screenshots/filemanager.png"></graphic>
</screenshot>
</para>

</sect1>

<sect1 id="application-webmail">
<title>Web mailer</title>

<para>
With the webmailer you can access your mailbox via an IMAP server. It is
possible to compose new messages, answer and forward your mails, e.g., simply
with your web browser.
</para>

<para>
<screenshot>
<screeninfo>Web mailer</screeninfo>
<graphic srccredit="Webmail - screenshot" scale="40" fileref="screenshots/webmail.png"></graphic>
</screenshot>
</para>

</sect1>

<sect1 id="application-faq">
<title>FAQ</title>

<para>
The FAQ system is no seperate application at present and still integrated in
the central OTRS framework. It supports editing and viewing FAQ
articles. To improve browsing of the different articles, they can be
structured in cathegories and sorted by language.
</para>

</sect1>

<sect1 id="application-systemstatus">
<title>System status</title>

<para>
With the system status application the OTRS admin can get an overview on
different system tasks. The out put of this module is reachable through the
adminarea of OTRS.
</para>

<para>
<screenshot>
<screeninfo>System status</screeninfo>
<graphic srccredit="Systemstatus - screenshot" scale="40" fileref="screenshots/systemstatus.png"></graphic>
</screenshot>
</para>

</sect1>

</chapter>

