<?xml version='1.0' encoding='ISO-8859-1'?>
<!DOCTYPE book PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
  "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">
<!-- $Id: configuration.xml,v 1.2 2005-09-08 09:32:15 cs Exp $ -->

<chapter id="configuration">
<title>Configuring the system</title>

<sect1 id="directories-and-configfiles">
<title>The config files of OTRS</title>

<para>
All config files of OTRS are stored in the directory
<filename>Kernel</filename> or in sub directories below. There is no need
to change other files than <filename>Kernel/Config.pm</filename> manualy
because all other files will be changed when the system is upgraded. Just
copy the configuration parameters from the other files into
<filename>Kernel/Config.pm</filename> and change them to your needs,
<filename>Kernel/Config.pm</filename> will never be touched during the
upgrade process and your manual settings are save in this file.
</para>

<para>
The file <filename>Kernel/Config/Defaults.pm</filename> contains the
parameters of the central OTRS framework. All basic system
settings like the mail configuration, database connection, default charset
or standard language are located in this file. The file
<filename>Kernel/Config/Files/Ticket.pm</filename> contains all
configuration parameters for the trouble ticket system.
</para>

<para>
In the directory <filename>Kernel/Config/Files</filename> some more files
are stored that are parsed when the OTRS loginpage is accessed. If
additional applications like the web mailer or the file manager are
installed, the configuration files of these applications can be found in
<filename>Kernel/Config/Files</filename>. Because of compartibility reasons
to older OTRS versions, at present there is always a .pm- and a .xml file
for every application and for the central framework available. The .pm
files are needed to parse all default and your own settings, the .xml files
are used by the graphical configuration frontend which is available since
OTRS 2.0 and which lets you configure most of all configuration parameters
of the system through your web browser. In future versions of OTRS the .pm
files will be removed and the system will configurable only via the .xml
files. All parameters in <filename>Kernel/Config/Defaults.pm</filename>
will be moved to <filename>Kernel/Config/Files/Framework.xml</filename> and
all parameters for the trouble ticket system will be no longer stored in
<filename>Kernel/Config/Files/Ticket.pm</filename> but in
<filename>Kernel/Config/Files/Ticket.xml</filename>. The format of the
configuration parameters will completely change to xml.
</para>

<para>
If the web frontend of OTRS is accessed, all .xml files in the
<filename>Kernel/Config/Files</filename> directory are parsed in alphabetical
order and the settings for the central framework and additional
applications will be loaded. Afterwards the settings in the two files
<filename>Kernel/Config/Files/ZZZAAuto.pm</filename> and
<filename>Kernel/Config/Files/ZZZAuto.pm</filename> will be evaluated. Both
files are used by the graphical configuration frontend and should never be
changed manualy. At last the file <filename>Kernel/Config.pm</filename>
will be read out that contains your individual settings and manualy changed
configuration parameters. Reading out the configuration files in this order
makes sure that your specific configuration settings are used by the
system.
</para>

</sect1>

<sect1 id="sysconfig">
<title>Configuring the system through the web interface</title>

<para>
Since OTRS 2.0 nearly all configuration parameters of the central framework
or additionaly installed applications can be changed easyly with the graphical
configuration frontend. Log in as OTRS administrator and follow the
"SysConfig" link in the adminarea to execute the new configuration tool.
</para>

<para>
<screenshot>
<screeninfo>The graphical configuration frontend</screeninfo>
<graphic srccredit="sysconfig - screenshot" scale="40" fileref="screenshots/admin-sysconfig.png"></graphic>
</screenshot>
</para>

<para>
Because OTRS has more than 600 configuration parameters at this time, there
exist different ways to access a specific configuration parameter quickly.
With the full-text search all configuration parameters can be scaned for
one or more keywords. The full-text search not only searches through the
names of the configuration parameters, also the descriptions of the
parameters are scanned. This makes it possible to find a configuration
parameter, even if the name of the parameter is not known.
</para>

<para>
Furthermore all configuration parameters are sorted in main groups and sub
groups. The main group represents the application that the configuration
parameter belongs to, e.g. "Framework" for the central OTRS framework,
"Ticket" for the ticket system, "FAQ" for the FAQ system and so on. The sub
groups of a main group can be accessed, if the application is selected from
the groups listbox and the "Show" button is pressed.
</para>

<para>
Every configuration parameter can be turned on or of via a checkbox. If the
parameter is turned off, the system will no longer take care on this
parameter or the default is used. With the "Reset"-button it is possible to
switch a changed configuration parameter back to the system default. The
"Update"-button submits all changes and the system uses the new settings.
</para>

<para>
If you like to save all the changes you made to the configuration of the
system, you can download a .pm file that contains all system parameters
which differ from the default. To restore your own settings it is possible
to upload such a previously saved file, for example to setup a new
installed system quickly.
</para>

<note>
<para>
The configuration parameters for the database connection can not be changed
via the graphical configuration frontend for security reasons. They have to
be set manualy in <filename>Kernel/Config.pm</filename>.
</para>
</note>

</sect1>

</chapter>
