<?xml version='1.0' encoding='ISO-8859-1'?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
  "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">
<!-- $Id: email.xml,v 1.19 2010-11-12 12:09:18 mb Exp $ -->

<chapter id="email">
<title>Sending/Receiving emails</title>

<section id="email-sending">
<title>Sending emails</title>

<section id="email-sending-sendmail">
<title>Via Sendmail (default)</title>

<para>
OTRS can send out emails via Sendmail (e.g.
 <ulink url="http://www.sendmail.org/">Sendmail</ulink>,
 <ulink url="http://www.postfix.org/">Postfix</ulink>,
 <ulink url="http://www.qmail.org">Qmail</ulink> or
 <ulink url="http://www.exim.org">Exim</ulink>).
The default configuration is to use Sendmail and should work out of the box.
</para>

<para>
You can configure the sendmail settings via the graphical configuration
frontend (Framework::Core::Sendmail)
</para>

</section>

<section id="email-sending-smtp">
<title>Via SMTP server or smarthost</title>

<para>
OTRS can send emails via SMTP (
<ulink url="http://www.ietf.org/rfc/rfc821.txt">Simple Mail Transfer Protocol /
RFC 821</ulink>) or Secure SMTP. You will want to use this on non-UNIX
platforms (e.g. Windows).
</para>

<para>
The SMTP server settings can be configured via the SysConfig
(Framework::Core::Sendmail). If you don't see SMTPS available as an option, you
miss the required Perl modules. In that case, please refer to
<link linkend="installation-of-perl-modules">
"Installation of Perl modules required for OTRS"
</link> for instructions.</para>

</section>

</section>


<section id="email-receiving">
<title>Receiving emails</title>

<section id="email-receiving-pop3">
<title>Mail accounts configured via the OTRS GUI</title>

<para>
OTRS is able to receive emails from POP3, POP3S, IMAP, and IMAPS mail accounts.
</para>

<para>
Configure your mail accounts via the PostMaster Mail Accounts link in the admin interface.
</para>

<para>
If a new mail account is created (see Figure 7.1 below), then its mail server name, login
name and password must be specified. Also, you need to select the mail server type,
which can be POP3, POP3S, IMAP or IMAPS. If you don't see
server type you'd want to use  available as an option, you miss the required
Perl modules. In that case, please
refer to <link linkend="installation-of-perl-modules">
"Installation of Perl modules required for OTRS"
</link> for instructions.</para>

<para>
<screenshot>
<screeninfo>Adding a mail account</screeninfo>
<graphic srccredit="Adminarea postmaster - screenshot" scale="40" fileref="screenshots/add-mailaccount.png"></graphic>
</screenshot>
</para>

<para>
    <emphasis>Figure 7.1. Adding a mail account.</emphasis>
</para>

<para>If you select "Yes" for "Trusted", any X-OTRS headers attached to an
incoming message are evaluated and executed. Because the X-OTRS header can
execute some actions in the ticket system you should only set "Trusted" to
"Yes" for known senders. X-OTRS-Headers are used by the

<link linkend="adminarea-postmasterfilter">
filter module
</link>

in OTRS. The X-OTRS headers are explained

<link linkend="table-of-x-otrs-headers">
in this table
</link>

in more detail. Any postmaster filter rules you'd have created are executed
even if "Trusted" is set to "Yes".
</para>

<para>
The distribution of incoming messages can be controlled if they need to
be sorted by queue or by the content of the To: field. If "Dispatching by
selected queue" is selected for "Dispatching", all incoming messages will
be sorted into the specified queue. The address where the
mail was sent to is disregarded in this case.
If "Dispatching by email To: field" was
selected for "Dispatching", the system checks if a queue is linked with the
address in the To: field of the incoming mail. You can link an address in
the

<link linkend="adminarea-emailaddresses">
E-mail address management
</link>

section of the admin area. If the address in the To field is linked with a
queue, the new message will be sorted into the linked queue. If no link is found
between the address in the To: field and queue then the message is
sorted into the "Raw" queue in the system, which is the

<link linkend="Ticket:Core::PostMaster:PostmasterDefaultQueue">
PostmasterDefaultQueue
</link>

after a default installation.
</para>

<para>
All data for the mail accounts are saved in the OTRS database. The
<filename>otrs.PostMasterMailbox.pl</filename> script, which is located in the
<filename>bin</filename> directory of your OTRS installation, uses the
settings in the database and fetches the mail. You can execute
<filename>./bin/otrs.PostMasterMailbox.pl</filename> manually to check if all your
mail settings are working properly.
</para>

<para>
On a normal installation, the mail will be fetched every 10 minutes
by the <filename>postmaster_mailbox</filename> cron job. For further information about
modifying cron jobs, please refer to the
<link linkend="cronjobs">
cron jobs
</link> chapter.
</para>

<note>
<para>
When fetching mail OTRS deletes the mail from the POP or IMAP server. There's no
option to also keep a copy on the server. If you'd want to achieve this, you'd
probably best create forwarding rules on your mail server. Please consult your
mail server documentation for details.
</para>
</note>
</section>


<section id="email-receiving-cmd">
<title>Via command line program and e.g. procmail (otrs.PostMaster.pl)</title>

<para>
If you can't use mail accounts to get the email into OTRS, the command line
program <filename>bin/otrs.PostMaster.pl</filename> might be a solution. It
takes the mails via STDIN and pipes
them directly into OTRS. That means email will be available in your OTRS system
if the MDA (mail delivery agent, e.g. procmail) executes this program.
</para>

<para>
To test <filename>bin/otrs.PostMaster.pl</filename> without MDA, execute the command
of the Script 7.1.
</para>

<para>
<screen>
linux:/opt/otrs# cd bin
linux:/opt/otrs/bin# cat ../doc/sample_mails/test-email-1.box | ./otrs.PostMaster.pl
linux:/opt/otrs/bin#
</screen>
</para>

<para>
    <emphasis>Script 7.1. Testing PostMaster withouth MDA.</emphasis>
</para>

<para>
If the email is shown in the QueueView, then your setup is working.
</para>

<para>
Procmail is a very common e-mail filter in Linux environments. It will be
installed on most systems. If not, have a look at the
<ulink url="http://www.procmail.org/"><citetitle>procmail homepage</citetitle></ulink>.
</para>

<para>
To configure procmail for OTRS (requires a procmail configured MTA, e.g.
sendmail, postfix, exim or qmail), use the
<filename>~otrs/.procmailrc.dist</filename> file and copy it to
<filename>.procmailrc</filename> and add the lines of the Script 7.2.
</para>

<para>
<programlisting>
SYS_HOME=$HOME
PATH=/bin:/usr/bin:/usr/local/bin
# --
# Pipe all email into the PostMaster process.
# --
:0 :
| $SYS_HOME/bin/otrs.PostMaster.pl
</programlisting>
</para>

<para>
    <emphasis>Script 7.2. Configuring procmail for OTRS.</emphasis>
</para>

<para>
All email sent to the local OTRS user will be piped into
<filename>bin/otrs.PostMaster.pl</filename> and then shown in your QueueView.
</para>

</section>


<section id="email-receiving-fetchmail">
<title>Fetching emails via POP3 or IMAP and fetchmail for otrs.PostMaster.pl</title>

<para>
In order to get email from your mail server, via a POP3 or IMAP mailbox, to
the OTRS machine/local OTRS account and to procmail, use
<ulink url="http://fetchmail.berlios.de/">fetchmail</ulink>.
</para>

<note>
<para>
A working SMTP configuration on the OTRS machine is required.
</para>
</note>

<para>
You can use the <filename>.fetchmailrc.dist</filename> in the home
directory of OTRS and copy it to <filename>.fetchmailrc</filename>.
Modfiy/change it for your needs (see the Example 7-1 below).
</para>

<example id='fetchmailrc'>
<title>.fetchmailrc</title>

<para>
<programlisting>
#poll (mailserver) protocol POP3 user (user) password (password) is (localuser)
poll mail.example.com protocol POP3 user joe password mama is otrs
</programlisting>
</para>

</example>

<para>
Don't forget to set the .fetchmailrc to 710 ("chmod 710 .fetchmailrc")!
</para>

<para>
With the <filename>.fetchmailrc</filename> from the Example 7-1 above, all email
will be forwarded to the local OTRS account, if the command
<command>fetchmail -a</command> is executed. Set up a cronjob with this
command if you want to fetch the mails regularly.
</para>
</section>


<section id="email-receiving-filter">
<title>Filtering/dispatching by OTRS/PostMaster modules (for more complex
dispatching)</title>

<para>
If you use the bin/otrs.PostMaster.pl or bin/otrs.PostMasterMailbox.pl method,
you can insert or modify X-OTRS header entries with the PostMaster filter modules.
With the X-OTRS headers, the ticket system can execute some actions on
incoming mails, sort them into a specific queue, change the priority or
change the customer ID, for example. More information about the X-OTRS
headers are available in the chapter about

<link linkend="adminarea-postmasterpop3-account">
adding mail accounts
</link>

in the admin area of OTRS.
</para>

<para>
There are some default filter modules:
</para>

<note>
<para>
The job name (e.g.
$Self-&gt;{'PostMaster::PreFilterModule'}-&gt;{'JobName'}) needs to be unique!
</para>
</note>

<para>
Kernel::System::PostMaster::Filter::Match is a default module to
match on some email header (e.g. From, To, Subject, ...). It can set
new email headers (e.g. X-OTRS-Ignore: yes or X-OTRS-Queue: spam) if a
filter rule matches. The jobs of the Example 7-2 can be inserted in
<filename>Kernel/Config.pm</filename>
</para>

<example id='filter-module-match-example'>
<title>Example jobs for the filter module Kernel::System::PostMaster::Filter::Match</title>

<para>
<programlisting>
    # Job Name: 1-Match
    # (block/ignore all spam email with From: noreply@)
    $Self-&gt;{'PostMaster::PreFilterModule'}-&gt;{'1-Match'} = {
        Module =&gt; 'Kernel::System::PostMaster::Filter::Match',
        Match =&gt; {
            From =&gt; 'noreply@',
        },
        Set =&gt; {
            'X-OTRS-Ignore' =&gt; 'yes',
        },
    };
    # Job Name: 2-Match
    # (sort emails with From: sales@example.com and Subject: **ORDER**
    # into queue 'Order')
    $Self-&gt;{'PostMaster::PreFilterModule'}-&gt;{'2-Match'} = {
        Module =&gt; 'Kernel::System::PostMaster::Filter::Match',
        Match =&gt; {
            To =&gt; 'sales@example.com',
            Subject =&gt; '**ORDER**',
        },
        Set =&gt; {
            'X-OTRS-Queue' =&gt; 'Order',
        },
    };
</programlisting>
</para>

</example>

<para>
Kernel::System::PostMaster::Filter::CMD is a default module to
pipe the email into an external command. The output is given to STDOUT and
if the result is true, then set new email header (e.g. X-OTRS-Ignore: yes
or X-OTRS-Queue: spam). The Example 7-3 can be used in
<filename>Kernel/Config.pm</filename>
</para>

<example id='filter-module-cmd-example'>
<title>Example job for the filter module Kernel::System::PostMaster::Filter::CMD</title>

<para>
<programlisting>
    # Job Name: 5-SpamAssassin
    # (SpamAssassin example setup, ignore spam emails)
    $Self-&gt;{'PostMaster::PreFilterModule'}-&gt;{'5-SpamAssassin'} = {
        Module =&gt; 'Kernel::System::PostMaster::Filter::CMD',
        CMD =&gt; '/usr/bin/spamassassin | grep -i "X-Spam-Status: yes"',
        Set =&gt; {
            'X-OTRS-Ignore' =&gt; 'yes',
        },
    };
</programlisting>
</para>

</example>

<para>
Of course it's also possible to develop your own PostMaster filter modules.
</para>

</section>

</section>

</chapter>
