<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">
<!-- $Id: monitoring-tickets.xml,v 1.9 2010-12-01 13:03:28 mg Exp $ -->
<chapter id="monitoring-tickets" >
<title>Ticket responsibility and ticket watching</title>

<para>
From OTRS 2.1 on, it is possible to define a person responsible for a ticket,
additionally to its owner. Moreover, all activities connected with the
ticket can be watched. These two functionalities are implemented with
the TicketResponsible and TicketWatcher features, and facilitate the
assignment of tasks and working within hierarchic team structures.
</para>


<section id="ticket-responsible" >
<title>Ticket responsibility</title>

<para>
The ticket responsible feature facilitates the complete processing of a ticket
by an agent, other then the ticket owner. Thus an agent who has locked a
ticket can pass it on to another agent, who is not the ticket owner, in order for
the second to respond to a customer request. After the request has been dealt
with, the first agent can withdraw the ticket responsibility from the
second agent.
</para>

<para>
With the configuration parameter

<link linkend="Ticket:Core::Ticket:Ticket::Responsible" >
Ticket::Responsible
</link>

, the ticket responsible feature can be activated. This will cause that 3 new icons appear
in your toolbar.
</para>

<para>
Ticket responsibility can be assigned by calling up the ticket content and
clicking on the "Responsible" link in the actions bar of a zoomed ticket in
the agent interface (see the Figure 9.1 below).
</para>

<para>
<screenshot>
<screeninfo>Ticket-Zoom with Responsible Menu</screeninfo>
<graphic srccredit="index.pl - screenshot" scale="40" fileref="screenshots/ticket-zoom-responsible.png"></graphic>
</screenshot>
</para>

<para>
    <emphasis>Figure 9.1. Changing the responsible of a ticket in its zoomed view.</emphasis>
</para>

<para>
After clicking on "Responsible", a pop-up to change the responsible of that ticket
will open (see Figure 9.2 below). This template can also be used to send a message to the
new responsible agent.
</para>

<para>
<screenshot>
<screeninfo>Ticket-Responsible Menu</screeninfo>
<graphic srccredit="index.pl - screenshot" scale="40" fileref="screenshots/ticket-responsible.png"></graphic>
</screenshot>
</para>

<para>
    <emphasis>Figure 9.2. Change a ticket's responsible pop-up.</emphasis>
</para>

<para>
The list of all tickets for which an agent is responsible from, can be accessed
through the Responsible View, which is shown as 3 icons in the toolbar of the OTRS
agent interface, as soon as the
ticket responsible feature gets activated.
</para>

</section>


<section id="ticket-watcher">
<title>Ticket watching</title>

<para>
From OTRS 2.1 on, agents (e.g. heads of department) can watch
certain tickets within the system without processing them, by using the
TicketWatcher feature.
</para>

<para>
The TicketWatcher feature can be activated with the configuration
parameter

<link linkend="Ticket:Core::TicketWatcher:Ticket::Watcher">
Ticket::Watcher
</link>

, which will add 3 new icons to your toolbar. Using

<link linkend="Ticket:Core::TicketWatcher:Ticket::WatcherGroup">
Ticket::WatcherGroup
</link>

one or more user groups with permission to watch tickets can be defined.
</para>

<para>
In order to watch a ticket, go to its zoomed view and click on the
"Subscribe" link in the ticket activities menu (see Figure 9.3 below).
</para>

<para>
<screenshot>
<screeninfo>Ticket-Zoom with subscribe menu</screeninfo>
<graphic srccredit="index.pl - screenshot" scale="40" fileref="screenshots/ticket-subscribe.png"></graphic>
</screenshot>
</para>

<para>
    <emphasis>Figure 9.3. Subscribing to a ticket in its zomed view.</emphasis>
</para>

<para>
If you no longer want to watch a specific ticket, go to its zoomed view and click on the
"Unsubscribe" link in the ticket activities menu (see Figure 9.4 below).
</para>

<para>
<screenshot>
<screeninfo>Ticket-Zoom with unsubscribe menu</screeninfo>
<graphic srccredit="index.pl - screenshot" scale="40" fileref="screenshots/ticket-unsubscribe.png"></graphic>
</screenshot>
</para>

<para>
    <emphasis>Figure 9.4. Unsubscribing from a ticket in its zomed view.</emphasis>
</para>

<para>
The list of all watched tickets can be accessed through the Watched View (see Figure 9.5 below),
which is shown as 3 icons in the toolbar of the OTRS agent interface, as soon as the
ticket watcher feature gets activated.
</para>


<para>
<screenshot>
<screeninfo>Mailbox: Watched tickets</screeninfo>
<graphic srccredit="index.pl - screenshot" scale="40" fileref="screenshots/ticket-subscribe-mailbox.png"></graphic>
</screenshot>
</para>

<para>
    <emphasis>Figure 9.5. Watched tickets view.</emphasis>
</para>
</section>

</chapter>
