<?xml version='1.0' encoding='ISO-8859-1'?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
    "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">
<!-- $Id: otrs.xml,v 1.8.2.2 2007-10-24 18:10:08 cs Exp $ -->

<chapter id="otrs">
<title>OTRS - Open Ticket Request System</title>

<abstract>
<para>
This chapter describes the features of the Open Ticket Request System
(OTRS). You will find informations about the hardware and software
requirements for OTRS. Additionally, this chapter tells you how to get
commercial support for OTRS, should you require it, and how to contact the
community.
</para>
</abstract>

<sect1 id="otrs-basics">
<title>Basics</title>

<para>
The Open Ticket Request System (OTRS) is a web application which can be
used with every HTML-compatible web browser. The web interface of OTRS
does not use active web content like Flash or Java applets to ensure that the
system is usable with mobile phones or other mobile computers. To use
OTRS, no special client operating system is necessary; only an HTML
browser is needed.
</para>

<para>
OTRS is separated into several components. The basic component is the
OTRS framework that contains all central functions for the application and the
ticket system. Via the web interface of the central OTRS framework, it is
possible to install additional applications like a web mailer, a content
manager, a file manager, a web calendar and a tool to monitor system status
information.
</para>
</sect1>

<sect1 id="features-of-otrs">
<title>Features</title>

<para>
OTRS has many features. The following list gives an overview of the features
included in the central framework.
</para>

<itemizedlist>
  <title>The features of OTRS</title>
  <listitem>
    <para>
    Web interface:
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Easy and initial handling with a web browser.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Because no active web contents like Flash or Java applets are used,
        the web interface is usable with most web browsers, even
        with mobile phones or other mobile computers.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        A web interface to administer the system via the web is available.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        A web interface to handle customer requests by employees/agents via the
        web is integrated.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        A web interface for customers is available to write new tickets, check the state
        and answer old tickets and search through their own tickets.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        The web interface can be customized with different themes; own themes
        can be integrated.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Support for many languages.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        The appearance of output templates can be customized (dtl).
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Mails from and into the system can contain multiple attachments.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </listitem>
  <listitem>
    <para>
    Mail interface:
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Support for mail attachments (MIME support).
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Automatic conversion of HTML into plain text messages (more
        security for dangerous content and enables faster searching).
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Mail can be filtered with the X-OTRS headers of the system or via
        mail addresses, e.g. for spam messages.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        PGP support, creation and import of own keys, signing and
        encrypting outgoing mail, signed and encrypted messages can
        be displayed.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Support for viewing and encrypting SMIME messages, handling of
        SMIME certificates.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Auto answers for customers, configurable for every queue.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Email notifications for agents about new tickets, follow-ups or
        unlocked tickets.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Follow-ups by references or In-Reply-To header entries.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </listitem>
  <listitem>
    <para>
    Tickets:
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Expanded queue view, fast overview of new requests in a queue.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Tickets can be locked.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Creation of own auto answer templates.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Creation of own auto responders, configurable for every queue.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Ticket history, overview of all events for a ticket (changes of
        ticket states, replies, notes, etc.).
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Print view for tickets.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Adding own (internal or external) notes to a ticket (text and
        attachments).
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Ticket zooming.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Access control lists for tickets can be defined.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Forwarding or bouncing tickets to other mail adresses.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Moving tickets between queues.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Changing/setting the priority of a ticket.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        The working time for every ticket can be counted.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Up-coming tasks for a ticket can be defined (pending features).
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Bulk actions on tickets are possible.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Automatic and timed actions on tickets are possible with the
        "GenericAgent".
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Full text search on all tickets is possible.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </listitem>
  <listitem>
    <para>
    System:
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
	    <para>
        OTRS runs on many operating systems (Linux, Solaris, AIX,
	    FreeBSD, OpenBSD, Mac OS 10.x, Microsoft Windows).
	    </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        ASP support (active service providing).
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Linking several objects is possible, e.g. tickets and FAQ entries.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Integration of external back-ends for the customer data, e.g. via
        AD, eDirectory or OpenLDAP.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Setting up an own ticket identifier, e.g.
        Cal#, Ticket#, Request#, e.g.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        The integration of your own ticket counter is possible.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Support of several database systems for the central OTRS back-end,
        e.g. MySQL, PostgreSQL, SAPDB, Oracle).
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Framework to create stats.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        utf-8 support for the front- and back-end.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Authentication for customers via
        database, LDAP, HTTPAuth or Radius.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Support of user accounts, user groups and roles.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Support of different access levels for several systems
        components or queues.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Integration of standard answer texts.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Support of sub queues.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Different salutations and signatures can be defined for every
        queue.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Email notifications for admins.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Information on updates via mail or the web interface.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Escalation for tickets.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Support for different time zones.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Simple integration of own add-ons or applications with the OTRS API.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Simple creation of own front-ends, e.g. for X11, console.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </listitem>
</itemizedlist>
</sect1>

<sect1 id="software-requirements">
<title>Hard and software requirements</title>

<para>
OTRS can be installed on many operating systems. OTRS runs not only on
linux and on other unix derivates (e.g. OpenBSD or FreeBSD) but on
all Microsoft Windows platforms too. OTRS has no excessive hardware requirements. We
recommend using a machine with at least a 2 GHz Xeon or comparable
CPU, 2 GB RAM and a 160 GB hard drive.
</para>

<para>
If you want to use OTRS, you need some other software components. The basic
software requirements are a web and a database server as well as a working
perl environment with some additional modules. The web server and
<application>perl</application> has to be installed on the same machine
as OTRS. The database back-end can be installed on the local or on an other
host.
</para>

<para>
For the web server, we recommend using <application>apache 1.3.x</application>
or <application>apache 2.x</application>. With this web server, you can use
the mod_perl module which improves greatly the performance of OTRS.
If you can't use apache, OTRS should run on any web server
that can execute perl scripts.
</para>

<para>
For database back-ends, we recommend to use <application>MySQL</application>
(3.1.x or higher) or <application>PostgreSQL</application>.
However, all database servers that use SQL for their database language should be
able to work with OTRS. If you use <application>MySQL</application> you
have the advantage that you can configure your database and some system
settings during the installation through a web front-end.
</para>

<para>
For <application>perl</application>, we recommend using at least version
5.8. You need some additional modules which can be installed either with
the perl shell and CPAN or via the package manager of your operating system
(<application>rpm</application>, <application>yast</application>,
<application>apt-get</application>).
</para>

<para>
The section on the

<link linkend="installation-of-needed-perl-modules">
manual installation of perl modules needed
</link>

describes in more detail how you can set up the perl modules that you need for
OTRS.
</para>

<para>
If you install a binary package of OTRS, which was built for your operating
system (rpm, Windows-Installer), either the package contains all perl
modules needed or the package manager of your system should take care of the
dependences of the perl modules needed.
</para>
</sect1>

<sect1 id="community">
<title>Community</title>

<para>
OTRS has a large user community. users and developers discuss OTRS and exchange information on the
trouble ticket system Via

<link linkend="additional-resources-mailinglists">
mailinglists
</link>

. There is available help for questions about the installation,
configuration, usage, localisation and development. Software bugs
can be reported via a

<link linkend="additional-resources-bugtracking">
bug tracking system
</link>

so that they reach the responsible developers directly and without getting
lost. That ensures that fixes for problems
are available very quick.
</para>

<para>
<screenshot>
<screeninfo>Homepage OTRS.org</screeninfo>
<graphic srccredit="Homepage OTRS.org" scale="40" fileref="screenshots/homepage-otrs.png"></graphic>
</screenshot>
</para>

<para>
Via the URL

<ulink url="http://www.otrs.org">
<citetitle>http://www.otrs.org</citetitle>
</ulink>

you can reach the homepage of the OTRS community.
</para>
</sect1>

<sect1 id="commercial-support-for-otrs">
<title>Commercial Support for OTRS</title>

<para>
Commercial support for OTRS is also available. Via the URL

<ulink url="http://www.otrs.com">
<citetitle>http://www.otrs.com</citetitle>
</ulink>

the pages of the OTRS AG can be reached, representing the commercial
part of the OtRS.org project.
</para>

<para>
The OTRS AG provide support, consulting and training for the Open Ticket
Request System. It also provides easy-to-handle complete solutions.
With these packages, the OTRS AG would like to serve medium-sized companies, local
authorities, institutions and big corporate groups. You can either buy
ready-made high-performance and high-availability systems or order special
made-to-measure packages.
</para>

<para>
On

<ulink url="http://www.otrs.com">
<citetitle>http://www.otrs.com</citetitle>
</ulink>

are available more detailed information about the OTRS AG. You can
contact the OTRS AG per email to

<ulink url="mailto:sales at otrs.com">
<citetitle>sales at otrs.com</citetitle>
</ulink>

</para>
</sect1>

</chapter>
