<?xml version='1.0' encoding='ISO-8859-1'?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
    "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">
<!-- $Id: otrs.xml,v 1.25 2009-04-22 08:23:25 martin Exp $ -->

<chapter id="otrs">
<title>OTRS - Open Ticket Request System</title>

<abstract>
<para>
This chapter describes the features of the Open Ticket Request System
(OTRS). You will find informations about the hardware and software
requirements for OTRS. Additionally, this chapter tells you how to get
commercial support for OTRS, should you require it, and how to contact the
community.
</para>
</abstract>

<sect1 id="otrs-basics">
<title>Basics</title>

<para>
The Open Ticket Request System (OTRS) is a web application which can be
used with every HTML-compatible web browser. The web interface of OTRS
does not use active web content like Flash or Java applets to ensure that the
system is usable with mobile phones or other mobile computers. To use
OTRS, no special client operating system is necessary; only an HTML
browser is needed.
</para>

<para>
OTRS is separated into several components. The basic component is the
OTRS framework that contains all central functions for the application and the
ticket system. Via the web interface of the central OTRS framework, it is
possible to install additional applications like a web mailer, a content
manager, a file manager, a web calendar and a tool to monitor system status
information.
</para>
</sect1>

<sect1 id="features-of-otrs">
<title>Features</title>

<para>
OTRS has many features. The following list gives an overview of the features
included in the central framework.
</para>

<itemizedlist>
  <title>The features of OTRS</title>
  <listitem>
    <para>
    Web interface:
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Easy and initial handling with a web browser.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Because no active web contents like Flash or Java applets are used,
        the web interface is usable with most web browsers, even
        with mobile phones or other mobile computers.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        A web interface to administer the system via the web is available.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        A web interface to handle customer requests by employees/agents via the
        web is integrated.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        A web interface for customers is available to write new tickets, check the state
        and answer old tickets and search through their own tickets.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        The web interface can be customized with different themes; own themes
        can be integrated.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Support for many languages.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        The appearance of output templates can be customized (dtl).
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Mails from and into the system can contain multiple attachments.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </listitem>
  <listitem>
    <para>
    Mail interface:
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Support for mail attachments (MIME support).
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Automatic conversion of HTML into plain text messages (more
        security for dangerous content and enables faster searching).
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Mail can be filtered with the X-OTRS headers of the system or via
        mail addresses, e.g. for spam messages.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        PGP support, creation and import of own keys, signing and
        encrypting outgoing mail, signed and encrypted messages can
        be displayed.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Support for viewing and encrypting SMIME messages, handling of
        SMIME certificates.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Auto answers for customers, configurable for every queue.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Email notifications for agents about new tickets, follow-ups or
        unlocked tickets.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Follow-ups by references or In-Reply-To header entries.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </listitem>
  <listitem>
    <para>
    Tickets:
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Expanded queue view, fast overview of new requests in a queue.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Tickets can be locked.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Creation of own auto answer templates.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Creation of own auto responders, configurable for every queue.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Ticket history, overview of all events for a ticket (changes of
        ticket states, replies, notes, etc.).
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Print view for tickets.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Adding own (internal or external) notes to a ticket (text and
        attachments).
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Ticket zooming.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Access control lists for tickets can be defined.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Forwarding or bouncing tickets to other mail adresses.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Moving tickets between queues.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Changing/setting the priority of a ticket.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        The working time for every ticket can be counted.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Up-coming tasks for a ticket can be defined (pending features).
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Bulk actions on tickets are possible.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Automatic and timed actions on tickets are possible with the
        "GenericAgent".
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Full text search on all tickets is possible.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </listitem>
  <listitem>
    <para>
    System:
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        OTRS runs on many operating systems (Linux, Solaris, AIX,
        FreeBSD, OpenBSD, Mac OS 10.x, Microsoft Windows).
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        ASP support (active service providing).
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Linking several objects is possible, e.g. tickets and FAQ entries.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Integration of external back-ends for the customer data, e.g. via
        AD, eDirectory or OpenLDAP.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Setting up an own ticket identifier, e.g.
        Call#, Ticket# or Request#.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        The integration of your own ticket counter is possible.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Support of several database systems for the central OTRS back-end,
        e.g. MySQL, PostgreSQL, Oracle, DB2).
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Framework to create stats.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        utf-8 support for the front- and back-end.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Authentication for customers via
        database, LDAP, HTTPAuth or Radius.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Support of user accounts, user groups and roles.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Support of different access levels for several systems
        components or queues.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Integration of standard answer texts.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Support of sub queues.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Different salutations and signatures can be defined for every
        queue.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Email notifications for admins.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Information on updates via mail or the web interface.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Escalation for tickets.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Support for different time zones.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Simple integration of own add-ons or applications with the OTRS API.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Simple creation of own front-ends, e.g. for X11, console.
        </para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </listitem>
</itemizedlist>

<sect2 id="new-features-of-2.4">
<title>New features of OTRS 2.4</title>

<itemizedlist>
<title>Licensing changed to AGPL Version 3</title>

<listitem>
<para>
Why AGPL instead of GPL? - AGPL and GPL are identical, with one exception: For software used in an SaaS environment Copyleft is effective in AGPL - which is not the case when using GPL. Keeping in mind the growing world of SaaS, ((otrs)) wants to ensure that future developments continue to return to the OTRS community. This is the reason for the switch to AGPL.
</para>

<para>
Why v3 instead of v2? - GPL v2 is getting older and has, especially in the USA, various legal uncertainties. In the opinion of ((otrs)) GPL v3 is keeping the spirit of GPL v2, and at the same time has been tailored to new needs. ((otrs)) views GPLv3, more specifically AGPLv3, as being the best balanced Copyleft Open Source License available today, offering Protection for copyright owners and users and providing the best security under the law.
</para>
</listitem>

</itemizedlist>

<itemizedlist>
<title>New Management Dashboard</title>

<listitem>
<para>
The need for a system-spanning, next to real-time, and personalized presentation of useful information led to an integrated Management Dashboard. It is possible to create plug-ins to display content from individual extensions alongside the standard content. Standard plug-ins are:
</para>
</listitem>

<listitem>
    <para>
Ticket volume (new &amp; open) from the last 24h, 48h and 72h
    </para>
</listitem>

<listitem>
    <para>
Calendar including an overview of upcoming events (escalations, auto-unlocks, etc.)
    </para>
</listitem>

<listitem>
    <para>
System-wide overview of ticket distribution within the queues
    </para>
</listitem>

<listitem>
    <para>
First Response Time/Solution Time of Queues
    </para>
</listitem>

<listitem>
    <para>
Integration of RSS
    </para>
</listitem>

</itemizedlist>


<itemizedlist>
<title>New Standard Reports</title>

<listitem>
<para>
The new reports provided with OTRS 2.4 are:
</para>
</listitem>

<listitem>
    <para>
Created Tickets
    </para>
</listitem>

<listitem>
    <para>
Closed Tickets
    </para>
</listitem>

<listitem>
    <para>
SLA Analysis
    </para>
</listitem>

<listitem>
    <para>
Required working time per customer / per queue
    </para>
</listitem>

<listitem>
    <para>
Solution time analysis per customer / per queue
    </para>
</listitem>

<listitem>
    <para>
Answer time analysis per customer / per queue
    </para>
</listitem>

</itemizedlist>


<itemizedlist>
<title>New Master/Slave Ticket Feature</title>

<listitem>
<para>
With the Master/Slave Ticket, it is possible to link multiple tickets of a similar nature, and handle them collectively. As soon as the problem is solved, only the master ticket must be closed. All other tickets will be closed automatically, and the solution text for the master ticket will be sent to all customers of slave tickets.
</para>

<para>
A new link type 'Slave' will be available. All tickets with this Type of link will inherit the following actions from their Master ticket:
</para>
</listitem>

<listitem>
    <para>
Status change
    </para>
</listitem>

<listitem>
    <para>
Email answers
    </para>
</listitem>

<listitem>
    <para>
Change in FreeText fields
    </para>
</listitem>

<listitem>
    <para>
Notes
    </para>
</listitem>

<listitem>
    <para>
Pending time changes
    </para>
</listitem>

<listitem>
    <para>
Priority changes
    </para>
</listitem>

<listitem>
    <para>
Owner changes
    </para>
</listitem>

<listitem>
    <para>
Responsibility changes
    </para>
</listitem>


</itemizedlist>


<itemizedlist>
<title>New Rich-Text/HTML E-Mail Support (WYSIWYG)</title>

<listitem>
<para>
With this feature, it is now possible to write e-mails, notes, and notifications in rich text format (HTML format). Using a WYSIWIG editor (What You See Is What You Get), it is possible to comfortably write using formatted text and even include inline pictures.
</para>
</listitem>

</itemizedlist>


<itemizedlist>
<title>New Out-Of-Office Feature</title>

<listitem>
    <para>
With this new feature it is possible for all users to activate "out-of-office" to notify colleagues and OTRS of the period of their absence. The out-of-office feature is active for a time frame set by the user. Activation of this feature has the following effects:
    </para>
    <para>
In the lists in which an agent can be selected as owner or reponsible (i.e. Ticket creation or changing ownership), the period of absence and the time till return will be shown behind the user's name. This will help making the absence of the user more transparent.
    </para>
    <para>
If an agent receives a follow-up during a period of absence, the ticket is automatically unlocked and a notifcation is sent to all agents in the queue. This allows immediate reaction to the customer follow-up by another service employee.
    </para>
</listitem>

</itemizedlist>

<itemizedlist>
<title>New Ticket Overviews and global Bulk Action</title>

<listitem>
    <para>
Flexibility of presentation within the ticket overview is a must. Based on the "S/M/L" (Small/Medium/Large) Ticket View every agent has the possibility to change the view for each type of overview (Queue View, Status View, etc) on-the-fly with a simple mouse click on the appropriate icon. This allows for the highest possible level of individualization and adjustment to any operational situation.
    </para>
    <para>
Additionally, decentralization of the Bulk Action feature integrated the Bulk Action in all ticket overviews (Bulk Action allows processing of multiple tickets at a time).
    </para>
</listitem>

</itemizedlist>

<itemizedlist>
<title>Postmaster Filter recognizes Follo-Ups to internal forwarded messages</title>

<listitem>
    <para>
Currently, e-mail replies to forwarded articles arrive in OTRS as email-external. The problem is that the answers to these forwarded articles can be seen by the customer in the web- interface. Although it is possible to classify e-mails of an entire domain as email-internal, this only shifts the problem. Also, such step makes it impossible to properly service customers in the domain, as the customer would not be able to track tickets in the customer web-interface any more. With this new feature, e-mail replies can be traced back, and email- internal or email-external will be set based upon the original Forward-Article type.
    </para>
</listitem>

</itemizedlist>

<itemizedlist>
<title>READ-ONLY Permissions and Notifications with watched Tickets</title>

<listitem>
    <para>
In the current release of OTRS it is possible for a user to maintain a Watched Tickets List. This feature is dealing with tickets marked as "subscribed" by a user. It has the advantage that users no longer lose track of tickets marked as "sub- scribed", and are able to view them on an individual list. The "Read-Only" Feature - Up to now, tickets marked as "sub- scribed" were shown in a list, however, the agent could only actually view them if they were in a queue for which the agent had read permissions. With the "Read-Only" Feature, agents subscribed to a ticket always have read permissions on the ticket, even if the ticket is moved to a queue where the agent has no permissions. "Notify" Feature - Via a personalized setting, every agent can define whether or not to receive notifications about tickets, just as the owner and responsible of a ticket would receive. This allows for active tracking of watched tickets.
    </para>
</listitem>

</itemizedlist>

<itemizedlist>
<title>Secure SMTP</title>

<listitem>
    <para>
OTRS can receive and send mails in multiple ways. All currently available methods for receiving emails have been implemented within OTRS 2.3 (POP3,POP3S,IMAP,IMAPS). Until now, there were two options for sending emails: using a local MTA (Sendmail, Postfix, etc.) or per SMTP. In OTRS 2.4.x, SMTPS (Sercure SMTP) has been implemented in order to keep up to the growing security standards.
    </para>
</listitem>

</itemizedlist>

</sect2>


<sect2 id="new-features-of-2.3">
<title>New features of OTRS 2.3</title>

<itemizedlist>
<title>Performance</title>

<listitem>
    <para>
        Data base- and code-improvements increase lead to a general performance gain of up to 20%.
    </para>
</listitem>

<listitem>
    <para>
        The support of an indexed full text search has been added. The feature is disabled per
        default because additional disc space is needed. The expected performance gain is 50%.
    </para>
</listitem>

<listitem>
    <para>
        Reduced reloads by using AJAX technology.
    </para>
</listitem>

<listitem>
    <para>
        Instead of an ongoing recalculating of the escalation time
        during the run time, it is only recalculated when it changes
        due to an event in OTRS. It is then being stored in the ticket
        object which allows a direct access of external reporting
        tools to the data base as well as a more efficient reporting
        on escalations. This will also lead into a substantial
        performance improvement.
    </para>
</listitem>
</itemizedlist>

<itemizedlist>
<title>Search functionality</title>
<listitem>
    <para>
        Support of logical expressions: ticket-, customer- and FAQ-
        search supports logical expressions, utilizing the AND, OR
        and ! operators as well as structuring expressions with
        parentheses.
    </para>
</listitem>

<listitem>
    <para>
        Search for ticket numbers by using the Browser OpenSearch
        feature (OpenSearch format).
    </para>
</listitem>

<listitem>
    <para>
        Search for ticket titles in the agent ticket search form
        and in the generic agent.
    </para>
</listitem>

<listitem>
    <para>
        Search for ticket close time in the agent ticket search form
        and in the generic agent.
    </para>
</listitem>
</itemizedlist>

<itemizedlist>
<title>Ticket zoom and ticket move</title>
<listitem>
    <para>
        Expand/Collapse of articles: the article view can be expanded
        to display all articles at once. The current article will
        remain in focus, and the preceding, or following articles will
        be displayed.
    </para>
</listitem>

<listitem>
    <para>
        Structured article tree - The article tree has been changed
        to a table.
    </para>
</listitem>

<listitem>
    <para>
        Printing of articles has been realized.
    </para>
</listitem>

<listitem>
    <para>
        The ticket title of linked tickets are displayed in case of a
        mouse over action.
    </para>
</listitem>

<listitem>
    <para>
        Merged tickets are displayed crossed out.
    </para>
</listitem>

<listitem>
    <para>
        Multiple files can be attached while moving a ticket using the
        ticket move mask.
    </para>
</listitem>
</itemizedlist>

<itemizedlist>
<title>Ticket FreeText and FreeTime opportunities</title>
<listitem>
    <para>
        When splitting a ticket, all FreeText and Free Time data will
        be copied to the new ticket.
    </para>
</listitem>

<listitem>
    <para>
        Ticket Free Time fields can be declared as mandatory.
    </para>
</listitem>

<listitem>
    <para>
        A URL can be configured that takes the value of a FreeText
        field and displays it as an URL link in the ticket.
    </para>
</listitem>

<listitem>
    <para>
        Added X-OTRS-TicketTime and X-OTRS-FollowUp-TicketTime email headers.
    </para>
</listitem>
</itemizedlist>

<itemizedlist>
<title>IMAP, IMAPS and POP3S support</title>
<listitem>
    <para>
        With OTRS 2.3 additionally to POP3, POP3S, IMAP and IMAPS is supported to fetch
        mails from your MTA.
    </para>
</listitem>
</itemizedlist>

<itemizedlist>
<title>Security</title>
<listitem>
    <para>
        In case of a lost password, OTRS is sending an e-mail to the
        user with a "password reset link". After clicking this link
        the new password is sent to the user in a second e-mail.
    </para>
</listitem>
</itemizedlist>

<itemizedlist>
<title>Notifications and escalations</title>
<listitem>
    <para>
        All agents that have a read permission on a certain queue can
        be selected for notification.
    </para>
</listitem>

<listitem>
    <para>
        An escalation view has been added that displays all tickets
        sorted by their remaining time to escalation.
    </para>
</listitem>
</itemizedlist>
</sect2>


<sect2 id="new-features-of-2.2">
<title>New features of OTRS 2.2</title>

<itemizedlist>
<title>New features of OTRS 2.2</title>

<listitem>
    <para>
    Support of Services and SLAs:
    As major step towards IT Servicemanagement OTRS 2.2 brings in the new
    attributes 'Service' and 'Service Level Agreements (SLA)'. While creating
    a new ticket a service requester has to select both a service
    (e. g. email-service)
    and a related SLA . SLA attributes are "response time", "update time" and
    "solution time". These attributes are used by the IT Service Organization
    for notification and escalation purposes in order to keep the agreed SLA.
    Service- and SLA-related informations within incoming email headers might
    also be used by the Postmaster-Filter as already known before.
    </para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
    <para>
    Support of native ticket types: Ticket types can now be managed over the admin interface. You
    do not longer need to use ticket free text field for this purpose.
    Installations which already use a ticket free text field for ticket type
    classification do not need to migrate. This feature will also be shown in
    zoom and print view for agents and customers and can be changed via the
    agent interface.
    </para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
    <para>
    Support of multiple authentication backends: Added support of multi authentication feature for agent and customer backend.
    By using this feature it is now possible to use multiple trusted
    authentication sources (i.e. use LDAP as a first source for authentification and in case
    of an
    unsuccessful authentification try a SQL DB as a second source).
    </para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
    <para>
    Support of different password crypt types:
    Supported and permitted password authentication types for agent and/or customer
    login are:
    </para>

    <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
        <para>unix_crypt()</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
        <para>md5()</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
        <para>plain()</para>
    </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>

    <para>
    Default is 'unix_crypt()'. The administrator can easily switch from unix_crypt()
    to md5() on the fly by changing the related configuration parameter.
    </para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
    <para>
    Changed OTRS internal CustomerUser structure:
    Customer datas (CustomerUser) are restructured and split into the objects
    "CustomerCompany" and "CustomerUser" within the internal OTRS database. Company
    related attributes like company name and address will be managed separately from
    those attributes related to a single contact (e.g. prename, surname, phone etc.).
    </para>

    <para>
    This information will be shown in zoom and print like the current customer info.
    </para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
    <para>
    Enhanced OPM-Format: OPM Packages are now delivered with an additional online help. The introducing
    page will inform the user about new features and will also give a short
    overview about the next steps to do after having installed the packages.
    </para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
    <para>
    PostMaster-Admin-Interface: The improvement has lead to a more detailled definition of those email adresses
    which have to be matched by PostMaster filter.
    </para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
    <para>
    SysConfig Improvement: A quicker page view and page saving leads to essential time savings during
    configuration process.
    </para>
</listitem>
</itemizedlist>

</sect2>


<sect2 id="new-features-of-2.1">
<title>New features of OTRS 2.1</title>

<itemizedlist>
<title>New features of OTRS 2.1</title>

<listitem>
    <para>
    Stable Support of MicrosoftRSQL Server: The first time OTRS offers an
    interface to MS SQL Server platforms. Thatþs why OTRS supports all
    popular operating systems like Linux, Windows, UNIX, Mac OS X etc. as
    well as all major Databases like MS SQL, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Oracle and DB2.
    </para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
    <para>
    Multi-Calender Function: This Feature simplifies working in distributed
    surroundings. National teams are supported by permitting different local
    working schedules and public holiday regulations. International
    organiszations are additionally supported by a time-zone feature.
    </para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
    <para>
    New Statistics-Framework: Gain access and define your Reports- and
    Statistics in a more flexible way than ever. A powerful and easy to use
    Wizard will guide you through the process. Once defined OTRS may deliver
    periodicaly needed Reports automatically to a predefined Mailing List.
    Export- and Importfunctions allow to transfer Statistics between
    different OTRS Installations. So you can define and test your Statistics
    before loading them up to your productive System.
    </para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
    <para>
    Optimized Synchronization of authorizations from LDAP-Directory Services:
    That simplifies the connection of all known LDAP-Directory Services like
    Microsoft Active Directory, OpenLDAP, Novell eDirectory, Oracle Internet
    Directory, etc. A usefull Feature which saves time and effort of
    maintaining authorizations in the local Database of OTRS.
    </para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
    <para>
    PDF-Generator: OTRS now supports the Output of Reports and Statistics
    as well as the results of a ticket search and ticket zoom in the
    PDF-Format.
    </para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
    <para>
    New implemented Knowledge Database / FAQ-Module: OTRS makes allowance
    for the need of an efficient Knowledge Management within daily Service
    Request handling. Fundamental in this context is a quick access towards
    existing problem-solving Know-How and standardized answers. Advantages:
    optimized search-functions, more
    effective administration of FAQ-Articles, faster Navigation and
    opportunities to rate an existing FAQ-Article.
    </para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
    <para>
    Tracking of Sub-orders and Support of hierarchical Team-Structures:
    New Features like the Ticket Supervisor and the Ticket Watchers
    support working within hierarchical Teams and enable you to define and
    depute Work packages temporarily to another Service Agent. While the
    Ticket Supervisor enables authorized Team members to depute a Ticket to
    another Service Agent without loosing the right to edit this ticket the
    Ticket Watcher allows you to track a ticket passive on the basis of an
    individual watchlist.
    </para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
    <para>
    Optimized Follow-Up-Detection: In addition to the subject heading, OTRS
    also checks for referable ticket numbers inside the Email-body and further
    attachments. This new feature aims to automatically assign an incoming
    Service Request to an existing Incident much faster than before.
    </para>
</listitem>
</itemizedlist>

</sect2>




</sect1>

<sect1 id="software-requirements">
<title>Hard and software requirements</title>

<para>
OTRS can be installed on many operating systems. OTRS runs not only on
linux and on other unix derivates (e.g. OpenBSD or FreeBSD) but on
all Microsoft Windows platforms too. OTRS has no excessive hardware requirements. We
recommend using a machine with at least a 2 GHz Xeon or comparable
CPU, 2 GB RAM and a 160 GB hard drive.
</para>

<para>
If you want to use OTRS, you need some other software components. The basic
software requirements are a web and a database server as well as a working
Perl environment with some additional modules. The web server and
<application>Perl</application> has to be installed on the same machine
as OTRS. The database back-end can be installed on the local or on an other
host.
</para>

<para>
For the web server, we recommend using <application>apache 2</application>. With this web server, you can use
the mod_perl module which improves greatly the performance of OTRS.
If you can't use apache, OTRS should run on any web server
that can execute Perl scripts.
</para>

<para>
For database back-ends, you can use <application>MySQL</application>,
 <application>PostgreSQL</application>, <application>Oracle</application>,
<application>MSSQL</application> or <application>DB2</application>.
If you use <application>MySQL</application> you
have the advantage that you can configure your database and some system
settings during the installation through a web front-end.
</para>

<para>
For <application>Perl</application>, we recommend using at least version
5.8.8. You need some additional modules which can be installed either with
the Perl shell and CPAN or via the package manager of your operating system
(<application>rpm</application>, <application>yast</application>,
<application>apt-get</application>).
</para>

<para>Software requirements</para>

<para>Perl</para>
    <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
        <para>Perl 5.8.8 or higher</para>
    </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>

<para>Webserver</para>
    <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
        <para>Webserver with CGI support (CGI is not recommended)</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
        <para>Apache2+mod_perl2 or higher (recommended, mod_perl is really fast!)</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
        <para>IIS6 or higher</para>
    </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>

<para>Databases</para>
    <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
        <para>MySQL 4.1 or higher</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
        <para>PostgreSQL 8.0 or higher</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
        <para>Oracle 10g or higher</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
        <para>DB2 8 or higher</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
        <para>MSSQL 2000 or higher</para>
    </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>

<para>
The section on the

<link linkend="installation-of-needed-perl-modules">
manual installation of Perl modules needed
</link>

describes in more detail how you can set up the Perl modules that you need for
OTRS.
</para>

<para>
If you install a binary package of OTRS, which was built for your operating
system (rpm, Windows-Installer), either the package contains all Perl
modules needed or the package manager of your system should take care of the
dependences of the Perl modules needed.
</para>
</sect1>

<sect1 id="community">
<title>Community</title>

<para>
OTRS has a large user community. users and developers discuss OTRS and exchange information on the
trouble ticket system Via

<link linkend="additional-resources-mailinglists">
mailinglists
</link>

. There is available help for questions about the installation,
configuration, usage, localisation and development. Software bugs
can be reported via a

<link linkend="additional-resources-bugtracking">
bug tracking system
</link>

so that they reach the responsible developers directly and without getting
lost. That ensures that fixes for problems
are available very quick.
</para>

<para>
<screenshot>
<screeninfo>Homepage OTRS.org</screeninfo>
<graphic srccredit="Homepage OTRS.org" scale="40" fileref="screenshots/homepage-otrs.png"></graphic>
</screenshot>
</para>

<para>
Via the URL

<ulink url="http://www.otrs.org">
<citetitle>http://www.otrs.org</citetitle>
</ulink>

you can reach the homepage of the OTRS community.
</para>
</sect1>

<sect1 id="commercial-support-for-otrs">
<title>Commercial Support for OTRS</title>

<para>
Commercial support for OTRS is also available. Via the URL

<ulink url="http://www.otrs.com">
<citetitle>http://www.otrs.com</citetitle>
</ulink>

the pages of the OTRS AG can be reached, representing the commercial
part of the OtRS.org project.
</para>

<para>
The OTRS AG provide support, consulting and training for the Open Ticket
Request System. It also provides easy-to-handle complete solutions.
With these packages, the OTRS AG would like to serve medium-sized companies, local
authorities, institutions and big corporate groups. You can either buy
ready-made high-performance and high-availability systems or order special
made-to-measure packages.
</para>

<para>
On

<ulink url="http://www.otrs.com">
<citetitle>http://www.otrs.com</citetitle>
</ulink>

are available more detailed information about the OTRS AG. You can
contact the OTRS AG per email to

<ulink url="mailto:sales at otrs.com">
<citetitle>sales at otrs.com</citetitle>
</ulink>

</para>
</sect1>

</chapter>
