<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
    "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">
<!-- $Id: otrs.xml,v 1.50.2.1 2013-02-06 14:33:35 mg Exp $ -->

<chapter id="otrs">
<title>OTRS Help Desk</title>

<abstract>
    <para>
        This chapter describes the features of OTRS Help Desk
        (OTRS). You will find information about the hardware and software
        requirements for OTRS. Additionally, this chapter tells you how to get
        commercial support for OTRS, should you require it, and how to contact the
        community.
    </para>
</abstract>

<section id="otrs-basics">
    <title>Basics</title>

    <para>
        OTRS Help Desk (OTRS) is a web application which is installed on a web
        server and can be used with a web browser.
    </para>

    <para>
        OTRS is separated into several components. The basic component is the
        OTRS framework that contains all central functions for the application and the
        ticket system. Via the web interface of the OTRS framework, it is
        possible to install additional applications such as ITSM modules, integrations
        with Network Monitoring solutions, a knowledge base (FAQ), et cetera.
    </para>
</section>

<section id="features-of-otrs">
    <title>Features</title>

    <para>
        OTRS has many features. The following list gives an overview of the features
        included in the central framework.
    </para>

    <itemizedlist>
      <title>The features of OTRS</title>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Web interface:
        </para>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Easy and initial handling with any modern web browser,
            even with mobile phones or other mobile computers.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            A web interface to administer the system via the web is available.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            A web interface to handle customer requests by employees/agents via the
            web is integrated.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            A web interface for customers is available to write new tickets, check the state
            and answer old tickets and search through their own tickets.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            The web interface can be customized with different themes; own themes
            can be integrated.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Support for many languages.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            The appearance of output templates can be customized (dtl).
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Mails from and into the system can contain multiple attachments.
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Mail interface:
        </para>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Support for mail attachments (MIME support).
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Automatic conversion of HTML into plain text messages (more
            security for dangerous content and enables faster searching).
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Mail can be filtered with the X-OTRS headers of the system or via
            mail addresses, e.g. for spam messages.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            PGP support, creation and import of own keys, signing and
            encrypting outgoing mail, signed and encrypted messages can
            be displayed.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Support for viewing and encrypting S/MIME messages, handling of
            S/MIME certificates.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Auto answers for customers, configurable for every queue.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Email notifications for agents about new tickets, follow-ups or
            unlocked tickets.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Follow-ups by references or In-Reply-To header entries.
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Tickets:
        </para>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Expanded queue view, fast overview of new requests in a queue.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Tickets can be locked.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Creation of own auto answer templates.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Creation of own auto responders, configurable for every queue.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Ticket history, overview of all events for a ticket (changes of
            ticket states, replies, notes, etc.).
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Print view for tickets.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Adding own (internal or external) notes to a ticket (text and
            attachments).
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Ticket zooming.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Access control lists for tickets can be defined.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Forwarding or bouncing tickets to other mail addresses.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Moving tickets between queues.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Changing/setting the priority of a ticket.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            The working time for every ticket can be counted.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Up-coming tasks for a ticket can be defined (pending features).
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Bulk actions on tickets are possible.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Automatic and timed actions on tickets are possible with the
            "GenericAgent".
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Full text search on all tickets is possible.
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        System:
        </para>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            OTRS runs on many operating systems (Linux, Solaris, AIX,
            FreeBSD, OpenBSD, Mac OS 10.x, Microsoft Windows).
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            ASP support (active service providing).
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Linking several objects is possible, e.g. tickets and FAQ entries.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Integration of external back-ends for the customer data, e.g. via
            AD, eDirectory or OpenLDAP.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Setting up an own ticket identifier, e.g.
            Call#, Ticket# or Request#.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            The integration of your own ticket counter is possible.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Support of several database systems for the central OTRS back-end,
            e.g. MySQL, PostgreSQL, Oracle, MSSQL).
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Framework to create stats.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            utf-8 support for the front- and back-end.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Authentication for customers via
            database, LDAP, HTTPAuth or Radius.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Support of user accounts, user groups and roles.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Support of different access levels for several systems
            components or queues.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Integration of standard answer texts.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Support of sub queues.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Different salutations and signatures can be defined for every
            queue.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Email notifications for admins.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Information on updates via mail or the web interface.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Escalation for tickets.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Support for different time zones.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Simple integration of own add-ons or applications with the OTRS API.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Simple creation of own front-ends, e.g. for X11, console.
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>

    <section id="new-features-of-3.1">
        <title>New features of OTRS 3.1</title>

        <section>
            <title>GENERIC INTERFACE - A Web Service Framework</title>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>GI is a flexible framework to allow web service interconnections of OTRS with third party applications.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>OTRS can act in both ways - as a provider (server, requested from remote) or requester (client, requesting remotely).</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Simple web service connections can be created without programming by configuring the Generic Interface.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Complex scenarios can be realized by plugging in custom OTRS extensions that add perl code to the GI infrastructure on different
                        architectural layers.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        <emphasis>Connectors</emphasis> expose parts of OTRS to Generic Interface web services.For example, a ticket connector exposes the ticket
                        create/update function, so that they can be used in a web service regardless which network transport is used.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>A scheduler daemon process supports asynchronous event handling. This is useful to asynchronously start web service requests from OTRS
                        to another system, after the agents request has been answered (e.g. when a ticket has been created). Otherwise, it might block the response,
                        resulting in increased response times for the agent.</para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
            <para>
            With the Generic Interface new web services can be configured easily by using existing OTRS modules, without additional code. They can be combined to
            create a new web service. When configuring a new web service connection, the administrator has to add:
            </para>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>A new web service in the admin GUI</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>The basic meta data (Transport type (SOAP), URL etc.) and</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Existing operations (part of a connector) and specify for each operation how the data must be mapped (inbound and outbound)</para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
            <para>
            A Generic Interface Debugger will help the OTRS administrator to check how requests are coming in and how they are handled through the different
            layers.
            </para>
            <section>
                <title>Current Features</title>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Network transports: SOAP/HTTP. Others like REST and JSON are scheduled to be added in the future depending on customers demand.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Configurable data mapping Graphical User Interface for key/value transformations with respect to incoming and outgoing data.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Graphical debugger to check the configuration and flow of information of configured web services.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>A ticket connector allowing the use of OTRS as a web service for ticket handling.</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </section>
            <section>
                <title>Future Features</title>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Additional network transports (REST, JSON).</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>The GI will replace the iPhoneHandle as the backend for mobile apps.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Additional connectors will be added to provide more parts of OTRS for use with web services (e.g. to allow the creation, update or
                            deletion of agents, users, services or CIs).</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </section>
        </section>

        <section>
            <title>DYNAMIC FIELDS</title>
            <para>The DynamicFields Feature replaces the existing ticket and article
            FreeText and FreeTime fields with a dynamic structure that will also allow to create custom forms in OTRS.
            </para>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>An unlimited amount of fields can be configured using an own graphical user interface for administration.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>The fields can have different types that can be used for both, tickets and articles. Available by default are:</para>
                    <itemizedlist>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Text</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Multiline text</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Checkbox</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Dropdown</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Multi-select</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Date</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Date and time</para>
                        </listitem>
                    </itemizedlist>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>New custom field types (e.g. custom field type dropdown with an external data source) can be added with small effort as the fields are
                        created in a modular, pluggable way.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>A future scenario is, that DynamicFields can be used for objects other than tickets or in custom modules. For example, a custom module
                        adding objects to handle "orders" in OTRS could use the DynamicFields to attach properties/data to these orders.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        A database update script will transform historic FreeText fields and related configuration settings into the new structure.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </section>

        <section>
            <title>TICKET MANAGEMENT IMPROVEMENTS</title>
            <section>
                <title>Ticket creation improved</title>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Multiple email addresses can now be specified as 'To:', 'CC:' or 'BCC:' when creating a new phone or email ticket.</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </section>
            <section>
                <title>Inbound phone call support</title>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Inbound phone calls can now be registered within an existing tickets (until now, only outbound calls were registered).</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </section>
            <section>
                <title>Ticket overview preview improved</title>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>It is now possible to exclude articles of certain sender types (e.g. articles from internal agents) in the SysConfig from being
                            displayed in the overview preview mode.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>A certain article type can be configured which will display articles of that type as expanded by default when the view is accessed.</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </section>
            <section>
                <title>Ticket move improved</title>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>The screen shown after moving a ticket is now configurable. Options are the ticket zoom view (LastScreenView) or the ticket list
                            (LastScreenOverview).</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </section>
            <section>
                <title>Bulk action improved</title>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>With the new bulk action, outbound emails can now be sent from multiple tickets at the same time. As tickets can have different queues,
                            and these queues each can have different templates, salutations and signatures, these are not used in the Bulk Action email.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>An additional bulk action allows configuring the ticket type for selected tickets.</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </section>
            <section>
                <title>Configurable Reject Sender Email Address</title>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>The feature allows configuring an email address instead of the administrator address to reject the creation of new tickets by email.
                            This feature can be used in all cases where customers are not allowed to create new tickets by email.</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </section>
        </section>

        <section>
            <title>PROCESS AUTOMATION</title>
            <section>
                <title>Escalation events added</title>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>OTRS will now create events for each of the available escalation types (response, update and resolution). This allows performing
                            actions (such as notifications) before the escalation occurs, in the moment it occurs and in the moment that the escalation ends.</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </section>
            <section>
                <title>Notification mechanism improved</title>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>A new generic agent notification module allows the OTRS administrator to define messages that will be shown in the agent web front-end
                            when agents log into the system.</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </section>
            <section>
                <title>Time calculation improved</title>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>All kind of times are from now on calculated by and based on the application server only solving the issues that were caused by
                            variances between the clock times of application and data base servers.</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </section>
            <section>
                <title>GenericAgent improved</title>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>The GenericAgent can now filter for tickets change time.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>In addition, the GenericAgent can set the ticket responsible for matched tickets.</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </section>
        </section>

        <section>
            <title>USER INTERFACE, RICH TEXT EDITOR, CHARSET</title>
            <section>
                <title>User interface performance improved</title>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>The speed for rendering and article display was improved, thanks to Stelios Gikas &lt;stelios.gikas@noris.net&gt;!</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </section>
            <section>
                <title>Rich Text Editor Update</title>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>IOS5 support added.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Block quotes can be left with the enter key.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>
                            Update from CKEditor 3.4 to CKEditor 3.6, so improvements refer to the releases of
                            <ulink url="http://ckeditor.com/blog/CKEditor_3.5_released">CKEditor 3.5</ulink> and
                            <ulink url="http://ckeditor.com/blog/CKEditor_3.6_released">CKEditor 3.6</ulink>.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>IE9 support improved.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Resizable dialogs.</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </section>
            <section>
                <title>Unicode Support - Non-UTF-8 Internal Encodings Dropped</title>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>UTF-8 is now the only allowed internal charset of OTRS.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>All language files are now formatted in UTF-8, which simplifies their handling and future improvements of the translation mechanism.</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </section>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>DATABASE DRIVER SUPPORT</title>
            <section>
                <title>PostgreSQL DRIVER compatibility improved</title>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>PostgreSQL 9.1 support added.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>A new legacy driver is now available for PostgreSQL 8.1 or earlier versions.</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </section>
            <section>
                <title>MS SQL DRIVER compatibility improved</title>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>The MS SQL driver now stores binary data in VARBINARY rather than deprecated type TEXT as well as NVARCHAR to store text strings rather
                            than VARCHAR (for improved Unicode support).</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </section>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>MAIL INTEGRATION</title>
            <section>
                <title>Mail handling improved</title>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>When connecting to IMAP mail accounts, it is now possible to handle emails from a specific email folder, other than the INBOX folder.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>OTRS can now also connect to IMAP servers using Transport Layer Security (TLS), useful for modern restricted environments.</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </section>
        </section>
    </section>

    <section id="new-features-of-3.0">
        <title>Top new features of OTRS 3.0</title>

        <itemizedlist>
            <title>Context</title>
            <listitem>
                <para>
    User Centered redesign of the Graphical User Interface which
    results in a dramatic shift from a comprehensive but static
    to a more powerful and dynamic application using state-of-the
    art technologies like Ajax, xHTML and optimized CSS.
                </para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <itemizedlist>
            <title>New Ticket and Article Indicator</title>
            <listitem>
                <para>
    This new feature has been implemented on both ticket and article level.
    It allows an agent at a glance to check for any updates within a ticket
    or on the article level to check for new and unread articles. You
    benefit from increased transparency and decreased response times.
                </para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <itemizedlist>
            <title>Optimized Fulltext Search</title>
            <listitem>
                <para>
    The new search feature allows you to flexibly customize the way you browse
    the information base. Options the new search feature provides range from
    single search-string searches to complex multi-string boolean search
    operations including various operators. You benefit from fully
    customizable searches according to your needs.
                </para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <itemizedlist>
            <title>New Ticket Zoom View</title>
            <listitem>
                <para>
    The redesign based on Ajax technology
    allows agents to display complex and linked information
    structures in real-time while keeping the agents' current
    working environment. The agent will benefit from increased
    orientation and increased workflow efficiency.
                </para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <itemizedlist>
            <title>Global Ticket Overviews</title>
            <listitem>
                <para>
    Well known from OTRS 2.4 the global
    ticket overviews have been optimized to achieve increased inter-
    activity. Depending on the use case and preferences of your
    agents they can easily change the ticket overviews layout
    according to their special needs. Options are small, medium
    and large, each providing a different degree of information
    details.
                </para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>


        <itemizedlist>
            <title>Accessibility</title>
            <listitem>
                <para>
    The redesign includes common accessibility standards WCAG and
    WAI-ARIA which also allows disabled users to better interact
    with OTRS Help Desk. The US Rehabilitation Acts Section 508 has
    been fulfilled.
                </para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <itemizedlist>
            <title>New Customer Interface</title>
            <listitem>
                <para>
    The customer web front-end can be integrated to your organizations
    intranet and is fully integrated into the redesigned help desk system.
                </para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <itemizedlist>
            <title>Archive Feature</title>
            <listitem>
                <para>
    OTRS 3.0 now offers a new archiving feature. With a separated archive
    you'll benefit from a reduced time spent for searches and increased
    display of results.
                </para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

    </section>


    <section id="new-features-of-2.4">
    <title>New features of OTRS 2.4</title>

    <itemizedlist>
    <title>Licensing changed to AGPL Version 3</title>

    <listitem>
    <para>
    Why AGPL instead of GPL? - AGPL and GPL are identical, with one exception: For software used in an SaaS environment Copyleft is effective in AGPL - which is not the case when using GPL. Keeping in mind the growing world of SaaS, ((otrs)) wants to ensure that future developments continue to return to the OTRS community. This is the reason for the switch to AGPL.
    </para>

    <para>
    Why v3 instead of v2? - GPL v2 is getting older and has, especially in the USA, various legal uncertainties. In the opinion of ((otrs)) GPL v3 is keeping the spirit of GPL v2, and at the same time has been tailored to new needs. ((otrs)) views GPLv3, more specifically AGPLv3, as being the best balanced Copyleft Open Source License available today, offering Protection for copyright owners and users and providing the best security under the law.
    </para>
    </listitem>

    </itemizedlist>

    <itemizedlist>
    <title>New Management Dashboard</title>

    <listitem>
    <para>
    The need for a system-spanning, next to real-time, and personalized presentation of useful information led to an integrated Management Dashboard. It is possible to create plug-ins to display content from individual extensions alongside the standard content. Standard plug-ins are:
    </para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
        <para>
    Ticket volume (new &amp; open) from the last 24h, 48h and 72h
        </para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
        <para>
    Calendar including an overview of upcoming events (escalations, auto-unlocks, etc.)
        </para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
        <para>
    System-wide overview of ticket distribution within the queues
        </para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
        <para>
    First Response Time/Solution Time of Queues
        </para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
        <para>
    Integration of RSS
        </para>
    </listitem>

    </itemizedlist>


    <itemizedlist>
    <title>New Standard Reports</title>

    <listitem>
    <para>
    The new reports provided with OTRS 2.4 are:
    </para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
        <para>
    Created Tickets
        </para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
        <para>
    Closed Tickets
        </para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
        <para>
    SLA Analysis
        </para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
        <para>
    Required working time per customer / per queue
        </para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
        <para>
    Solution time analysis per customer / per queue
        </para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
        <para>
    Answer time analysis per customer / per queue
        </para>
    </listitem>

    </itemizedlist>


    <itemizedlist>
    <title>New Master/Slave Ticket Feature</title>

    <listitem>
    <para>
    With the Master/Slave Ticket, it is possible to link multiple tickets of a similar nature, and handle them collectively. As soon as the problem is solved, only the master ticket must be closed. All other tickets will be closed automatically, and the solution text for the master ticket will be sent to all customers of slave tickets.
    </para>

    <para>
    A new link type 'Slave' will be available. All tickets with this Type of link will inherit the following actions from their Master ticket:
    </para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
        <para>
    Status change
        </para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
        <para>
    Email answers
        </para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
        <para>
    Change in FreeText fields
        </para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
        <para>
    Notes
        </para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
        <para>
    Pending time changes
        </para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
        <para>
    Priority changes
        </para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
        <para>
    Owner changes
        </para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
        <para>
    Responsibility changes
        </para>
    </listitem>


    </itemizedlist>


    <itemizedlist>
    <title>New Rich-Text/HTML E-Mail Support (WYSIWYG)</title>

    <listitem>
    <para>
    With this feature, it is now possible to write e-mails, notes, and notifications in rich text format (HTML format). Using a WYSIWYG editor (What You See Is What You Get), it is possible to comfortably write using formatted text and even include in-line pictures.
    </para>
    </listitem>

    </itemizedlist>


    <itemizedlist>
    <title>New Out-Of-Office Feature</title>

    <listitem>
        <para>
    With this new feature it is possible for all users to activate "out-of-office" to notify colleagues and OTRS of the period of their absence. The out-of-office feature is active for a time frame set by the user. Activation of this feature has the following effects:
        </para>
        <para>
    In the lists in which an agent can be selected as owner or responsible (i.e. Ticket creation or changing ownership), the period of absence and the time till return will be shown behind the user's name. This will help making the absence of the user more transparent.
        </para>
        <para>
    If an agent receives a follow-up during a period of absence, the ticket is automatically unlocked and a notification is sent to all agents in the queue. This allows immediate reaction to the customer follow-up by another service employee.
        </para>
    </listitem>

    </itemizedlist>

    <itemizedlist>
    <title>New Ticket Overviews and global Bulk Action</title>

    <listitem>
        <para>
    Flexibility of presentation within the ticket overview is a must. Based on the "S/M/L" (Small/Medium/Large) Ticket View every agent has the possibility to change the view for each type of overview (Queue View, Status View, etc) on-the-fly with a simple mouse click on the appropriate icon. This allows for the highest possible level of individualization and adjustment to any operational situation.
        </para>
        <para>
    Additionally, decentralization of the Bulk Action feature integrated the Bulk Action in all ticket overviews (Bulk Action allows processing of multiple tickets at a time).
        </para>
    </listitem>

    </itemizedlist>

    <itemizedlist>
    <title>Postmaster Filter recognizes Follow-Ups to internal forwarded messages</title>

    <listitem>
        <para>
    Currently, e-mail replies to forwarded articles arrive in OTRS as email-external. The problem is that the answers to these forwarded articles can be seen by the customer in the web- interface. Although it is possible to classify e-mails of an entire domain as email-internal, this only shifts the problem. Also, such step makes it impossible to properly service customers in the domain, as the customer would not be able to track tickets in the customer web-interface any more. With this new feature, e-mail replies can be traced back, and email- internal or email-external will be set based upon the original Forward-Article type.
        </para>
    </listitem>

    </itemizedlist>

    <itemizedlist>
    <title>Configurable event based notifications</title>

    <listitem>
        <para>
    Until now, a very inflexible notification could be sent to an agents and customers, for example Agent: New Ticket or Customer: Status Change. In order to make the notification system more flexible, a complete overhaul was performed on the messaging mechanism. The new system allows messaging to agents, customers, or a dedicated email address, based on the event taking place.
        </para>
        <para>
    With this, it is now possible to just inform the customer when the ticket has been closed. Or, for example, when a VIP customer creates a ticket, a message can be sent to a specific address. Events (i.e. TicketCreate, TicketStateUpdate, TicketPriorityUpdate, ArticleCreate), and all known message variables (i.e. &lt;OTRS_TICKET_TicketNumber&gt; &lt;OTRS_TICKET_Priority&gt;), are freely selectable for creating triggered messages via the web interface.
        </para>
    </listitem>

    </itemizedlist>


    <itemizedlist>
    <title>READ-ONLY Permissions and Notifications with watched Tickets</title>

    <listitem>
        <para>
    In the current release of OTRS it is possible for a user to maintain a Watched Tickets List. This feature is dealing with tickets marked as "subscribed" by a user. It has the advantage that users no longer lose track of tickets marked as "sub- scribed", and are able to view them on an individual list. The "Read-Only" Feature - Up to now, tickets marked as "sub- scribed" were shown in a list, however, the agent could only actually view them if they were in a queue for which the agent had read permissions. With the "Read-Only" Feature, agents subscribed to a ticket always have read permissions on the ticket, even if the ticket is moved to a queue where the agent has no permissions. "Notify" Feature - Via a personalized setting, every agent can define whether or not to receive notifications about tickets, just as the owner and responsible of a ticket would receive. This allows for active tracking of watched tickets.
        </para>
    </listitem>

    </itemizedlist>

    <itemizedlist>
    <title>Secure SMTP</title>

    <listitem>
        <para>
    OTRS can receive and send mails in multiple ways. All currently available methods for receiving emails have been implemented within OTRS 2.3 (POP3,POP3S,IMAP,IMAPS). Until now, there were two options for sending emails: using a local MTA (Sendmail, Postfix, etc.) or per SMTP. In OTRS 2.4.x, SMTPS (Secure SMTP) has been implemented in order to keep up to the growing security standards.
        </para>
    </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>

    </section>

</section>

<section id="software-requirements">
    <title>Hardware and software requirements</title>

    <para>
    OTRS can be installed on many different operating systems. OTRS can run on
    linux and on other unix derivates (e.g. OpenBSD or FreeBSD). You can also deploy
    it on Microsoft Windows. OTRS does not have excessive hardware requirements. We
    recommend using a machine with at least a 2 GHz Xeon or comparable
    CPU, 2 GB RAM and a 160 GB hard drive for a small setup.
    </para>

    <para>
    To run OTRS you'll also need to use a web server and a database server.
    Apart from that, on the OTRS machine, you should install perl and/or install
    some additional perl modules.
    The web server and <application>Perl</application> have to be installed on the same machine
    as OTRS. The database back-end can be installed locally or on another host.
    </para>

    <para>
    For the web server we recommend using the <application>Apache HTTP Server</application>, because
    its module mod_perl improves greatly the performance of OTRS. Apart from that,
    OTRS should run on any web server that can execute Perl scripts.
    </para>

    <para>
    You can deploy OTRS on different databases. You can choose between <application>MySQL</application>,
     <application>PostgreSQL</application>, <application>Oracle</application>, or
    <application>Microsoft SQL Server</application>.
    If you use <application>MySQL</application> you have the advantage that the database
    and some system settings can be configured during the installation, through a web front-end.
    </para>

    <para>
    For <application>Perl</application>, we recommend using at least version
    5.8.8. You need some additional modules which can be installed either with
    the Perl shell and CPAN or via the package manager of your operating system
    (<application>rpm</application>, <application>yast</application>,
    <application>apt-get</application>).
    </para>

    <para>Software requirements</para>

    <section id="perl-support">
        <title>Perl support</title>
        <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para>Perl 5.8.8 or higher</para>
        </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
    </section>

    <section id="webserver-support">
        <title>Web server support</title>
        <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para>Apache2 + mod_perl2 or higher (recommended, mod_perl is really fast!)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Webserver with CGI support (CGI is not recommended)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Microsoft Internet Information Server (IIS) 6 or higher</para>
        </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
    </section>

    <section id="database-support">
        <title>Database support</title>

        <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para>MySQL 4.1 or higher</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>PostgreSQL 7.0 or higher (8.2 or higher recommended)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Oracle 10g or higher</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Microsoft SQL Server 2005 or higher</para>
        </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <para>
            The section in the manual about
            <link linkend="installation-of-perl-modules">installation of Perl modules</link>
            describes in more detail how you can set up those which are needed for OTRS.
        </para>

        <para>
        If you install a binary package of OTRS, which was built for your operating
        system (rpm, Windows-Installer), either the package contains all Perl
        modules needed or the package manager of your system should take care of the
        dependencies of the Perl modules needed.
        </para>
    </section>

    <section id="webbrowser-support">
        <title>Web browser support</title>
        <para>
            For the Agent interface of OTRS, you'll be OK if you use a modern browser with JavaScript support enabled.
            We support the following browsers:
        </para>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>Internet Explorer 8.0 or higher</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Mozilla Firefox 3.6 or higher</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Google Chrome</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Opera 10 or higher</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Safari 4 or higher</para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <para>
            We recommend to always use the latest version of your browser, because it has the best JavaScript and rendering performance.
            Dramatical performance varieties between the used browsers can occur with big data or big systems.
            We are happy to consult you on that matter.
        </para>
        <para>
            For the OTRS Customer Interface, in addition to the browsers listed above,  you can also use
            Internet Explorer versions 6 or 7, and we do not require JavaScript either.
        </para>
    </section>
</section>

<section id="community">
    <title>Community</title>

    <para>
    OTRS has a large user community. Users and developers discuss about OTRS and
    interchange information on related issues through the
    <link linkend="additional-resources-mailinglists">mailing-lists</link>.
    You can use the mailing lists to discuss installation,
    configuration, usage, localization and development of OTRS. You can report software bugs
    in our <link linkend="additional-resources-bugtracking">bug tracking system</link>.
    </para>

    <para>
    The homepage of the OTRS community is:
    <ulink url="http://www.otrs.com/open-source/"><citetitle>http://www.otrs.com/open-source/</citetitle></ulink>.
    </para>
</section>

<section id="commercial-support-for-otrs">
    <title>Professional Services for OTRS</title>

    <para>
        Whether you need help in configuring or customizing OTRS or you want to be on the safe side,
        don't hesitate to contact us: We offer a wide range of professional services such as
        world-wide enterprise support, consulting and engineering including process design,
        implementation, customization, application support, and fully managed service.
    </para>
    <para>
        Our <ulink url="http://www.otrs.com/en/solutions/service-contracts/">Service Contracts</ulink> guarantee instant help
        and professional support as well as support assessment and last but not least free access to
        <ulink url="http://www.otrs.com/en/solutions/subscriptions/otrsfeatureadd-ons/">OTRS Feature Add-ons</ulink> -
        useful additional features for your OTRS.
    </para>
    <para>
        <ulink url="http://www.otrs.com/">The OTRS Group</ulink> offers specific
        <ulink url="http://www.otrs.com/en/solutions/training/">training programs</ulink> in different countries.
        You can either participate in one of our public OTRS Administrator trainings which take place regularly,
        or benefit from an inhouse training that covers all the specific needs of your company.
    </para>

</section>

</chapter>
