<?xml version='1.0' encoding='ISO-8859-1'?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
  "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">
<!-- $Id: time.xml,v 1.2 2006-02-22 12:09:35 cs Exp $ -->

<chapter id="time">
<title>Time related functions in OTRS</title>

<sect1 id="time-settings">
<title>Specifying the relevant times for OTRS</title>

<para>
Some actions in OTRS are initiated in dependency to the actual system time.
The escalation of tickets and the calculation of the escalation time for
tickets depend on a proper setup of the relevant times
for the ticket system. Also sending out the notifications for escalated
tickets and for tickets that have reached the pending time is triggered in
dependency to the time settings. The age of a ticket and the automatical
unlock mechanism are influenced by a proper time setup too.
</para>

<para>
With the configuration parameters

<link linkend="Framework:Core::Time:TimeWorkingHours">
TimeWorkingHours
</link>,

<link linkend="Framework:Core::Time:TimeVacationDays">
TimeVacationDays
</link>

and

<link linkend="Framework:Core::Time:TimeVacationDaysOneTime">
TimeVacationDaysOneTime
</link>

the relevant time settings for the system can be specified either via the

<link linkend="sysconfig">
SysConfig interface
</link>

or directly in the <filename>Kernel/Config.pm</filename> file.
</para>

<sect2 id="TimeWorkingHours">
<title>TimeWorkingHours</title>

<para>
Setup the relevant working hours for your system in
<filename>Kernel/Config.pm</filename> file the following way:

</para>

<example id='specifying-workinghours'>
<title>Specifying the relevant working hours for the system</title>

<para>
<programlisting>
    $Self->{'TimeWorkingHours'} = {
        Mon => [ 8,9,10,11,12,13,14,15,16,17,18,19,20 ],
        Tue => [ 8,9,10,11,12,13,14,15,16,17,18,19,20 ],
        Wed => [ 8,9,10,11,12,13,14,15,16,17,18,19,20 ],
        Thu => [ 8,9,10,11,12,13,14,15,16,17,18,19,20 ],
        Fri => [ 8,9,10,11,12,13,14,15,16,17,18,19,20 ],
        Sat => [  ],
        Sun => [  ],
    };
</programlisting>
</para>

</example>

<para>
Only during the specified working hours tickets can escalate, notifications
for escalated and pending tickets will be send and tickets will be unlocked
automaticly. Furthermorde only these hours influence the calculation of
the escalation time and the age of a ticket.
</para>
</sect2>

<sect2 id="TimeVacationDays">
<title>TimeVacationDays</title>

<para>
General holidays with the same date every year can be specified for the
system in the <filename>Kernel/Config.pm</filename> file the following way:
</para>

<example id='specifying-vacation-days'>
<title>Specifying regular holidays in the system</title>

<para>
<programlisting>
    $Self->{'TimeVacationDays'} = {
        1 => {
            1 => 'New Year\'s Eve!',
        },
        5 => {
            1 => '1 St. May',
        },
        12 => {
            24 => 'Christmas',
            25 => 'First Christmas Day',
            26 => 'Second Christmas Day',
            31 => 'Silvester',
        },
    };
</programlisting>
</para>

</example>

<para>
During this days no time related calculations or actions are done by the
system.
</para>
</sect2>

<sect2 id="TimeVacationDaysOneTime">
<title>TimeVacationDaysOneTime</title>

<para>
Free days or holidays that variate for every year can be specified in
the <filename>Kernel/Config.pm</filename> file the following way.
</para>

<example id='specifying-sometime-vacation-days'>
<title>Specifying iregular holidays in the system</title>

<para>
<programlisting>
    $Self->{'TimeVacationDaysOneTime'} = {
        2005 => {
            12 => {
                27 => 'Anual closing',
                28 => 'Anual closing',
                29 => 'Anual closing',
                30 => 'Anual closing',
            },
        },
        2006 => {
            6 => {
                12 => 'Anual works outing',
            },
        },
    };
</programlisting>
</para>

</example>

<para>
During this days no time related calculations or actions are done by the
system.
</para>

</sect2>
</sect1>

<sect1 id="unlock-tickets">
<title>Automated unlocking of tickets</title>

<para>
Locked tickets can be unlocked automaticly by the system. This feature might
be usefull if an agent has locked tickets that need to be processed, but the
agent can't work on this tickets because she is on holiday for example. The
automated unlock feature unlocks tickets after a given time to ensure that
no locked tickets will be forgotten and other agents can process this
tickets.
</para>

<para>
The unlock time for tickets can be specified in the

<link linkend="adminarea-queue">
settings
</link>

for every queue. The module <filename>bin/UnlockTickets.pl</filename>,
which should be execued via a cron job periodicaly, realizes the
automated unlock of tickets. Tickets only are unlocked dduring the
hours set by the

<link linkend="TimeWorkingHours">
TimeWorkingHours
</link>

configuration parameter. During days specified in

<link linkend='TimeVacationDays'>
TimeVacationDays
</link>

and

<link linkend='TimeVacationDaysOneTime'>
TimeVacationDaysOneTime
</link>

no tickets are unlocked automaticly.
</para>

<para>
Notifications on unlocked tickets are send out to those agents only, that
have the queue with the unlocked tickets set in "My queues" and that have
activatet the notification on unlocked tickets in their personal

<link linkend="user-preferences">
preferences
</link>
.
</para>

</sect1>

<sect1 id="pending-tickets">
<title>Pending tickets</title>

<para>
With OTRS you can create pending tickets. The system can send out a
notification at a given point of time and remind an agent on a locked
ticket. This feature might be usefull to get reminded contacting a customer
somewhen in the future, because the customer is not reachable at the moment for
example.
</para>

<para>
Reminders on pending tickets are only send out during hours specified
with the

<link linkend="TimeWorkingHours">
TimeWorkingHours
</link>

configuration parameter. The <filename>bin/PendingJobs.pl</filename> module,
which should be executed via a cron job periodicaly, driggers the delivery
of the pending reminders.
</para>

</sect1>

<sect1 id="escalate-tickets">
<title>Ticket escalation</title>

<para>
With OTRS it is possible to let ticket escalate. If a ticket is
escalated, no other tickets are displaied for the queue where the escalated
ticket is stored or in QueueView, the escalated ticket has to be locked
first. So the escalation of tickets can ensure that tickets must be
considered after they have reached a given age.
</para>

<para>
The age after a ticket escalates can be specified in the

<link linkend="adminarea-queue">
settings
</link>

for every queue. With a job for the

<link linkend="adminarea-genericagent">
GenericAgent
</link>

notifications on escalated tickets can be delivered to agents, that have
the queue with the escalated ticket in "My queues" enabled and that have
activated notifications on escalated tickets in their personal

<link linkend="user-preferences">
preferences
</link>
.
</para>

<example id='genericagent-job-for-escalated-tickets'>
<title>GenericAgent job to send notification on escalated tickets</title>

<para>
The file <filename>Kernel/Config/GenericAgent.pm</filename> already
contains a example job for notification delivery to agents on escalated
tickets. The jobs in this file are processed by the GenericAgent, which is
executed periodicaly by a cron job. Just open the file and remove the
comments ("#"") for the following lines:
</para>

<para>
<programlisting>
%Jobs = (
   # --
   # [name of job] -> send escalation notifications
   # --
   'send escalation notifications' => {
       Escalation => 1,
       # new ticket properties
       New => {
           Module => 'Kernel::System::GenericAgent::NotifyAgentGroupOfCustomQueue',
       },
   },
   # insert your jobs (see Kernel/Config/GenericAgent.pm.examples)
);
</programlisting>
</para>

</example>

<para>
If a new ticket is stored in a queue that has set a value for escalation
time, the positive value for the set escalation time is shown first. The
displayed value for the escalation time does not change, if the system is
not in the hours specified for TimeWorkingHours or if currently is a day
specified in TimeVacationDays or TimeVacationDaysOneTime.
</para>

<para>
If the system is in a time window which is relevant for the calculation for
time specific events, the escalation time is counted down. If the value 0
is reached the ticket escalates. Further on the value for the escalation
time gets negative, the ticket has exceeded the point of time for the
escalation. During the next run of the GenericAgent the job for the
notification about escalated tickets is executed and the messages will be
send out to the agents. The escalated ticket blocks the view of all other
tickets in the queue and must be processed. Even if the escalated ticket is
locked and processed the displayied value for the escalation time stays in
the negative range. This behaviour does not change as long as the ticket
is in an open state (open, new, pending, e.g.). The value for the escalation
time only gets reset if the state changes to closed. If the same ticket is
reopened for example by a follow-up, the count down for the escalation
time starts again with the positive value set for the queue where the
ticket is stored.
</para>

<para>
So a ticket only can escalate, if it is not locked and if it is in an open
state. If the ticket is locked and not yet closed, the escalation time is
counted down and the ticket escalates if the time value is zero. If the
state was changed to closed and if the ticket is reopened by a follow-up
request, the escalation process described before starts again.
</para>

</sect1>

</chapter>
