<?xml version='1.0' encoding='ISO-8859-1'?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
    "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">
<!-- $Id: tts.xml,v 1.3 2006-04-20 15:51:24 cs Exp $ -->

<chapter id="tts">
<title>Basics about trouble ticket systems</title>

<abstract>
<para>
This chapter gives a short overview about the idea of trouble
tickets in general and trouble ticket systems in detail. A short example
shows the advantages of a ticket system.
</para>
</abstract>

<sect1 id="basic-tts-example">
<title>What is a trouble ticket system, when do you need it?</title>

<para>
The following example describes what a trouble ticket system is and how you
can save time and money if you use such a system in your company.
</para>

<para>
Let's imagine that Max is a manufacturer who produces video recorders.
Since programming video recorders is very complex, Max gets many
mails from customers who need help with the devices. Some days,
Max has not enough time to answer all mails so that
his customers have to be patient until they get an answer. Some customers
don't want to wait that long so that they write another mail with the same
question. All mails containing support requests are stored in only one inbox
file. The requests are not sorted and the mails are answered with a normal
mail program.
</para>

<para>
Then the developers Joe and John have to help Max answer the
mails because Max can't reply fast enough to all the messages. Since Max,
Joe and John use the same system with the same inbox file, they all access
the same inbox. Joe and John don't know that Max often got two identical
requests from a desperate customer. So Joe
answers the first and John the second mail of the customer, both with
a helpful hint on how to solve the problem. The customer receives two
different answers, and Max does not know what John and
Joe wrote. Max neither has an overview about the replies of Joe and John nor does he
know all the problems the customers have had with the video recorders nor which
problems occur very often nor how much time and money he has to spend for
customer support.
</para>

<para>
At a meeting, a colleague tells Max about trouble ticket systems and
that they can solve Max's problems with the customer support. After
looking for information in the internet, Max  decides to install the Open Ticket
Request System (OTRS) on a computer that can be reached via the web
by both his customers and his employees. Now, the customer requests are no
longer send to Max's private inbox but to the mail account that is used for
OTRS. The ticket system is connected to this mailbox and saves all requests in
its database. For every new request, the system generates an auto-answer and
sends it to the customer so that the customer knows that his request has
arrived and will be answered soon. OTRS generates an explicit
identification, the ticket number, for every single request. Now, the
customers are happy because they got a quick response to their requests and
it is not necessary to send a secound message with the same question. Max,
John and Joe can now login into OTRS with a simple web browser and answer
the requests. Since the system locks a ticket which is answered, no message
is edited twice.
</para>

<para>
Lets imagine that Mr Smith makes a request to Max's company and his
message is processed by OTRS. John gives a brief reply to this request but Mr
Smith wants to know more so he replies to John's mail. Since John
has other things to do, Max answers Mr Smith's message. The
history function of OTRS makes it easy for Max to read both Mr Smith's first
message and John's response so that he is able to write a more
detailed reply to Mr Smith. Mr Smith does not know that two different
people were involved in the communication process, he is only happy about
the solution for his problem that arrived with Max's last reply.
</para>

<para>
Of course, this is only a short overview about the possibilities and features of
trouble ticket systems. But if many customer requests (mails and phone
calls) must be handled by different people, a ticket system can help
to save working time and money. A ticket system helps you to structure your
support or helpdesk environment and you can define workflow processes. The
communication between customers and companies gets more transparent which
results in more effectiveness for both sides.
</para>

</sect1>

<sect1 id="what-is-a-tt">
<title>What is a trouble ticket?</title>

<para>
A trouble ticket is comparable to a medical report for a hospital
patient. A medical report is generated when the patient visits the
hospital for the first time. All important data about the patient, such as personal
data and facts about the medical problem, are noted in the medical report.
Each doctor adds to the medical report information on the illness and any medication
 so that all doctors and the whole nursing staff can get a quick
and detailed overview about the patient's problem. When the patient has
recovered and leaves hospital, the medical report gets closed and all
information get archived.
</para>

<para>
Trouble ticket systems like OTRS, handle trouble tickets like normal email.
The messages are saved in the system. When a customer sends a request, a new
ticket is generated by the system which is comparable to a new medical report being opened. The
answer to this new ticket can be compared to a doctor's entry in
the medical report, a new answer to a change in the
clinical picture of the patient. A ticket is finished if an
answer is send back to the customer or if the ticket is closed by the
system. If a customer sends an answer for a already closed ticket, the ticket
will be reopened and the new information will be added. To keep the
consistency of all data in the system, every ticket is stored and archived
with all relevant information. Since tickets are handled like normal
emails, attachments will be stored, too. Notes can be added as additional
information to every email. All tickets are stored on the hard drive or in
the database of the system. Also additional information like notes,
dates, employees involved, working time needed for a ticket etc. are stored. All
tickets can be sorted and it is possible to search through all data.
</para>
</sect1>

</chapter>
