<?xml version='1.0' encoding='ISO-8859-1'?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
    "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">
<!-- $Id: tts.xml,v 1.1 2005-09-13 10:51:49 cs Exp $ -->

<chapter id="tts">
<title>Basics about trouble ticket systems</title>

<abstract>
<para>
This chapter tryes to give a short overview about the idea of trouble
tickets in general and trouble ticket systems in detail. A short example
shows the advantages of a ticket system.
</para>
</abstract>

<sect1 id="basic-tts-example">
<title>What is a trouble ticket system, when do you need it?</title>

<para>
The following example describes what a trouble ticket system is and how you
can save time and mony if you use such a system in your company.
</para>

<para>
Lets imagine, that Max is a fabricant who produces video recorders.
Because programing the video recorders is very complex, Max gets many
mails from customers who need help with the devices. There
are days, when Max has not enough time to anser all mails and so
his customers has to be patient till they get an answer. Some customers
don't want to wait that long and so they write another mail with the same
question. All mails with the support requests are stored in only one inbox
file, the requests are not sorted and the mails are answered with a normal
mail program.
</para>

<para>
Some days the developers Joe and John have to help Max to answer the
mails, because Max can't reply to all messages fast enough. Because Max,
Joe and John use the same system with the same inbox file, they all access
the same inbox. Joe and John don't know, that Max ofthen got two identical
requests from the same desperated customer. So it happens, that Joe
answers the first and John the second mail of the same customer, both with
another helpfull hint how to solve the problem. That results in two
different answers for the customer and Max does not know what John and
Joe wrote. Max has no overview on the replys of Joe and John, he does not
know all problems that the customer have with the video recorders, which
problems occure very ofthen and how much time and money he has to spend for
the customer support.
</para>

<para>
At a meeting a colleague tells Max about trouble ticket systems and
that tey can solve the problems that Max has with his customer support. Max
looks around in the internet and he decides to install the Open Ticket
Request System (OTRS) on to a machine that can be reached via the web
by his customers and his employees. Now the customer requests are not
longer send to Max's private inbox but to the mail account that is used for
OTRS. The ticket system connects to this mailbox and saves all requests in
its database. For every new request the system generates a auto answer and
sends it to the customer, so the customer knows, that his request has
arrived and will be answered soon. OTRS generates an explicit
identification for every request, the ticket number. Now the customers are
happy, because they got a quick response to their requests, there is no
need to send a secound message with the same question. Max, John and Joe
can login into OTRS now with a simple web browser and answer the requests.
Because the system locks a ticket which is answered, no message is
edited two times.
</para>

<para>
Lets imagine, that Mr. Schmith makes a request to Max's company and his
message is processed by OTRS. John answers this request shortly but Mr.
Smith wants to know more and he replys again to Johns mail. Because John
has other things to do, Max answers to Mr. Smith's message. The
history function of OTRS makes it easy for Max to read the first message of
Mr. Schmith and John's response, so he is able to write a longer and more
detailed reply to Mr. Smith. Mr. Smith does not know, that two different
people were involved in the communication process, he is only happy about
the solution for his problem that arrived with Max's last reply.
</para>

<para>
Ofcourse this is only a short overview on the possibilities and features of
trouble ticket systems. But if many customer requests (mails and phone
calls) must be handled by different people, a ticket system can help
to save working time and money. A ticket system helps you to structure your
support or helpdesk envirorment and you can define workflow processes. The
communication between customers and companies gets more transparent and
that results in mor content customers and  employees.
</para>

</sect1>

<sect1 id="what-is-att">
<title>What is a trouble ticket?</title>

<para>
A trouble ticket is a little bit like a medical report for a hospital
patient. A new medical report is generated, if the patient visits the
hospital the first time. All important data for the patient, personal data
and facts about the medical problem, get inserted in the medical report.
Every doctor adds information about the illness and the medication to the
medical report so every one can get a quick and detailed overview about the
problem of the patient. Every new doctor can quickliy see what's going on
with the patient. If the illness is over and the patient is healthy again,
the medical report gets closed and all information get archived.
</para>

<para>
Trouble ticket systems like OTRS handle trouble tickets like normal emails.
The messages are saved in the system. If a customer sends a request, a new
ticket is generated by the system, a new medical report is opened. The
answer to this new ticket can be compared like an entry of a doctor into
the medical report, a new anser of the customer like a change in the
clinical picture of the patient. A ticket is finished, if an
answer is send back to the customer or if the ticket is closed by the
system. Sends a customer an answer to a already closed ticket, the ticket
will be reopened and the new informations will be added. To keep the
consistency of all data in the system, every ticket is stored and archived
with all specific informations. Because tickets are handled like normal
emails also attachments will be stored. Notes can be added as additional
information to every email. All tickets are stored  on the hard drive or in
the database of the system, also the additional informations like notes,
date, involved employees, needed working time for a ticket, e.g. All
tickets can be sorted and it is possible to search through all data.
</para>
</sect1>

</chapter>
