<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">


<!-- $Id: dynamicfields.xml,v 1.4 2012-12-03 08:37:27 mg Exp $ -->
<section id="dynamicfields">
    <title>Динамические Поля</title>
    <section id="dynamicfields-introduction">
        <title>Introduction</title>
        <para>
            A dynamic field is a special kind of field in OTRS, created to extend the
information stored on a ticket or article. These fields are not fixed in the
system and they can appear only in specific screens, they can be mandatory
or not, and their representation in the screens depends on the field type
defined at their creation time according to the data to be held by the
field. For example, there are fields to hold a text, a date, a selection of
items, etc.
        </para>
        <para>
            Dynamic fields are the evolution of TicketFreeText TicketFreeKey
TicketFreeTime, ArticleFreeText and ArticleFreeKey fields that where
commonly used in OTRS 3.0 and before. The limitation of these "Free Fields"
was that they can be defined up to 16 (text or dropdown) fields and 6 time
fields for a ticket and 3 (text or dropdown)  fields for each article only,
not more.
        </para>
        <para>
            Now with dynamic fields the limitation in the number of fields per ticket or
article is removed, you can create as many dynamic fields you like either
for ticket or articles.  And beyond that, the framework behind the dynamic
fields is prepared to handle custom fields for other objects rather than
just ticket and articles.
        </para>
        <para>
            This new framework that handles the dynamic fields is build using a modular
approach, where each kind of dynamic field can be seen as a plug-in module
for the framework.  This means that the variety of dynamic fields can be
easily extended by public OTRS modules, OTRS Feature Add-ons, OTRS custom
developments, and other custom developments.
        </para>
        <para>
            The following dynamic field types are included with this release:
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        Text (одна строка текста)
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        Textarea (несколько строк текста)
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        Checkbox
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        Выпадающий список (единственный выбор, несколько значений)
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        Multiselect (множественный выбор, несколько значений)
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        Date
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        Date / Time
                    </para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </para>
    </section>
    <xi:include xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" href="dynamicfields-configuration.xml" />
</section>
