<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">

<section id="scheduler">
    <title>Планировщик OTRS</title>
    <para>
        The OTRS Scheduler is an independent system process that executes tasks in
background. These kind of processes are know as <emphasis>daemons</emphasis>
in Unix / Linux systems or as <emphasis>services</emphasis> on Windows
environments. It is independent but that doesn't mean that the Scheduler
does everything alone, it is fully integrated into OTRS and can use any OTRS
module as needed to complete each task.
    </para>
    <para>
        Currently the OTRS Scheduler is only able to handle Generic Interface
tasks. These kind of tasks execute invokers that send requests to remote
systems. Other handlers for different tasks will be added in future OTRS
versions.
    </para>
    <para>
        For sanity reasons the Scheduler process needs to be restarted from time to
time. This is done automatically by the scheduler process itself once a day,
but it can be adjusted as needed using the SysConfig by editing the
"Scheduler::RestartAfterSeconds" setting.
    </para>
    <para>
        The OTRS Scheduler is a fully automated process, the only needed human
interaction is to check its status periodically and start or stop it as
needed.
    </para>
    <note>
        <para>
            If the Scheduler is stopped for any reason, all pending tasks and new tasks
registered when the Scheduler is stopped will be executed as soon as the
Scheduler starts again (unless the tasks are set to be executed in the
future).
        </para>
    </note>
    <section id="scheduler-gui">
        <title>Графический интерфейс планировщика</title>
        <para>
            Планировщик не виден в Графическом Пользовательском Интерфейсе OTRS до того
времени пока он остается работать.
        </para>
        <section id="scheduler-gui-notify">
            <title>Планировщик Не Запускает Уведомления</title>
            <para>
                There are two different types of notifications if the system detects that
the scheduler is not running. This detection is based on the update
frequency of the Scheduler process. If the difference between current time
and the last process update time is 2 times the process update frequency a
warning message will be displayed in the OTRS notification area. If it is
over 4 times the process frequency then an alert will be displayed instead.
            </para>
            <para>
                Параметр Планировщика обновление времени может быть настроен с помощью
параметра "Scheduler::PIDUpdateTime" в файле SysConfig.
            </para>
            <para>
                If you see a warning message it is not always necessary to take an action,
but it is highly recommended to check if the scheduler process is
running. If you see an alert, then there is a high chance that the scheduler
is in fact not running and should be started.
            </para>
            <para>
                По умолчанию Планировщик не запускает уведомлений, если есть действительный
веб-сервис, зарегистрированный в базе данных и он отображается только для
пользователей из группы "admin".
            </para>
            <para>
                Чтобы отключить уведомления (не рекомендуется) или же изменить или добавить
группы уведомлений, пожалуйста, отредактируйте настройку
"Frontend::NotifyModule###800-Scheduler-Check" в файле SysConfig.
            </para>
            <para>
                <screenshot>
<screeninfo>Уведомления Планировщика</screeninfo> <graphic srccredit="scheduler
notification - screenshot" scale="40"
fileref="screenshots/scheduler-notify.png"></graphic></screenshot>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emphasis>Figure: Уведомления планировщика.</emphasis>
            </para>
        </section>
        <section id="scheduler-gui-start">
            <title>Запуск Планировщика</title>
            <para>
                By clicking on the Scheduler not running notification link (either warning
or alert) a dialog box will open to let you start the Scheduler process
again. The Scheduler can be started normally or forced to start, by clicking
on the appropriate check box in the dialog.
            </para>
            <note>
                <para>
                    A forced Scheduler start is only necessary if previous Scheduler process was
terminated abnormally and the Process ID is still registered in the
database.
                </para>
                <para>
                    Используйте инструменты командной строки, описанные ниже, чтобы иметь полный
контроль над процессами Планировщика и иметь возможность проверить его
реальное состояние.
                </para>
            </note>
            <para>
                <screenshot>
<screeninfo>Запуск Планировщика</screeninfo> <graphic srccredit="scheduler start
- screenshot" scale="40"
fileref="screenshots/scheduler-start.png"></graphic></screenshot>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emphasis>Рисунок: Запуск Планировщика.</emphasis>
            </para>
        </section>
    </section>
    <section id="scheduler-cli">
        <title>Интерфейс командной строки Планировщика</title>
        <para>
            Командная строка Планировщика позволяет управлять процессами (Запуск /
Остановка) или запрашивать их состояние. Также есть инструменты для
регистрации процесса, который будет управлять операционной системой.
        </para>
        <para>
            В комплекте с OTRS есть два набора инструментов командной строки, один для
операционной системы Linux а другой для MS Windows.
        </para>
        <section id="scheduler-cli-linux">
            <title>Unix / Linux</title>
            <section id="scheduler-cli-linux-init">
                <title>Файлы Init.d Планировщика</title>
                <para>
                    Init.d files are special scripts that are called by the operating system at
startup and shutdown (or restart) times.
                </para>
                <para>
                    OTRS provide init.d scripts to start / stop the OTRS Scheduler process
automatically by the operating system, these scripts are located under
OTRS_HOME/scripts.
                </para>
                <para>
                    Init.d scripts need to be copied to the correct location for your operating
system. They need to have the proper permissions and some internal variables
need to be set to work properly.
                </para>
                <itemizedlist mark="round">
                    <title>Init.d Скрипт Внутренних Переменных</title>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>
                            <command>OTRS_HOME</command> - путь установки OTRS.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>
                            <command>User</command> - имя пользователя процесса apache.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>
                            <command>Group</command> - apache обрабатывает группу пользователей с таким
именем.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
                <note>
                    <para>
                        В настоящее время в распоряжении Linux-платформ есть только сценарии init.d
                    </para>
                </note>
                <table>
                    <title>Список Init-сценариев и Поддерживаемых Операционных систем</title>
                    <tgroup cols="2">
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry>Сценарий инициализации</entry>
                            <entry>Поддерживаемы операционные системы</entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry>otrs-scheduler-linux</entry>
                            <entry>Red Hat, Fedora, CentOS, SUSE, openSUSE, Debian, Ubuntu</entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>otrs-scheduler-gentoo-init.d, otrs-scheduler-gentoo-conf.d</entry>
                            <entry>Gentoo</entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                    </tgroup>
                </table>
                <example>
                    <title>Пример Запуска OTRS-Планировщика из сценария Init.d</title>
                    <para>
                        <screen>
                            shell> /etc/init.d/otrs-scheduler-linux start
                        </screen>
                    </para>
                </example>
                <itemizedlist mark="round">
                    <title>Возможные действия</title>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>
                            <command>start</command> запуск процесса OTRS-Планировщика.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>
                            <command>stop</command> остановка процесса OTRS-Планировщика.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>
                            <command>restart</command> перезапуск процесса OTRS-Планировщика.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>
                            <command>status</command> запросить статус процесса OTRS-Планировщика.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
                <para>
                    Для корректной работы Планировщика необходима база данных, поскольку он
регистрирует свой ID процесса, именно по этой причине необходимо:
                    <itemizedlist mark="round">
                        <listitem>
                            <para>
                                Выполните скрипт init.d для <emphasis>запуска</emphasis> процесса
Планировщика, после того как запущен процес базы данных.
                            </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>
                                Execute the Scheduler init.d script to <emphasis>stop</emphasis> the
Scheduler before the database process shuts down.
                            </para>
                        </listitem>
                    </itemizedlist>
                </para>
                <note>
                    <para>
                        If you want the Scheduler to run at system startup, please read the
documentation of the operating system to find out the right location to
place the init.d scripts, how to configure them to run automatically and how
to set the run order.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </section>
            <section id="scheduler-cli-linux-daemon">
                <title>Файл "Демона" Планировщика</title>
                <para>
                    Это часть Планировщика, который остается работать в фоновом режиме, проверяя
задания, которые нужно выполнить. Она также обеспечивает основные функции
для управления процессом.
                </para>
                <para>
                    Все Unix / Linux системы используют файл
<command>OTRS_HOME/bin/otrs.Scheduler.pl</command>.
                </para>
                <example>
                    <title>Пример для Запуска OTRS-Планировщика</title>
                    <para>
                        <screen>
                            shell> OTRS_HOME/bin/otrs.Scheduler.pl -a start
                        </screen>
                    </para>
                </example>
                <itemizedlist mark="round">
                    <title>Доступные Опции</title>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>
                            <command>-a </command> действие.
                        </para>
                        <itemizedlist mark="round">
                            <title>Возможные значения</title>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>
                                    <command>start</command>- старт процесса Планировщика.
                                </para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>
                                    <command>stop</command>- остановка процесса Планировщика.
                                </para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>
                                    <command>status</command>- для запроса статуса процесса Планировщика.
                                </para>
                            </listitem>
                        </itemizedlist>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>
                            <command>-f </command> принудительный старт или остановка процесса
Планировщика.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
                <example>
                    <title>Пример принудительной остановки Планировщика OTRS</title>
                    <para>
                        <screen>
                            shell> OTRS_HOME/bin/otrs.Scheduler.pl -a stop -f 1
                        </screen>
                    </para>
                </example>
                <note>
                    <para>
                        Force stop the Scheduler is used remove the process ID from the database
when the scheduler is not running and the process is still registered.
                    </para>
                    <para>
                        Force start the Scheduler is used to start the Scheduler process if the
scheduler is not running and the process is registered.
                    </para>
                    <para>
                        Force start or stop are only necessary if the start of the process is needed
to be done before the process update time expires. Otherwise an expired
entry in the database is discarded by normal start.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </section>
        </section>

       <section id="scheduler-cli-windows">
            <title>Windows</title>
            <section id="scheduler-cli-windows-scm">
                <title>Установщик Планировщика</title>
                <para>
                    The integration of the services into the MS Windows Operating System is done
via the Windows Service Control Manager (SCM). In order to make the OTRS
Scheduler process to be controlled by the SCM is necessary to register this
service
                </para>
                <para>
                    OTRS предоставляет сценарий
<command>OTRS_HOME/bin/otrs.Scheduler4WinInstaller.pl</command> для
регистрации и отмены регистрации OTRS-планировщика в SCM.
                </para>
                <example>
                    <title>Пример Регистрации OTRS-Планировщика в Widows SCM</title>
                    <para>
                        <screen>
                            shell> OTRS_HOME/bin/otrs.Scheduler4WinInstaller.pl -a install
                        </screen>
                    </para>
                </example>
                <itemizedlist mark="round">
                    <title>Доступные Опции</title>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>
                            <command>-a </command> действие.
                        </para>
                        <itemizedlist mark="round">
                            <title>Возможные значения</title>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>
                                    <command>install</command>- для установки процесса Планировщика в Windows
SCM.
                                </para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>
                                    <command>remove</command>- для удаления процесса Планировщика из Windows
SCM.
                                </para>
                            </listitem>
                        </itemizedlist>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
                <para>
                    After installing into the Widows SCM the OTRS Scheduler process can be used
like any other service in Windows. It can be started, stopped and restarted
and can be configured to be started manually or automatic.
                </para>
                <note>
                    <para>
                        Обратитесь к документации Windows для более подробного изучения Сервисов
Windows и Windows SCM.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </section>
            <section id="scheduler-cli-linux-service">
                <title>Сервисный Файл Планировщика</title>
                <para>
                    Это часть Планировщика, который остается работать в фоновом режиме, проверяя
задания, которые нужно выполнить. Она также обеспечивает основные функции
для управления процессом.
                </para>
                <para>
                    Операционная Система Windows использует файл
<command>OTRS_HOME/bin/otrs.Scheduler4Win.pl</command>.
                </para>
                <example>
                    <title>Пример для Запуска OTRS-Планировщика</title>
                    <para>
                        <screen>
                            shell> OTRS_HOME/bin/otrs.Scheduler4Win.pl -a start
                        </screen>
                    </para>
                </example>
                <itemizedlist mark="round">
                    <title>Доступные Опции</title>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>
                            <command>-a </command> действие.
                        </para>
                        <itemizedlist mark="round">
                            <title>Возможные значения</title>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>
                                    <command>start</command>- старт процесса Планировщика.
                                </para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>
                                    <command>stop</command>- остановка процесса Планировщика.
                                </para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>
                                    <command>status</command>- для запроса статуса процесса Планировщика.
                                </para>
                            </listitem>
                        </itemizedlist>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>
                            <command>-f </command> принудительный старт или остановка процесса
Планировщика.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
                <example>
                    <title>Пример принудительной остановки Планировщика OTRS</title>
                    <para>
                        <screen>
                            shell> OTRS_HOME/bin/otrs.Scheduler4Win.pl -a stop -f 1
                        </screen>
                    </para>
                </example>
                <note>
                    <para>
                        Force stopping the Scheduler is used to remove the process ID from the
database when the scheduler is not running and the process is still
registered.
                    </para>
                    <para>
                        Force starting the Scheduler is used to start the Scheduler process if the
scheduler is not running and the process is still registered.
                    </para>
                    <para>
                        Force start or stop are only necessary if starting the process is needed to
be done before the process update time expires. Otherwise an expired entry
in the database would be discarded by a normal start.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </section>
        </section>
    </section>
</section>
