<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
  "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">


<!-- $Id: applications.xml,v 1.15 2010-12-07 13:56:43 mg Exp $ -->
<chapter id="application">
<title>Additional applications</title>

<abstract>
<para>
You can install additional application packages to extend the functionality
of the OTRS framework. This can be done via the package manager in the
adminarea, which downloads the applications from an online repository and
manages package dependencies. It is also possible to install packages from
local files, in case your OTRS system does not have a direct internet
connection.
</para>
</abstract>

<section id="application-calendar">
<title>Calendar</title>

<para>
You can edit and view both private and public user-based appointments with
the web-based Calendar (see Figure 20.1 below).
</para>

<para>
<screenshot>
<screeninfo>Calendar</screeninfo> <graphic srccredit="Calendar -
screenshot" scale="40" fileref="screenshots/calendar.png"></graphic></screenshot>
</para>

<para>
    <emphasis>Figure 20.1. Calendar package.</emphasis>
</para>
</section>

<section id="application-filemanager">
<title>File Manager</title>

<para>
The File Manager (see Figure 20.2 below) makes it possible to access the
content of a directory that is located in the file system of the machine
where OTRS is installed. You can use your web browser to upload, download,
delete and view files, browse and create subdirectories, etc.
</para>

<para>
<screenshot>
<screeninfo>File Manager</screeninfo> <graphic srccredit="Filemanager -
screenshot" scale="40" fileref="screenshots/filemanager.png"></graphic></screenshot>
</para>

<para>
    <emphasis>Figure 20.2. File Manager package.</emphasis>
</para>

</section>

<section id="application-webmail">
<title>Web Mail</title>

<para>
Using the Web Mail package (see Figure 20.3 below), you can access your
mailbox via an IMAP server.  With a web browser, it is possible to compose
new messages, answer and forward your mails, etc.
</para>

<para>
<screenshot>
<screeninfo>Web Mail</screeninfo> <graphic srccredit="Webmail -
screenshot" scale="40" fileref="screenshots/webmail.png"></graphic></screenshot>
</para>

<para>
    <emphasis>Figure 20.3. Web Mail module.</emphasis>
</para>

</section>

<section id="application-faq">
<title>FAQ</title>

<para>
It is the Knowledge Base component. It supports editing and viewing of FAQ
articles. Articles can be viewed and restricted to agents, customer users or
anonymous users; they can also be structured in groups and have different
languages.
</para>

</section>


</chapter>
