<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
  "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">


<!-- $Id: configuration.xml,v 1.12 2010-12-01 11:02:21 mg Exp $ -->
<chapter id="configuration">
<title>Configuration of the system</title>

<section id="directories-and-configfiles">
<title>The config files of OTRS</title>

<para>
All configuration files of OTRS are stored in the directory
<filename>Kernel</filename> and in its sub directories. There is no need to
manually change any other file than <filename>Kernel/Config.pm</filename>,
because the rest of the files will be changed when the system gets
upgraded. Just copy the configuration parameters from the other files into
<filename>Kernel/Config.pm</filename> and change them to your needs. This
file will never be touched during the upgrade process, so your manual
settings are safe.
</para>

<para>
The file <filename>Kernel/Config/Defaults.pm</filename> contains the
parameters of the central OTRS framework. It defines all basic system
settings, like the mail configuration, database connection, default charset
and standard language. The file
<filename>Kernel/Config/Files/Ticket.pm</filename> contains all
configuration parameters for the trouble ticket system.
</para>

<para>
In the directory <filename>Kernel/Config/Files</filename> there are some
other files that are parsed when the OTRS login page is accessed. If
additional applications like the FAQ or the file manager are installed, the
configuration files for those can also be found in the mentioned path.
</para>

<para>
To keep compatibility with older OTRS versions, there is always a .pm- and a
.xml file for every application and for the central framework. The .pm files
are needed to parse all default and customized settings. The XML files are
used by the graphical configuration frontend, which is available with OTRS
2.0 onwards, and which lets you set most of the configuration parameters of
the system through your web browser. In future versions of OTRS the .pm
files will be removed and the system will be configurable only via the .xml
files. All parameters in <filename>Kernel/Config/Defaults.pm</filename> will
be moved to <filename>Kernel/Config/Files/Framework.xml</filename> and all
parameters for the trouble ticket system will be no longer stored in
<filename>Kernel/Config/Files/Ticket.pm</filename> but in
<filename>Kernel/Config/Files/Ticket.xml</filename>. The format of the
configuration parameters will completely change to xml.
</para>

<para>
If the web frontend of OTRS is accessed, all .xml files in the
<filename>Kernel/Config/Files</filename> directory are parsed in
alphabetical order and the settings for the central framework and additional
applications will be loaded. Afterwards, the settings in the two files
<filename>Kernel/Config/Files/ZZZAAuto.pm</filename> and
<filename>Kernel/Config/Files/ZZZAuto.pm</filename> will be evaluated. Both
files are used by the graphical configuration frontend and should never be
changed manually. Lastly, the file <filename>Kernel/Config.pm</filename>
that contains your individual settings and manually changed configuration
parameters, will be parsed. Reading the configuration files in this order
makes sure that your specific configuration settings are used by the system.
</para>

</section>


<section id="sysconfig">
<title>Configuring the system through the web interface</title>

<para>
With OTRS 2.0 and subsequent versions, nearly all configuration parameters
of the central framework or additional installed applications, can be
changed easily with the graphical configuration frontend. Log in as OTRS
administrator and follow the "SysConfig" link in the adminarea to execute
the new configuration tool (see Figure 6.1 below).
</para>

<para>
<screenshot>
<screeninfo>The graphical configuration frontend</screeninfo> <graphic srccredit="sysconfig -
screenshot" scale="40" fileref="screenshots/admin-sysconfig.png"></graphic></screenshot>
</para>

<para>
    <emphasis>Figure 6.1. The graphical configuration frontend.</emphasis>
</para>

<para>
Because OTRS currently has over 600 configuration parameters, there are
different ways to access quickly to a specific one.  With the full text
search, all configuration parameters can be scanned for one or more
keywords. The full text search not only searches through the names of the
configuration parameters, but also the descriptions of the parameters are
scanned. This allows to find an element, even if its name is unknown.
</para>

<para>
Furthermore, all configuration parameters are sorted in main groups and sub
groups. The main group represents the application that the configuration
parameter belongs to, e.g. "Framework" for the central OTRS framework,
"Ticket" for the ticket system, "FAQ" for the FAQ system, and so on. The sub
groups can be accessed if the application is selected from the groups
listbox and the "Select group" button is pressed.
</para>

<para>
Every configuration parameter can be turned on or off via a checkbox. If the
parameter is turned off, the system will ignore this parameter or the
default is used. It is possible to switch a changed configuration parameter
back to the system default using the reset link.  The "Update" button,
submits all changes for the the system to use the new settings.
</para>

<para>
If you want to save all the changes you made to the configuration of your
system, for example, to setup a new installed system quickly, you can use
the "Export settings" button, which will create a .pm file. To restore your
own settings, just press the "Import settings" and select the .pm created
before.
</para>

<note>
<para>
For security reasons, the configuration parameters for the database
connection cannot be changed in the SysConfig. They have to be set manually
in <filename>Kernel/Config.pm</filename>.
</para>
</note>

</section>

</chapter>
