<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
  "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">


<!-- $Id: first-steps.xml,v 1.13 2010-12-02 14:41:14 mg Exp $ -->
<chapter id="first-steps-in-otrs">
<title>First steps in OTRS</title>

<abstract>
<para>
This chapter 's goal is to give a quick overview about how OTRS is working
and how the web interface is structured. The differences between agents,
customers and administrators are explained , and the first login as OTRS
admin will be accomplished to take a closer look at the user preferences
which are available for every account.
</para>
</abstract>

<section id="agent-interface">
<title>Agent web interface</title>

<para>
All agents use the agent web interface to work with OTRS. Agents answer the
customer requests, create new tickets for customers or other agents, write
tickets about telephone calls with customers, write FAQ entries or edit
customer data, etc.
</para>

<para>
Soposing that your OTRS host is reachable via the URL <ulink
url="http://www.example.com/"> <citetitle>http://www.example.com</citetitle>
</ulink> , then the agents and also the OTRS administrator can reach the
login screen by using the address <ulink
url="http://www.example.com/otrs/index.pl">
<citetitle>http://www.example.com/otrs/index.pl</citetitle> </ulink> in a
web browser (see Figure 4.1 below).
</para>

<para>
<screenshot>
<screeninfo>index.pl - Agent login screen</screeninfo> <graphic srccredit="index.pl -
screenshot" scale="40" fileref="screenshots/login.png"></graphic></screenshot>
</para>

<para>
    <emphasis>Figure 4.1. Login screen of the agent interface.</emphasis>
</para>

</section>

<section id="customer-interface">
<title>Customer web interface</title>

<para>
Customers have a special web interface in OTRS. Through this web interface
customers can create new accounts, get an overview on own tickets, create
and edit tickets, change their account settings, etc.
</para>

<para>
Supposing that the host with the OTRS installation is reachable via the
domain <ulink url="http://www.example.com/">
<citetitle>http://www.example.com</citetitle> </ulink> then the login screen
for customers can be reached by the URL <ulink
url="http://www.example.com/otrs/customer.pl">
<citetitle>http://www.example.com/otrs/customer.pl</citetitle> </ulink> with
a web browser (see Figure 4.2 below).
</para>

<para>
<screenshot>
<screeninfo>customer.pl - Customer login screen</screeninfo> <graphic srccredit="customer.pl -
screenshot" scale="40" fileref="screenshots/customer-login.png"></graphic></screenshot>
</para>

<para>
    <emphasis>Figure 4.2. Login screen of the customer interface.</emphasis>
</para>

</section>

<section id="public-interface">
<title>Public web interface</title>

<para>
In addition to the web interfaces for agents and customers, OTRS has a
public web interface (see Figure 4.3 below) that is available through the
FAQ-Module (must be installed separately). It provides public access to the
FAQ system, and lets visitors search through the FAQ entries without any
authorization.
</para>


<para>
Supposing that the host with the OTRS installation is reachable via the
domain <ulink url="http://www.example.com/">
<citetitle>http://www.example.com</citetitle> </ulink> then the public web
interface can be reached via the URL <ulink
url="http://www.example.com/otrs/faq.pl">
<citetitle>http://www.example.com/otrs/faq.pl</citetitle> </ulink> . Also
the address <ulink url="http://www.example.com/otrs/public.pl">
<citetitle>http://www.example.com/otrs/public.pl</citetitle> </ulink> makes
it possible to access the FAQ system.
</para>

<para>
<screenshot>
<screeninfo>public.pl - Public web interface</screeninfo> <graphic srccredit="public.pl -
screenshot" scale="40" fileref="screenshots/public-interface.png"></graphic></screenshot>
</para>

<para>
    <emphasis>Figure 4.3. Public web interface.</emphasis>
</para>

</section>

<section id="first-login">
<title>First login</title>

<para>
Access to the login screen, as described in the section about <link
linkend="agent-interface"> the agent web interface </link>
</para>

<para>
The login screen lets you enter a user name and a password. Because no users
are created after a fresh installation of the system, you have to login as
OTRS administrator first, using "root@localhost" for username and "root" for
password.
</para>

<warning>
<para>
This account data is valid on every new installed OTRS system. For that
reason you should change the password for the OTRS administrator as soon as
possible! This can be done via the <link linkend="user-preferences">
preferences </link> for the OTRS administrator account.
</para>
</warning>

<para>
If you don't want to login as OTRS administrator just enter the user name
and password for your normal agent account.
</para>

<para>
If you have forgotten your password, you can get a new password through the
system. Just press in the link below the login button and enter the mail
address that is registered for you OTRS account into the input field and
press the submit button (see Figure 4.4).
</para>

<para>
<screenshot>
<screeninfo>login.pl - Request new password</screeninfo> <graphic srccredit="login.pl -
screenshot" scale="40"
fileref="screenshots/request-new-password.png"></graphic></screenshot>
</para>

<para>
    <emphasis>Figure 4.4. Request new password.</emphasis>
</para>

</section>

<section id="gui-overview">
<title>An overview to the web interface</title>

<para>
After you have successfully logged into the system, the web interface is
loaded.  Per default you are in the Dashboard after the login (see Figure
4.5 below).  The Dashboard is completely customizable. At the beginnig it
shows your locked tickets, allows direct access to the views: queue, status
and escalation, and also to create new phone and e-mail tickets. Besides, it
gives you a quick summary of the tickets which are: pending, escalated, new
and open, among other things.
</para>

<para>
<screenshot>
<screeninfo>Screen after first successfull login</screeninfo> <graphic srccredit="First screen -
screenshot" scale="40" fileref="screenshots/first-screen.png"></graphic></screenshot>
</para>

<para>
    <emphasis>Figure 4.5. Dashboard of the agent interface.</emphasis>
</para>

<para>
To improve the clarity, the web interface is separated into different
areas.  At the very top of the windows, there is some general information,
like the current username, the logout button, icons that show the amount of
locked tickets and allow direct access to them, links to create a new
phone/e-mail ticket. It also gives you the change to go to the queue, status
and escalation views.
</para>

<para>
Below the icons is the navigation bar. It shows buttons that enable you to
navigate to different areas or modules of the system and let you execute
some global actions. By pressing the Dashboard button, you can go to the
dashboard (default start page, after login). If you click on the Ticket
button, you will get a submenu with the different valid operations, like
changing the ticket's view, create a new ticket (phone/e-mail) or search for
a specific ticket.  The Statistics button is also a menu that allows
choosing from having an overview of the registered statistics, create a new
one or import an existing one. The Customers button leads you to the
Customer Managment. By clicking the Admin button, you can access to all the
administrator modules, where you can, e.g. create new agents, queues,
etc. There is also a Search button to make ticket searches.
</para>

<para>
If some additional application are installed, e.g. the file manager or the
web mailer, buttons to reach this applications are also displayed.
</para>

<para>
The red bar below the navbar shows different system messages. If you are
logged in as OTRS administrator you get a message, that you should not work
as administrator.
</para>

<para>
Below the title of the section you are currently in, there are several
subsections (each of them in a separate box), which can be dragged and
dropped to reallocate them, as long as they remain in the same column. In
order to drag the single elements, you need to place the cursor in the
header of the element.
</para>

<para>
In the left column you can see the data about some tickets (if available),
clasified in: reminder, escalated, new and open. In each of the categories,
you are also able to see all tickets you are allowed to access or how many
tickets you have locked and how many are located in "My Queues".
</para>

<para>
"My Queues" are the queues, that you want to observe more attentive. You can
select them in your <link linkend="user-preferences"> account preferences
</link> .
</para>

<para>
In the right column you can find the current settings, which will be
expanded/hidden by pressing in the Settings area, as shown in the Figure 4.6
(this section is fixed, so you can not drag and drop it). Once you accessed
to the settings, you can check/unchecked the items and save your changes.
</para>

<para>
<screenshot>
<screeninfo>Edit the dashboard's settings</screeninfo> <graphic srccredit="Dashboard's
settings" scale="40" fileref="screenshots/edit-settings.png"></graphic></screenshot>
</para>

<para>
    <emphasis>Figure 4.6. Settings of the dashboard.</emphasis>
</para>

<para>
Below the settings you can see a statistic of the last 7 days' tickets, as
you might expect, this graphic will be empty in a brand new system. There is
also a section for upcoming events and OTRS news.
</para>

<para>
On the bottom of the screen the site footer is displayed (see Figure 4.7
below). It contains some links to directly access to the OTRS official
website, get information about OTRS, ask for help or go to the top of the
page.
</para>

<para>
<screenshot>
<screeninfo>Footer</screeninfo> <graphic srccredit="Footer"
scale="40" fileref="screenshots/footer.png"></graphic></screenshot>
</para>

<para>
    <emphasis>Figure 4.7. Footer.</emphasis>
</para>

</section>

<section id="what-is-a-queue">
<title>What is a queue?</title>

<para>
Because queues are very important in OTRS, this section tries to explain
more detailed their meaning.
</para>

<para>
On common mail systems all messages are into an inbox file. An inbox is a
big file where the messages are stored. New messages are appended at the end
of the inbox file. The mail program, which is used to read and write mails,
reads the inbox file and presents the content to the user.
</para>

<para>
A queue in OTRS, is somehow comparable to an inbox file, but has some extra
features. It also can store many messages, but the mails are saved in
another way. You don't need to know any detail of queues if you only want to
use OTRS, the only important thing to know is in which queue a ticket is
stored. The users of OTRS, better called agents, can open and edit tickets
in a queue and of course they can move tickets from one queue to another.
But why should they move tickets?
</para>

<para>
To explain it more practically, remember Max's company describe in the
section about a <link linkend="basic-tts-example"> example of a ticket
system </link> . Max installed OTRS to get rid of his support chaos. His
agents and himself are using the system to manage the support requests for
the video recorders.
</para>

<para>
One queue that contains all request is enough for this situation. However,
after some time, Max decides to also sell DVD recorders.  Now, the customers
not only have questions about the video recorder, but also about the new
product. More and more emails get into the one queue of Max's OTRS and it's
hard to keep the overview.
</para>

<para>
One day, Max decides to optimize the structure of his support system and
adds two new queues, thus now three queues are used. Into the old queue
("raw") all mails are stored if they arrive at the ticket system. The two
new queues are one for the video recorder ("video recorder") and the other
one for the dvd recorder requests ("dvd recorder").
</para>

<para>
Max asks Sandra to watch the "raw" queue and sort (dispatch) the mails
either into "video recorder" or "dvd recorder", depending on what the
customer is asking.  John only has access to the "video reorder" queue, Joe
can only answer tickets in the "dvd recorder" queue. Max is able to edit
tickets in all queues.
</para>

<para>
Because OTRS supports access management for users, groups and roles, it is
easy to setup queues that only are accessible for some specific
accounts. Max could also use another way to get his requests into the
different queues, with filter rules or if two different mail addresses are
used Sandra only has to dispatch emails into the two other queues, that
can't be dispatched automatically.
</para>

<para>
Sorting your incoming messages into different queues helps you to keep the
support system structured and tidy. Because your agents are arranged into
different groups with different access rights onto queues, the system can be
optimized even more. Queues can be used to define work flow processes or to
create the structure of a company. Max could implement, for example, another
queue called "sales", which could contain the sub queues "requests",
"offers", "orders", "billing", etc. Such a queue structure could help Max to
optimize his order transactions.
</para>

<para>
The better a system is structured, the less time is needed for the different
tasks. That results in less working time, consequently less money. Queues
can help to optimize the processes in your company.
</para>
</section>

<section id="user-preferences">
<title>User preferences</title>

<para>
Many settings of a user account in OTRS can be customized to meet each one
needs, via the user preferences. Customers, agents and the OTRS
administrator have the possibility to adjust their own account
preferences. In order to do so, agents have to click on their name at the
right top corner of the web interface (see Figure 4.8 below), and customers
must click on the "Preferences" link (see Figure 4.9 below).
</para>

<para>
<screenshot>
<screeninfo>Account preference screen for agents</screeninfo> <graphic srccredit="index.pl -
screenshot" scale="40"
fileref="screenshots/agent-preferences.png"></graphic></screenshot>
</para>

<para>
    <emphasis>Figure 4.8. Agent's personal preferences.</emphasis>
</para>

<para>
An agent can configure 3 different categories of preferences: user profile,
email settings and other settings. The default posibilities are:
</para>

<itemizedlist>
    <title>User Profile</title>
    <listitem>
        <para>Change the current password.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
        <para>Adjust the interface language.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
        <para>Choose the default spelling dictionary.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
        <para>Switch the frontend skin to wear.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
        <para>Shift the frontend theme.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
        <para>Activate and configure the out of office time.</para>
    </listitem>
</itemizedlist>

<itemizedlist>
    <title>Email Settings</title>
    <listitem>
        <para>
Select the events when the system shall send a notification to the email
address.
        </para>
    </listitem>
</itemizedlist>

<itemizedlist>
    <title>Other Settings</title>
    <listitem>
        <para>Select the queues you want to monitor in "My Queues".</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
        <para>Set the refresh period for the queue view.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
        <para>Choose the screen that should be displayed after a ticket is created.</para>
    </listitem>
</itemizedlist>

<para>
<screenshot>
<screeninfo>Account preferences screen for customers</screeninfo> <graphic srccredit="customer.pl -
screenshot" scale="40"
fileref="screenshots/customer-preferences.png"></graphic></screenshot>
</para>

<para>
    <emphasis>Figure 4.8. Customer's personal preferences.</emphasis>
</para>

<para>
A customer can select the web interface language, the refresh period for the
ticket overview, manage the S/MIME certificates and choose the maximum
amount of shown tickets. It is also possible to set a new password.
</para>
</section>

</chapter>
