<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">


<!-- $Id: genericinterface-webservice-gui.xml,v 1.6 2013-01-18 07:26:37 mg Exp $ -->
<section id="webservice_gui">
    <title>Графический интерфейс веб-сервиса</title>
    <para>
        Графический пользовательский интерфейс является тем инструментом, который
позволяет создавать сложные настройки веб-сервиса в дружественной и приятной
среде интерфейса. Он позволяет:
    </para>
    <para>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Создание и Удалинеи веб-сервисов
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Импортировать и Экспортировать настройки (в формате YAML) для существующих
веб-сервисов.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Просматривать, Возвращаться и Экспортировать устаревшие конфигурационные
параметры для существующих веб-сервисов на странице истории конфигурации.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Отслеживать все сообщения журнала для каждого из веб-сервисов на странице
Отладчика.
                </para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
    </para>

    <section id="webservice_gui_overview">
        <title>Обзор Веб-интерфейса</title>
        <para>
            The "Web Services" link in the main screen of Admin Interface (in the System
Administration box) leads to the web services overview screen, where you are
able to manage your web service configurations. You can add new web services
or change the configuration of the existing ones from this screen.
        </para>
        <para>
            Every web service configuration screen has in the upper part of the screen a
navigation path in a "bread crumbs" style. This navigation path is useful to
know exactly in which part of the web service configuration we are, and also
we can jump back to any level of the configuration at any time (this action
will not save any changes).
        </para>
        <note>
            <para>
                To create a new web service, press the button "Add web service", and provide
the needed information.
            </para>
        </note>
        <para>
            <screenshot>
<screeninfo>Обзор Веб-интерфейса</screeninfo> <graphic srccredit="Adminarea web
service - screenshot" scale="40"
fileref="screenshots/genericinterface-webservice-overview.png"></graphic></screenshot>
        </para>
        <para>
            <emphasis>Рисунок: Обзор Веб-сервисов</emphasis>
        </para>
    </section>

    <section id="webservice_gui_add">
        <title>Добавить Веб Сервис</title>
        <para>
            The only required field in this part is the web service "Name" that needs to
be unique in the system and non empty. Other fields are also necessary for
the configuration like the "Debug Threshold" and "Validity" but these fields
are already filled with the default value for each list.
        </para>
        <para>
            The default value for "Debug Threshold" is "debug", under this configuration
all communication logs are registered in the database, each Debug Threshold
value is more restrictive and discard communication logs set for lower
values.
        </para>
        <para>
            <itemizedlist>
                <title>Отладка уровней (от нижних к верхним)</title>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        Отладка
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        Информация
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        Уведомление
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        Ошибка
                    </para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </para>
        <para>
            Также есть возможность определить протокол транспортной сети для "OTRS как
Поставщика" и "OTRS как Запрашиваемую Сторону".
        </para>
        <para>
            Нажмите кнопку "Сохнанить", чтобы зарегистрировать новый веб-сервис в базе
данных или кнопку "Отменить" чтобы отменить эту операцию.
        </para>
        <para>
            If you already have a web service configuration file in YAML format you can
click on the "Import web service" button on the left side of the screen. For
more information on importing web services please check the next section
"Web Service Change".
        </para>
        <note>
            <para>
                Нажмите на имя веб-сервиса на странице просмотра чтобы изменить или добавить
больше элементов веб-сервису.
            </para>
        </note>
        <para>
            <screenshot>
<screeninfo>Добавить Веб-сервис</screeninfo> <graphic srccredit="Adminarea web
service add - screenshot" scale="40"
fileref="screenshots/genericinterface-webservice-add.png"></graphic></screenshot>
        </para>
        <para>
            <emphasis>Рисунок: Добавление нового веб-сервиса</emphasis>
        </para>
    </section>

    <section id="webservice_gui_change">
        <title>Изменения веб-сервиса:</title>
        <para>
            On this screen you have a complete set of functions to handle every part of
a web service. On the left side in the action column you can find some
buttons that allows you to perform all possible actions on a web service:
        </para>
        <para>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Клонирование веб-сервиса.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Экспортировать веб-сервис.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Импортировать веб-сервис.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    История конфигурации.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Удалить веб-сервис.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    Отладчик.
                </para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        </para>
        <note>
            <para>
                Переход к "История конфигурации" и "Отладчик" приведет к открытию различных
страниц.
            </para>
        </note>

        <section id="webservice-clone">
            <title>Клонирование веб-сервиса:</title>
            <para>
                Для клонирования веб-сервиса необходимо нажать кнопку "Клонировать
веб-сервис", появится диалоговое окно, в котором можно использовать имя по
умолчанию или же установить новое имя для клонируемого веб-сервиса.
            </para>
            <note>
                <para>
                    <emphasis>Запомните </emphasis> название веб-сервиса должно быть уникальным
для всей системы.
                </para>
            </note>
            <para>Нажмите кнопку "Клонировать" чтобы создать копию веб-сервиса или кнопку
"Отменитьl", чтобы закрыть диалоговое окно.</para>
            <para>
                <screenshot>
<screeninfo>Клонирование веб-сервиса</screeninfo> <graphic srccredit="Adminarea web
service clone - screenshot" scale="40"
fileref="screenshots/genericinterface-webservice-clone.png"></graphic></screenshot>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emphasis>Рисунок: Клонирование веб-сервиса.</emphasis>
            </para>
        </section>

        <section id="webservice-export">
            <title>Экспорт веб-сервиса</title>
            <para>
                The "Export web service" button gives you the opportunity to dump the
configuration of the current web service into a YAML file, download it and
store it on your file system. This can be specially useful if you want to
migrate the web service from one server to another, for example from a
testing environment to a production system.
            </para>
            <warning>
                <para>
                    Все сохраненные пароли в настройках веб-сервиса будут экспортированы в виде
обычного текста.
                </para>
            </warning>
            <para>
                Сразу же после нажатия кнопки "Экспорт веб-сервиса" появится диалоговое окно
сохранения, на подобе того, которое появляется когда вы нажимаете в браузере
ссылку сохранить.
            </para>
            <note>
                <para>
                    Each browser on each operating system has its own save dialog screen and
style, depending on the browser and its configuration it is possible that no
dialog is shown and the file is saved to a default directory on your file
system. Please check your browser documentation for more specific
instructions if needed.
                </para>
            </note>
            <para>
                <screenshot>
<screeninfo>Экспорт веб-сервиса</screeninfo> <graphic srccredit="Adminarea web
service export - screenshot" scale="40"
fileref="screenshots/genericinterface-webservice-export.png"></graphic></screenshot>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emphasis>Рисунок: Экспорт веб-сервиса.</emphasis>
            </para>
        </section>

        <section id="webservice-import">
            <title>Импорт веб-сервиса:</title>
            <para>
                A valid web service configuration YAML file is required to use the import
web service feature. Click on the "Import web service" button, browse for
the configuration file or provide the complete path in the input box.
            </para>
            <para>
                Нажмите кнопку "Импорт" чтобы создать новый веб-сервис с файла или кнопку
"Отменить" чтобы закрыть диалоговое окно.
            </para>
            <note>
                <para>
                    The web service name will be taken from the configuration file name (e.g. if
the file name is MyWebservice.yml the resulting web service will be named
MyWebservice). If a web service is registered in the system with the same
name as the web service that you want to import, the system will lead you to
the web service change screen to let you change the name of the imported web
service.
                </para>
            </note>
            <para>
                <screenshot>
<screeninfo>Импорт веб-сервиса</screeninfo> <graphic srccredit="Adminarea web
service import - screenshot" scale="40"
fileref="screenshots/genericinterface-webservice-import.png"></graphic></screenshot>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emphasis>Рисунок: Импорт веб-сервиса.</emphasis>
            </para>
        </section>

        <section id="webservice-history">
            <title>История веб-сервиса</title>
            <para>
                Every change to the web service configuration creates a new entry in the web
service history (as a journal). The web service history screen displays a
list of all configuration versions for a web service. Each row (version) in
the "Configuration History List" represents a single revision in the web
service history.
            </para>
            <para>
                Click on one of the rows to show the whole configuration as it was on that
particular date / time. The configuration will be shown in the "History
details" section of this screen. Here you are also able to export the
selected web service configuration version or to restore that version into
the current web service configuration.
            </para>
            <para>
                "Экспортировать настройки веб-сервиса" ведет себя точно так же как
"Экспортировать веб-сервис". Для более подробной информации обратитесь к
этому разделу.
            </para>
            <para>
                If changes to the current web service configuration does not work as
expected and it is not easy to revert the changes manually, you can click on
the "Revert web service configuration" button. This will open a dialog to
ask you if you are sure to revert the web service configuration. Click
"Revert web service configuration" in this dialog to replace the current
configuration with the selected version, or click "Cancel" to close the
dialog.
            </para>
            <warning>
                <para>
                    Помните, что все пароли сохраненные в конфигурации веб-сервиса будут
экспортироваться в виде обычного текста.
                </para>
                <para>
                    Пожалуйста, будьте внимательны при восстановление параметров конфигурации,
эта операция не может быть отменена.
                </para>
            </warning>
            <para>
                <screenshot>
<screeninfo>История веб-сервиса</screeninfo> <graphic srccredit="Adminarea web
service history - screenshot" scale="40"
fileref="screenshots/genericinterface-webservice-history.png"></graphic></screenshot>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emphasis>Рисунок: История веб-сервиса</emphasis>
            </para>
        </section>

        <section id="webservice-delete">
            <title>Удаление веб-сервиса</title>
            <para>
                Иногда возникает необходимость удалить веб-сервис полностью. Для этого можно
нажать кнопку "Удалить веб-сервис", появится диалоговое окно с вопросом о
подтверждении операции.
            </para>
            <para>
                Кликните на кнопку "Удалить" чтобы подтвердить удаление веб-сервиса или
кнопку "Отменить" чтобы закрыть диалоговое окно.
            </para>
            <warning>
                <para>
                    Операция удаления веб-сервиса не может быть отменена, пожалуйста, будьте
внимательны при удалении веб-сервисов.
                </para>
             </warning>
            <para>
                <screenshot>
<screeninfo>Удаление веб-сервиса</screeninfo> <graphic srccredit="Adminarea web
service delete - screenshot" scale="40"
fileref="screenshots/genericinterface-webservice-delete.png"></graphic></screenshot>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emphasis>Рисунок: Удаление веб-сервиса</emphasis>
            </para>
        </section>

        <section id="webservice-debugger">
            <title>Отладчик веб-сервиса:</title>
            <para>
                Отладчик хранит журнал веб-сервиса. На странице отладчика можно следить за
всеми связями веб-сервера, когда он работает в роли поставщика и получателя.
            </para>
            <para>
                Когда отображается эта страница начинает загружаться список запросов. После
того как список будет полность загружен, можно выбрать одну из строк (что
означает последовательность связей) и просмотреть подробню информацию. Эта
информация будет отображаться во всплывающем окне ниже.
            </para>
            <para>
                Можно сузить список используя фильтр в правой части страницы. Фильтрацию
можно производить по:
            </para>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        Тип связи (поставщик или запрашиваемая сторона)
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        Дата: до и / или после определенной даты
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        Удаленный IP-адрес
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        Сочетание всех.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
            <para>
                После того как настройки фильтра завершены, нажмите кнопку "Обновить" и
новый список, отвечающий вашим критериям будет отображен.
            </para>
            <note>
                <para>
                    В зависимости от критериев поиска установленых в фильтре,  новый поиск может
вернуть пустой список.
                </para>
            </note>
            <para>
                On the left part of the screen under the action column you can select "Go
back to the web service" or clear the debugger log by pushing the "Clear"
button.  This will open a dialog that ask you to confirm erasing of the
log. Click "Clear" in the dialog button to perform the action or click on
"Cancel" to close this dialog.
            </para>
            <para>
                В разделе "Подробности Запроса" можно просматривать подробную информацию о
комуникации. Здесь можно следить за полным потоком и проверять всевозможные
ошибки или подтвержать успешные ответы.
            </para>
            <para>
                <screenshot>
<screeninfo>Отладчик веб-сервиса:</screeninfo> <graphic srccredit="Adminarea web
service debugger - screenshot" scale="40"
fileref="screenshots/genericinterface-webservice-debugger.png"></graphic></screenshot>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emphasis>Рисунок: Отладчик веб-сервиса.</emphasis>
            </para>
        </section>

        <section id="webservice-configuration-change">
            <title>Изменение настроек веб-службы</title>
            <para>
                Returning to the web service change screen, now we are going to review the
right side of it. Here we have the possibility to modify all the general
data for a web service such as name, description, debug threshold, etc. Also
there are two more sections below that allows us to modify specific
parameters for communication types "OTRS as Provider" and "OTRS as
Requester".
            </para>
            <para>
                The web service configuration needs to be saved on each level. This means
that if a setting is changed, links to other, deeper parts of the
configuration will be disabled forcing to save the current configuration
level. After saving the disabled links will be re-enabled again allowing you
to continue with the configuration.
            </para>
            <para>
                On the "OTRS as provider" section it is possible to set or configure the
network transport protocol. Only network transport backends that are
registered are shown on the list. To configure the network transport click
on the "Configure" button.  It is also possible to add new operations in
this box. To do this select one of the available operations from the "Add
Operation" list. This will lead you to the operation configuration
screen. After saving the new operation it will be listed in the table above.
            </para>
            <para>
                "OTRS как запрашивающая сторона" очень похож на предыдущий, но вместо
"операций" здесь можно добавить invokers
            </para>
            <para>
                Click the "Save" button to save and continue configuring the web service,
"Save and finish" to save and return to the web service overview screen, or
"Cancel" to discard current configuration level changes and return to web
service overview screen.
            </para>
            <para>
                <screenshot>
<screeninfo>Изменение веб-сервиса</screeninfo> <graphic srccredit="Adminarea web
service change - screenshot" scale="40"
fileref="screenshots/genericinterface-webservice-change.png"></graphic></screenshot>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emphasis>Рисунок: Изменения веб-службы.</emphasis>
            </para>
            <note>
                <para>
                    Like the other Generic Interface configuration screens such as Network
Transport, operation, Invoker and Mapping, the initial configuration (add)
screen will only present two options: "Save" and "Cancel", when the
configuration is re-visited then a new option "Save and Finish" will
appear.  The behavior of this feature is defined below.
                </para>
                <para>
                    "Save" will store the current configuration level in the database and it
will return to the same screen to review your changes or to configure deeper
settings.
                </para>
                <para>
                    "Save and Finish" сохнанит текущий уровень настроек в базе данных и вернется
к предыдущей странице в иерархии конфигурации.
                </para>
                <para>
                    "Отменить" будет отменять любые изменения конфигурации и возвращать их к
текущему уровню конфигурации, после чего возвращаться на к предыдущему
экрану в иерархии настроек.
                </para>
            </note>

        <section id="webservice-provider-network-transport">
            <title>Транспортаня сеть Веб-сервиса</title>
            <para>
                In future the list of available network transports will be
increased. Currently only the "HTTP::SOAP" transport is available. Each
transport has different configuration options to setup and they might use
different frontend modules to configure it, but mostly they should look
similar to the "HTTP::SOAP" transport configuration module.
            </para>
            <para>
                For "HTTP::SOAP" protocol as provider the configuration is quite simple.
There are only two settings: "Namespace" and "Maximum message length". These
fields are required. The first one is a URI to give SOAP methods a context,
reducing ambiguities, and the second one it's a field where you can specify
the maximum size (in bytes) for SOAP messages that OTRS will process.
            </para>
            <para>
                <screenshot>
<screeninfo>Транспортаня сеть Веб-сервиса</screeninfo> <graphic srccredit="Adminarea web
service provider network transport - screenshot" scale="40"
fileref="screenshots/genericinterface-webservice-provider-transport.png"></graphic></screenshot>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emphasis>Рисунок: Транспортаня сеть Веб-сервиса.</emphasis>
            </para>
        </section>

        <section id="webservice-operation">
            <title>Операции веб-сервиса</title>
            <para>
                The actions that can be performed when you are using OTRS as a provider are
called "Operations". Each operation belongs to a controller. Controllers are
collections of operations or invokers, normally operations from the same
controller need similar settings and shares the same configuration
dialog. But each operation can have independent configuration dialogs if
needed.
            </para>
            <para>
                Name, Description, Backend, and Mappings are fields that normally appear on
every operation, other special fields can appear in non default
configuration dialogs to fulfill specific needs of the operation.
            </para>
            <para>
                Normally there are two mapping configuration sections on each operation, one
for the incoming data and another one for the outgoing data. You can choose
different mapping types (backends) for each mapping direction, since their
configuration is independent from each other and also independent from the
operation backend. The normal and most common practice is that the operation
uses same mapping type in both cases (with inverted configuration). The
complete mapping configuration is done in a separate screen which depends on
the mapping type.
            </para>
            <para>
                The operation backend is pre-filled and is not editable. You will see this
parameter when you choose the operation on the web service edit screen. The
field is only informative.
            </para>
            <para>
                In the left part of the screen on the action column you have the options:
"Go back to web service" (discarding all changes since the last save) and
"Delete". If you click on the last one, a dialog will open and ask you if
you like to remove the operation. Click on "Delete" button to confirm the
removal of the operation and it configuration or "Cancel" to close the
delete dialog.
            </para>
            <para>
                <screenshot>
<screeninfo>Операции веб-сервиса</screeninfo> <graphic srccredit="Adminarea web
service operation - screenshot" scale="40"
fileref="screenshots/genericinterface-webservice-operation.png"></graphic></screenshot>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emphasis>Рисунок: Операции веб-сервиса</emphasis>
            </para>
        </section>

           <section id="webservice-requester-transport">
                <title>Web Service Provider Transport</title>
                <para>
                    The network transport configuration for the requester is similar to the
configuration for the provider. For the Requester "HTTP::SOAP" network
transport there are more fields to be set.
                </para>
                <para>
                    Apart from the "Endpoint" (URI of the Remote System web service interface to
accept requests) and "Namespace" which are required fields, you can also
specify:
                </para>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>
                            Кодировка (такая как utf-8, latin1, iso-8859-1, cp1250, и т.д.) для
SOAP-сообщений.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>
                            SOAPAction Header: you can use this to send an empty or filled SOAPAction
header.  Set to "No" and the SOAPAction header on the SOAP message will be
an empty string, or set to "Yes" to send the soap action in Namespace#Action
format and define the separator (typically "/" for .Net web services and "#"
for the rest).
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>
                            Аутентификация: установить механизм аутентификации, установлено в "-" чтобы
не использовать любую проверку подлинности или выбрать ее из списка, после
чего появится поле с подробной информацией.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
                <note>
                    <para>
                        Currently only the "BasicAuth" (HTTP) authentication mechanism is
implemented.  You can decide whether or not to use it depending on the
Remote System configuration. If used, you must provide the User Name and the
Password to access the remote system.
                    </para>
                </note>
                <warning>
                    <para>
                        If you supply a password for authentication and after you export the web
service to a YAML file this password will be revealed and will be written
into a plain text string inside the YAML file. Be aware of it and take
precautions if needed.
                    </para>
                </warning>
                <para>
                    <screenshot>
<screeninfo>Web Service Requester Network Transport</screeninfo> <graphic srccredit="Adminarea web
service requester network transport - screenshot" scale="40"
fileref="screenshots/genericinterface-webservice-requester-transport.png"></graphic></screenshot>
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emphasis>Figure: Web service requester network transport.</emphasis>
                </para>
            </section>

            <section id="webservice-invoker">
                <title>Вызов веб-сервиса:</title>
                <para>
                    The actions that can be performed when you are using OTRS as a requester are
called "Invokers". Each invoker belongs to a controller (controllers are
collections of operations or invokers), normally invokers from the same
controller need similar settings and share the same configuration dialogs.
Each invoker can have independent configuration dialogs if needed.
                </para>
                <para>
                    Name, Description, Backend, and Mappings are fields that normally appear on
every invoker, as well as the list of event triggers other special fields
can appear on non default configuration dialogs to fulfill special needs of
the invoker.
                </para>
                <para>
                    Normally there are two mapping configuration sections for each invoker, one
for the incoming data and another one for the outgoing data. You can choose
different mapping types (backends) for each mapping direction, since their
configuration is independent from each other and also independent from the
invoker backend. The normal and most common practice is that the invoker
uses the same mapping type in both cases, with inverted configuration. The
complete mapping configuration is done in a separate screen, which depends
on the mapping type.
                </para>
                <para>
                    The invoker backend is pre-filled and is not editable. You will see this
parameter when you choose the invoker on the web service edit screen. The
field is only informative.  informative.
                </para>
                <para>
                    Event triggers are events within OTRS such as "TicketCreate", "ArticleSend",
etc.  These can act as triggers to execute the invoker. Each invoker needs
to have at least one event trigger registered, or the invoker will be
useless, because it will never be called. The asynchronous property of the
event triggers define if the OTRS process will handle the invoker or if it
will be delegated to the Scheduler.
                </para>
                <note>
                    <para>
                        The OTRS Scheduler is a separated process that executes tasks in the
background.  Using this the OTRS process itself will not be affected if the
Remote System takes a long time to respond, if it is not available or if
there are network problems. If you don't use the scheduler using web
services can make OTRS slow or non-responsive. Therefore it is highly
recommend to use asynchronous event triggers as often as possible.
                    </para>
                </note>
                <para>
                    To add an Event trigger first select the event family from the first list,
then the event name from the second list, then set the asynchronous property
(if unchecked means that the event trigger will not be asynchronous) and
then click on the plus button. A new event trigger will be created and it
will be listed on the invoker "Event Triggers" list.
                </para>
                <para>
                    To delete an Event trigger, simply locate the event trigger to be deleted in
the "Event Triggers" list and click on the trash icon at the end of the
row. This will open a dialog that ask you if you are sure to delete the
event trigger. Click "Delete" to remove the event trigger from the list, or
"Cancel" to close the dialog.
                </para>
                <para>
                    In the left part of the screen on the action column you have the options:
"Go back to web service" (discarding all changes since the last save) and
"Delete".  If you click on the last one, a dialog will emerge and ask you if
you like to remove the invoker. Click on the "Delete" button to confirm the
removal of the invoker and its configuration or "Cancel" to close the delete
dialog.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <screenshot>
<screeninfo>Вызов веб-сервиса:</screeninfo> <graphic srccredit="Adminarea web
service invoker - screenshot" scale="40"
fileref="screenshots/genericinterface-webservice-invoker.png"></graphic></screenshot>
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emphasis>Figure: Web service invoker.</emphasis>
                </para>
            </section>

            <section id="webservice-mapping">
                <title>Web Service Mapping</title>
                <para>
                    There are cases where you need to transform the data from one format to
another (map or change data structure), because normally a web service is
used to interact with a Remote System, that is highly probable that is not
another OTRS system and / or could not understand the OTRS data structures
and values. In these cases some or all values has to be changed, and
sometimes even the names of the values (keys) or sometimes the complete
structure, in order to match with the expected data on the other end. To
accomplish this task the the Generic Interface Mapping Layer exists.
                </para>
                <para>
                    Each Remote System has it own data structures and it is possible to create
new mapping modules for each case (e.g. there is a customized mapping module
for SAP Solution Manager shipped with OTRS), but it is not always
necessary.  The module Mapping::Simple should cover most of the mapping
needs.
                </para>
                <note>
                    <para>
                        Если Mapping::Simple не покрывает все потребности в отображении для
веб-сервиса, поэтому должен быть создан новый модуль отображения. Чтобы
узнать больше о том как создавать новый модуль отображения, пожалуйста
обратитесь к руководству OTRS - Development Manual.
                    </para>
                </note>
                <para>
                    Этот модуль дает возможность установить значение для отображения по
умолчанию для каждого ключа или значения для всех передаваемых данных.
                </para>
                <para>
                    At the beginning of the screen you will see a general section where you can
set the default rules that will apply for all the unmapped keys and
values. there are three options available, these options are listed below:
                </para>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>
                            Не изменять: не касается ключей и значений в любом случае.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>
                            Ignore (drop key/value pair): when this is applied to the key it deletes the
key and value, because when a key is deleted then in consequence it
associated value is deleted too. When this is applied to the value, only the
value is deleted, keeping the key, that now will be associated to an empty
value.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>
                            MapTo (use provided key or value as default): all keys and / or values
without a defined map rule, will use this as default, when you select this
option a new text field will appear to set this default.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
                <para>
                    Clicking on the "+" button for new key map, will display a new box for a
single mapping configuration. You can add as many key mappings as
needed. Just click on the "+" button again and a new mapping box will appear
below the existing one. From this mapping boxes you can define a map for a
single key, with the next options:
                </para>
                <para>
                    <itemizedlist>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>
                                Точное значение(я): строка со старым значением будет заменена новой в случае
полного совпадения "старого" ключа.
                            </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>
                                Регулярное выражение: строки будут изменены с помощью правила
преобразования.
                            </para>
                        </listitem>
                    </itemizedlist>
                </para>
                <para>
                    Pressing the new value map "+" button will display a new row for a value
map.  Here also is possible to define rules for each value to be mapped with
the same options as for the key map (Exact value and Regular
expression). You can add as many values to map as needed, and if you want to
delete one of them, just click on the "-" button for each mapping value row.
                </para>
                <para>
                    Удаление целого раздела ключей отображения возможно, просто нажмите на
кнопку "-", расположеную в верхнем правом углу каждого окна, для которого вы
хотите удалить.
                </para>
                <para>
                    If you need to delete a complete mapping configuration: go back to the
corresponding operation or invoker screen, look for the mapping direction
that you select before and set its value to "-", and save the configuration
to apply changes.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <screenshot>
<screeninfo>Web Service Mapping</screeninfo> <graphic srccredit="Adminarea web
service mapping - screenshot" scale="40"
fileref="screenshots/genericinterface-webservice-mapping.png"></graphic></screenshot>
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emphasis>Figure: Web service mapping.</emphasis>
                </para>
            </section>
        </section>

    </section>
</section>
