<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
    "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">
<!-- $Id: otrs.xml,v 1.4 2013-01-03 12:40:20 mg Exp $ -->

<section id="otrs">
<title>OTRS Help Desk</title>

<abstract>
    <para>
        This chapter describes the features of OTRS Help Desk
        (OTRS). You will find information about the hardware and software
        requirements for OTRS. Additionally, this chapter tells you how to get
        commercial support for OTRS, should you require it, and how to contact the
        community.
    </para>
</abstract>

<section id="otrs-basics">
    <title>Basics</title>

    <para>
        OTRS Help Desk (OTRS) is a web application which is installed on a web
        server and can be used with a web browser.
    </para>

    <para>
        OTRS is separated into several components. The basic component is the
        OTRS framework that contains all central functions for the application and the
        ticket system. Via the web interface of the OTRS framework, it is
        possible to install additional applications such as ITSM modules, integrations
        with Network Monitoring solutions, a knowledge base (FAQ), et cetera.
    </para>
</section>

<section id="features-of-otrs">
    <title>Features</title>

    <para>
        OTRS has many features. The following list gives an overview of the features
        included in the central framework.
    </para>

    <itemizedlist>
      <title>The features of OTRS</title>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Web interface:
        </para>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Easy and initial handling with any modern web browser,
            even with mobile phones or other mobile computers.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            A web interface to administer the system via the web is available.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            A web interface to handle customer requests by employees/agents via the
            web is integrated.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            A web interface for customers is available to write new tickets, check the state
            and answer old tickets and search through their own tickets.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            The web interface can be customized with different themes; own themes
            can be integrated.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Support for many languages.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            The appearance of output templates can be customized (dtl).
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Mails from and into the system can contain multiple attachments.
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Mail interface:
        </para>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Support for mail attachments (MIME support).
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Automatic conversion of HTML into plain text messages (more
            security for dangerous content and enables faster searching).
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Mail can be filtered with the X-OTRS headers of the system or via
            mail addresses, e.g. for spam messages.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            PGP support, creation and import of own keys, signing and
            encrypting outgoing mail, signed and encrypted messages can
            be displayed.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Support for viewing and encrypting S/MIME messages, handling of
            S/MIME certificates.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Auto answers for customers, configurable for every queue.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Email notifications for agents about new tickets, follow-ups or
            unlocked tickets.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Follow-ups by references or In-Reply-To header entries.
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        Tickets:
        </para>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Expanded queue view, fast overview of new requests in a queue.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Tickets can be locked.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Creation of own auto answer templates.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Creation of own auto responders, configurable for every queue.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Ticket history, overview of all events for a ticket (changes of
            ticket states, replies, notes, etc.).
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Print view for tickets.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Adding own (internal or external) notes to a ticket (text and
            attachments).
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Ticket zooming.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Access control lists for tickets can be defined.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Forwarding or bouncing tickets to other mail addresses.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Moving tickets between queues.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Changing/setting the priority of a ticket.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            The working time for every ticket can be counted.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Up-coming tasks for a ticket can be defined (pending features).
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Bulk actions on tickets are possible.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Automatic and timed actions on tickets are possible with the
            "GenericAgent".
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Full text search on all tickets is possible.
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>
        System:
        </para>
        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            OTRS runs on many operating systems (Linux, Solaris, AIX,
            FreeBSD, OpenBSD, Mac OS 10.x, Microsoft Windows).
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            ASP support (active service providing).
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Linking several objects is possible, e.g. tickets and FAQ entries.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Integration of external back-ends for the customer data, e.g. via
            AD, eDirectory or OpenLDAP.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Setting up an own ticket identifier, e.g.
            Call#, Ticket# or Request#.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            The integration of your own ticket counter is possible.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Support of several database systems for the central OTRS back-end,
            e.g. MySQL, PostgreSQL, Oracle, MSSQL).
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Framework to create stats.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            utf-8 support for the front- and back-end.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Authentication for customers via
            database, LDAP, HTTPAuth or Radius.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Support of user accounts, user groups and roles.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Support of different access levels for several systems
            components or queues.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Integration of standard answer texts.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Support of sub queues.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Different salutations and signatures can be defined for every
            queue.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Email notifications for admins.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Information on updates via mail or the web interface.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Escalation for tickets.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Support for different time zones.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Simple integration of own add-ons or applications with the OTRS API.
            </para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Simple creation of own front-ends, e.g. for X11, console.
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>

    <section id="new-features-of-3.2">
        <title>New features of OTRS 3.2</title>
        <section>
        	<title>More customer focused</title>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>The new "Customer Information Center" provides a great dashboard-like view on a customer (company). You can see
                    <itemizedlist>
                        <listitem><para>Escalated, reminder, new and open tickets of the customer company.</para></listitem>
                        <listitem><para>Customer users (contacts) belonging to this customer company, with their individual ticket count and shortcuts for creating new tickets for them.</para></listitem>
                        <listitem><para>An overall ticket status view of the customer company.</para></listitem>
                    </itemizedlist>
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem><para>New feature "switch to customer" makes it possible for an agent with the required permissions to look into the customers's panel with their rights.</para></listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>More customizeable</title>
            <section>
            	<title>Process Management</title>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem><para>The new <link linkend="process-management">process management</link> makes it possible to represent processes within OTRS.</para></listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </section>
            <section>
            	<title>Customer Interface Improvements</title>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem><para>The customer web interface now fully supports AJAX and ACLs.</para></listitem>
                    <listitem><para>It now requires JavaScript and can no longer be used with Internet Explorer 6 or earlier versions.</para></listitem>
                    <listitem><para>In the Customer Interface, you can now set the default ticket type for new tickets. Additionally, you can now also hide the ticket type and use a default value for all tickets created via the customer interface.</para></listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
                </section>
            <section>
            	<title>Agent Interface Improvements</title>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem><para>Agents can now search for tickets based on escalation time.</para></listitem>
                    <listitem><para>Added possibility to show DynamicFields by default in ticket search.</para></listitem>
                    <listitem><para>Screen usage optimizations in the ticket screens to avoid scrolling in popup windows. For each ticket screen, the size of the richtext editor can now be configured separately.</para></listitem>
                    <listitem><para>It is now possible to move tickets to another queue from within the TicketAction dialogs (TicketNote, TicketClose etc.) after activating a configuration option. This is turned off by default.</para></listitem>
                    <listitem><para>Ticket search will now directly jump to the ticket zoom screen if only one ticket was found.</para></listitem>
                    <listitem><para>Added the ability to hide the Article Type from TicketActionCommon-based screens which can be helpful to fit more data in the browser window.</para></listitem>
                    <listitem><para>There is a new out-of-office dashboard widget that lists all currently unavailable agent colleagues.</para></listitem>
                    <listitem><para>New CKEditor 4 makes working with rich text content (such as HTML emails) easier and more stable.</para></listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </section>
            <section>
            	<title>Administration improvements</title>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem><para>Event Based notifications can now be sent out only for specific Article Sender Types.</para></listitem>
                    <listitem><para>The Statistics engine in OTRS now understands 'Weeks' in addition to days, months and years. This means you can for instance now create a report for tickets 'created last week', or generate a report that shows created tickets per queue per week.</para></listitem>
                    <listitem><para>It is possible to place customized DTL (template) files in <code>Custom/Kernel/Output/HTML</code>, so that they override the system's default DTL files just as how this already works for Perl files.</para></listitem>
                    <listitem><para>In AdminSMIME it is now possible to display human readable certificate contents.</para></listitem>
                    <listitem><para>SysConfig now supports config setting types Date and DateTime.</para></listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </section>
        </section>
        <section>
        	<title>Better scalability</title>
            <section>
            	<title>Ticket Archiving Improved</title>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem><para>When tickets are archived, the information which agent read the ticket and articles can be removed, as well as the ticket subscriptions of agents. This is active by default and helps reduce the amount of data in the database on large systems with many tickets and agents.</para></listitem>
                    <listitem><para>There is also a new script to remove this data from existing archived tickets.</para></listitem>
                    <listitem><para>Archived tickets are now always shown as 'read' by the agent.</para></listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </section>
            <section>
            	<title>Performance Improvements</title>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem><para>Session management is up to 10 times faster, especially with many active users.</para></listitem>
                    <listitem><para>It is now possible to limit the number of concurrent agents and/or users to avoid server capacity overload.</para></listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Greatly reduced the number of executed database statements in ticket overviews and ticket masks in agent and customer frontend.
                            <itemizedlist>
                                <listitem><para>This will reduce the load on database servers, especially on large systems. In some cases OTRS will become visibly more responsive (if the system was slowed down by the DB load or latency).</para></listitem>
                            </itemizedlist>
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem><para>Improved performance of LDAP user synchronization.</para></listitem>
                    <listitem><para>Improved cache performance with many cache files.</para></listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </section>
        </section>
        <section>
        	<title>More Interoperable</title>
            <section>
            	<title>FAQ Connector for the GenericInterface</title>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem><para>It is now possible to access the data of the FAQ module (OTRS knowledge database) via web service (GenericInterface). This can be useful to embed FAQ articles on your company website, for example.</para></listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </section>
        </section>
    </section>

    <section id="new-features-of-3.1">
        <title>New features of OTRS 3.1</title>

        <section>
            <title>1 GENERIC INTERFACE - A Web Service Framework</title>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>GI is a flexible framework to allow web service interconnections of OTRS with third party applications.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>OTRS can act in both ways - as a provider (server, requested from remote) or requester (client, requesting remotely).</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Simple web service connections can be created without programming by configuring the Generic Interface.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Complex scenarios can be realized by plugging in custom OTRS extensions that add perl code to the GI infrastructure on different
                        architectural layers.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        <emphasis>Connectors</emphasis> expose parts of OTRS to Generic Interface web services.For example, a ticket connector exposes the ticket
                        create/update function, so that they can be used in a web service regardless which network transport is used.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>A scheduler daemon process supports asynchronous event handling. This is useful to asynchronously start web service requests from OTRS
                        to another system, after the agents request has been answered (e.g. when a ticket has been created). Otherwise, it might block the response,
                        resulting in increased response times for the agent.</para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
            <para>
            With the Generic Interface new web services can be configured easily by using existing OTRS modules, without additional code. They can be combined to
            create a new web service. When configuring a new web service connection, the administrator has to add:
            </para>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>A new web service in the admin GUI</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>The basic meta data (Transport type (SOAP), URL etc.) and</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Existing operations (part of a connector) and specify for each operation how the data must be mapped (inbound and outbound)</para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
            <para>
            A Generic Interface Debugger will help the OTRS administrator to check how requests are coming in and how they are handled through the different
            layers.
            </para>
            <section>
                <title>1.1 Current Features</title>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Network transports: SOAP/HTTP. Others like REST and JSON are scheduled to be added in the future depending on customers demand.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Configurable data mapping Graphical User Interface for key/value transformations with respect to incoming and outgoing data.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Graphical debugger to check the configuration and flow of information of configured web services.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>A ticket connector allowing the use of OTRS as a web service for ticket handling.</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </section>
            <section>
                <title>1.2 Future Features</title>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Additional network transports (REST, JSON).</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>The GI will replace the iPhoneHandle as the backend for mobile apps.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Additional connectors will be added to provide more parts of OTRS for use with web services (e.g. to allow the creation, update or
                            deletion of agents, users, services or CIs).</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </section>
        </section>

        <section>
            <title>2 DYNAMIC FIELDS</title>
            <para>The DynamicFields Feature replaces the existing ticket and article
            FreeText and FreeTime fields with a dynamic structure that will also allow to create custom forms in OTRS.
            </para>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>An unlimited amount of fields can be configured using an own graphical user interface for administration.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>The fields can have different types that can be used for both, tickets and articles. Available by default are:</para>
                    <itemizedlist>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Text</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Multiline text</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Checkbox</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Dropdown</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Multi-select</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Date</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>Date and time</para>
                        </listitem>
                    </itemizedlist>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>New custom field types (e.g. custom field type dropdown with an external data source) can be added with small effort as the fields are
                        created in a modular, pluggable way.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>A future scenario is, that DynamicFields can be used for objects other than tickets or in custom modules. For example, a custom module
                        adding objects to handle "orders" in OTRS could use the DynamicFields to attach properties/data to these orders.</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        A database update script will transform historic FreeText fields and related configuration settings into the new structure.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </section>

        <section>
            <title>3 TICKET MANAGEMENT IMPROVEMENTS</title>
            <section>
                <title>3.1 Ticket creation improved</title>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Multiple email addresses can now be specified as 'To:', 'CC:' or 'BCC:' when creating a new phone or email ticket.</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </section>
            <section>
                <title>3.2 Inbound phone call support</title>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Inbound phone calls can now be registered within an existing tickets (until now, only outbound calls were registered).</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </section>
            <section>
                <title>3.3 Ticket overview preview improved</title>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>It is now possible to exclude articles of certain sender types (e.g. articles from internal agents) in the SysConfig from being
                            displayed in the overview preview mode.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>A certain article type can be configured which will display articles of that type as expanded by default when the view is accessed.</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </section>
            <section>
                <title>3.4 Ticket move improved</title>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>The screen shown after moving a ticket is now configurable. Options are the ticket zoom view (LastScreenView) or the ticket list
                            (LastScreenOverview).</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </section>
            <section>
                <title>3.5 Bulk action improved</title>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>With the new bulk action, outbound emails can now be sent from multiple tickets at the same time. As tickets can have different queues,
                            and these queues each can have different templates, salutations and signatures, these are not used in the Bulk Action email.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>An additional bulk action allows configuring the ticket type for selected tickets.</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </section>
            <section>
                <title>3.6 Configurable Reject Sender Email Address</title>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>The feature allows configuring an email address instead of the administrator address to reject the creation of new tickets by email.
                            This feature can be used in all cases where customers are not allowed to create new tickets by email.</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </section>
        </section>

        <section>
            <title>4 PROCESS AUTOMATION</title>
            <section>
                <title>4.1 Escalation events added</title>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>OTRS will now create events for each of the available escalation types (response, update and resolution). This allows performing
                            actions (such as notifications) before the escalation occurs, in the moment it occurs and in the moment that the escalation ends.</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </section>
            <section>
                <title>4.2 Notification mechanism improved</title>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>A new generic agent notification module allows the OTRS administrator to define messages that will be shown in the agent web front-end
                            when agents log into the system.</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </section>
            <section>
                <title>4.3 Time calculation improved</title>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>All kind of times are from now on calculated by and based on the application server only solving the issues that were caused by
                            variances between the clock times of application and data base servers.</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </section>
            <section>
                <title>4.4 GenericAgent improved</title>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>The GenericAgent can now filter for tickets change time.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>In addition, the GenericAgent can set the ticket responsible for matched tickets.</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </section>
        </section>

        <section>
            <title>5 USER INTERFACE, RICH TEXT EDITOR, CHARSET</title>
            <section>
                <title>5.1 User interface performance improved</title>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>The speed for rendering and article display was improved, thanks to Stelios Gikas &lt;stelios.gikas@noris.net&gt;!</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </section>
            <section>
                <title>5.2 Rich Text Editor Update</title>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>IOS5 support added.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Block quotes can be left with the enter key.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>
                            Update from CKEditor 3.4 to CKEditor 3.6, so improvements refer to the releases of
                            <ulink url="http://ckeditor.com/blog/CKEditor_3.5_released">CKEditor 3.5</ulink> and
                            <ulink url="http://ckeditor.com/blog/CKEditor_3.6_released">CKEditor 3.6</ulink>.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>IE9 support improved.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>Resizable dialogs.</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </section>
            <section>
                <title>5.3 Unicode Support - Non-UTF-8 Internal Encodings Dropped</title>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>UTF-8 is now the only allowed internal charset of OTRS.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>All language files are now formatted in UTF-8, which simplifies their handling and future improvements of the translation mechanism.</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </section>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>6 DATABASE DRIVER SUPPORT</title>
            <section>
                <title>6.1 PostgreSQL DRIVER compatibility improved</title>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>PostgreSQL 9.1 support added.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>A new legacy driver is now available for PostgreSQL 8.1 or earlier versions.</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </section>
            <section>
                <title>6.2 MS SQL DRIVER compatibility improved</title>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>The MS SQL driver now stores binary data in VARBINARY rather than deprecated type TEXT as well as NVARCHAR to store text strings rather
                            than VARCHAR (for improved Unicode support).</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </section>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>7 MAIL INTEGRATION</title>
            <section>
                <title>7.1 Mail handling improved</title>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>When connecting to IMAP mail accounts, it is now possible to handle emails from a specific email folder, other than the INBOX folder.</para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>OTRS can now also connect to IMAP servers using Transport Layer Security (TLS), useful for modern restricted environments.</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </section>
        </section>
    </section>

    <section id="new-features-of-3.0">
        <title>Top new features of OTRS 3.0</title>

        <itemizedlist>
            <title>Context</title>
            <listitem>
                <para>
    User Centered redesign of the Graphical User Interface which
    results in a dramatic shift from a comprehensive but static
    to a more powerful and dynamic application using state-of-the
    art technologies like Ajax, xHTML and optimized CSS.
                </para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <itemizedlist>
            <title>New Ticket and Article Indicator</title>
            <listitem>
                <para>
    This new feature has been implemented on both ticket and article level.
    It allows an agent at a glance to check for any updates within a ticket
    or on the article level to check for new and unread articles. You
    benefit from increased transparency and decreased response times.
                </para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <itemizedlist>
            <title>Optimized Fulltext Search</title>
            <listitem>
                <para>
    The new search feature allows you to flexibly customize the way you browse
    the information base. Options the new search feature provides range from
    single search-string searches to complex multi-string boolean search
    operations including various operators. You benefit from fully
    customizable searches according to your needs.
                </para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <itemizedlist>
            <title>New Ticket Zoom View</title>
            <listitem>
                <para>
    The redesign based on Ajax technology
    allows agents to display complex and linked information
    structures in real-time while keeping the agents' current
    working environment. The agent will benefit from increased
    orientation and increased workflow efficiency.
                </para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <itemizedlist>
            <title>Global Ticket Overviews</title>
            <listitem>
                <para>
    Well known from OTRS 2.4 the global
    ticket overviews have been optimized to achieve increased inter-
    activity. Depending on the use case and preferences of your
    agents they can easily change the ticket overviews layout
    according to their special needs. Options are small, medium
    and large, each providing a different degree of information
    details.
                </para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>


        <itemizedlist>
            <title>Accessibility</title>
            <listitem>
                <para>
    The redesign includes common accessibility standards WCAG and
    WAI-ARIA which also allows disabled users to better interact
    with OTRS Help Desk. The US Rehabilitation Acts Section 508 has
    been fulfilled.
                </para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <itemizedlist>
            <title>New Customer Interface</title>
            <listitem>
                <para>
    The customer web front-end can be integrated to your organizations
    intranet and is fully integrated into the redesigned help desk system.
                </para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <itemizedlist>
            <title>Archive Feature</title>
            <listitem>
                <para>
    OTRS 3.0 now offers a new archiving feature. With a separated archive
    you'll benefit from a reduced time spent for searches and increased
    display of results.
                </para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

    </section>
</section>

<section id="software-requirements">
    <title>Hardware and software requirements</title>

    <para>
    OTRS can be installed on many different operating systems. OTRS can run on
    linux and on other unix derivates (e.g. OpenBSD or FreeBSD). You can also deploy
    it on Microsoft Windows. OTRS does not have excessive hardware requirements. We
    recommend using a machine with at least a 2 GHz Xeon or comparable
    CPU, 2 GB RAM and a 160 GB hard drive for a small setup.
    </para>

    <para>
    To run OTRS you'll also need to use a web server and a database server.
    Apart from that, on the OTRS machine, you should install perl and/or install
    some additional perl modules.
    The web server and <application>Perl</application> have to be installed on the same machine
    as OTRS. The database back-end can be installed locally or on another host.
    </para>

    <para>
    For the web server we recommend using the <application>Apache HTTP Server</application>, because
    its module mod_perl improves greatly the performance of OTRS. Apart from that,
    OTRS should run on any web server that can execute Perl scripts.
    </para>

    <para>
    You can deploy OTRS on different databases. You can choose between <application>MySQL</application>,
     <application>PostgreSQL</application>, <application>Oracle</application>, or
    <application>Microsoft SQL Server</application>.
    If you use <application>MySQL</application> you have the advantage that the database
    and some system settings can be configured during the installation, through a web front-end.
    </para>

    <para>
    For <application>Perl</application>, we recommend using at least version
    5.8.8. You need some additional modules which can be installed either with
    the Perl shell and CPAN or via the package manager of your operating system
    (<application>rpm</application>, <application>yast</application>,
    <application>apt-get</application>).
    </para>

    <para>Software requirements</para>

    <section id="perl-support">
        <title>Perl support</title>
        <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para>Perl 5.8.8 or higher</para>
        </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
    </section>

    <section id="webserver-support">
        <title>Web server support</title>
        <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para>Apache2 + mod_perl2 or higher (recommended, mod_perl is really fast!)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Webserver with CGI support (CGI is not recommended)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Microsoft Internet Information Server (IIS) 6 or higher</para>
        </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
    </section>

    <section id="database-support">
        <title>Database support</title>

        <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para>MySQL 4.1 or higher</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>PostgreSQL 7.0 or higher (8.2 or higher recommended)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Oracle 10g or higher</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>Microsoft SQL Server 2005 or higher</para>
        </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <para>
            The section in the manual about
            <link linkend="installation-of-perl-modules">installation of Perl modules</link>
            describes in more detail how you can set up those which are needed for OTRS.
        </para>

        <para>
        If you install a binary package of OTRS, which was built for your operating
        system (rpm, Windows-Installer), either the package contains all Perl
        modules needed or the package manager of your system should take care of the
        dependencies of the Perl modules needed.
        </para>
    </section>

    <section id="webbrowser-support">
        <title>Web browser support</title>
        <para>
            To use OTRS, you'll be OK if you use a modern browser with JavaScript support enabled.
            We support the following browsers:
        </para>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>Internet Explorer 8.0 or higher (agent interface)</para>
                <para>Internet Explorer 7.0 or higher (customer interface)</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Mozilla Firefox 3.6 or higher</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Google Chrome</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Opera 10 or higher</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Safari 4 or higher</para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        <para>
            We recommend to always use the latest version of your browser, because it has the best JavaScript and rendering performance.
            Dramatical performance varieties between the used browsers can occur with big data or big systems.
            We are happy to consult you on that matter.
        </para>
    </section>
</section>

<section id="community">
    <title>Community</title>

    <para>
    OTRS has a large user community. Users and developers discuss about OTRS and
    interchange information on related issues through the
    <link linkend="additional-resources-mailinglists">mailing-lists</link>.
    You can use the mailing lists to discuss installation,
    configuration, usage, localization and development of OTRS. You can report software bugs
    in our <link linkend="additional-resources-bugtracking">bug tracking system</link>.
    </para>

    <para>
    The homepage of the OTRS community is:
    <ulink url="http://www.otrs.com/open-source/"><citetitle>http://www.otrs.com/open-source/</citetitle></ulink>.
    </para>
</section>

<section id="commercial-support-for-otrs">
    <title>Commercial Support and Services for OTRS</title>

    <para>
    Commercial support for OTRS is also available. You can find the available options on the website of OTRS Group, the company behind OTRS:
    <ulink url="http://www.otrs.com/"><citetitle>http://www.otrs.com/</citetitle></ulink>.
    </para>

    <para>
    OTRS Group provides subscription support services, customization, consulting and
    training for <ulink url="http://www.otrs.com/products/otrs-help-desk/">
    <citetitle>OTRS Help Desk</citetitle></ulink> and <ulink url="http://www.otrs.com/en/products/otrs-itsm/">
    <citetitle>OTRS ITSM</citetitle></ulink>. It also provides
    <ulink url="http://www.otrs.com/solutions/"><citetitle>Best Practice Product Editions</citetitle></ulink>.
    With these Editions, OTRS Group helps organizations to design, deploy and
    optimize OTRS for each unique environment. Additionally, OTRS Group provides
    hosted versions including <ulink url="http://www.otrs.com/en/solutions/ondemand/"><citetitle>OTRS OnDemand
    </citetitle></ulink> and <ulink url="http://www.otrs.com/en/solutions/managed-otrs/"><citetitle>Managed OTRS</citetitle></ulink>.
    </para>

    <para>
    You can find more detailed information about OTRS Group on
    <ulink url="http://www.otrs.com"><citetitle>http://www.otrs.com</citetitle></ulink>
    and you can contact us via email on
    <ulink url="mailto:sales@otrs.com"><citetitle>sales at otrs.com</citetitle></ulink>.
    </para>
</section>

</section>
