<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">


<!-- $Id: scheduler.xml,v 1.2.2.1 2013-02-06 14:50:34 mg Exp $ -->
<chapter id="scheduler">
    <title>OTRS Scheduler</title>
    <para>
        The OTRS Scheduler is an independent system process that executes tasks in
background. These kind of processes are know as <emphasis>daemons</emphasis>
in Unix / Linux systems or as <emphasis>services</emphasis> on Windows
environments. It is independent but that doesn't mean that the Scheduler
does everything alone, it is fully integrated into OTRS and can use any OTRS
module as needed to complete each task.
    </para>
    <para>
        Currently the OTRS Scheduler is only able to handle Generic Interface
tasks. These kind of tasks executes invokers that send requests to remote
systems. Other handlers for different tasks will be added in future OTRS
versions.
    </para>
    <para>
        For sanity reasons the Scheduler process needs to be restarted from time to
time. This is done automatically by the scheduler process itself once a day,
but it can be adjusted as needed using the SysConfig by editing the
"Scheduler::RestartAfterSeconds" setting.
    </para>
    <para>
        The OTRS Scheduler is a set it and forget it process, the only needed human
interaction is to check its status periodically and start or stop it as
needed.
    </para>
    <note>
        <para>
            If the Scheduler is stopped for any reason all pending tasks and new tasks
registered when the Scheduler is stopped will be executed as soon as the
Scheduler starts again (unless the tasks are set to be executed in the
future).
        </para>
    </note>
    <section id="scheduler-gui">
        <title>Scheduler Graphical Interface</title>
        <para>
            The Scheduler is not visible in the OTRS Graphical User Interface unless it
stops running.
        </para>
        <section id="scheduler-gui-notify">
            <title>Scheduler Not Running Notification</title>
            <para>
                There are two different types of notifications if the system detects that
scheduler is not running. This detection is based on the Scheduler process
update frequency, if the difference between current time and the last
process update time is 2 times the process update frequency a warning
message will be displayed in the OTRS notification area. If it is over 4
times the process frequency then an alert will be displayed instead.
            </para>
            <para>
                The Scheduler process update time can be configured via the SysConfig in the
"Scheduler::PIDUpdateTime" setting.
            </para>
            <para>
                If you would see a warning message it is not always necessary to take an
action, but is highly recommended to check if the scheduler process is
running. If you see an alert, then is highly probable that the scheduler is
in fact not running and should be started.
            </para>
            <para>
                By default the Scheduler not running notification is enabled, if there is a
valid web service registered in the database, and is only displayed to the
users in the "admin" group.
            </para>
            <para>
                To disable the notification (not recommended) or to change or add the
notification groups, please edit the
"Frontend::NotifyModule###800-Scheduler-Check" setting in the SysConfig.
            </para>
            <para>
                <screenshot>
<screeninfo>Scheduler Notification</screeninfo> <graphic srccredit="scheduler
notification - screenshot" scale="40"
fileref="screenshots/scheduler-notify.png"></graphic></screenshot>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emphasis>Figure: Scheduler notification.</emphasis>
            </para>
        </section>
        <section id="scheduler-gui-start">
            <title>Start Scheduler</title>
            <para>
                By clicking on the Scheduler not running notification link (either warning
or alert) a dialog box will open to let you start the Scheduler process
again. The Scheduler can be started normally or forced to start, by clicking
on the appropriate check box in the dialog.
            </para>
            <note>
                <para>
                    A forced Scheduler start is only necessary if previous Scheduler process was
terminated abnormally and the Process ID is still registered in the
database.
                </para>
                <para>
                    To have full control of the Scheduler process and to check it real status
please use the command line tools described below.
                </para>
            </note>
            <para>
                <screenshot>
<screeninfo>Start Scheduler</screeninfo> <graphic srccredit="scheduler start
- screenshot" scale="40"
fileref="screenshots/scheduler-start.png"></graphic></screenshot>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emphasis>Figure: Start Scheduler.</emphasis>
            </para>
        </section>
    </section>
    <section id="scheduler-cli">
        <title>Scheduler Command Line Interface</title>
        <para>
            The Scheduler command line tools let you control the Scheduler process
(Start / Stop) or query it status. There are also tools to register the
process to be controlled by the operating system.
        </para>
        <para>
            Included with OTRS there are two set of CLI tools, one for Unix / Linux OS
and another for MS Windows OS.
        </para>
        <section id="scheduler-cli-linux">
            <title>Unix / Linux</title>
            <section id="scheduler-cli-linux-init">
                <title>Scheduler Init.d Files</title>
                <para>
                    Init.d files are special scripts that are called by the operating system at
startup and shutdown (or restart) times.
                </para>
                <para>
                    OTRS provide init.d scripts to start / stop the OTRS Scheduler process
automatically by the operating system, this scripts are located under
OTRS_HOME/scripts.
                </para>
                <para>
                    Init.d scripts needs to be copied to the correct location for your operating
system, they need to had the proper permissions and some internal variables
needs to be set to work properly.
                </para>
                <itemizedlist mark="round">
                    <title>Init.d Script Internal Variables</title>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>
                            <command>OTRS_HOME</command> - the path of your OTRS installation.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>
                            <command>User</command> - the apache process user name.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>
                            <command>Group</command> - the apache process user's group name.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
                <note>
                    <para>
                        Currently there are only init.d scripts for Linux platforms.
                    </para>
                </note>
                <table>
                    <title>List of Init Scripts And Supported Operating Systems</title>
                    <tgroup cols="2">
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry>Init Script</entry>
                            <entry>Supported OS</entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry>otrs-scheduler-linux</entry>
                            <entry>Red Hat, Fedora, CentOS, SUSE, openSUSE, Debian, Ubuntu</entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>otrs-scheduler-gentoo-init.d, otrs-scheduler-gentoo-conf.d</entry>
                            <entry>Gentoo</entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                    </tgroup>
                </table>
                <example>
                    <title>Example To Start The OTRS Scheduler Form An Init.d Script</title>
                    <para>
                        <screen>
                            shell> /etc/init.d/otrs-scheduler-linux start
                        </screen>
                    </para>
                </example>
                <itemizedlist mark="round">
                    <title>Available Actions</title>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>
                            <command>start</command> to start the OTRS Scheduler process.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>
                            <command>stop</command> to stop the OTRS Scheduler process.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>
                            <command>restart</command> to restart the OTRS Scheduler process.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>
                            <command>status</command> to query the OTRS Scheduler process status.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
                <para>
                    The Scheduler needs the database to be available to register its Process ID,
for this reason is necessary to:
                    <itemizedlist mark="round">
                        <listitem>
                            <para>
                                Execute the Scheduler init.d script to <emphasis>start</emphasis> the
Scheduler process after the database process is up and running.
                            </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            <para>
                                Execute the Scheduler init.d script to <emphasis>stop</emphasis> the
Scheduler before the database process shuts down.
                            </para>
                        </listitem>
                    </itemizedlist>
                </para>
                <note>
                    <para>
                        If you want the Scheduler to run at system startup, please read the
documentation of the operating system for the right location to place the
init.d scripts, how to configure them to run automatically and how to set
the run order.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </section>
            <section id="scheduler-cli-linux-daemon">
                <title>Scheduler Daemon File</title>
                <para>
                    This is the part of the Scheduler that stays running in the background
checking for tasks to execute. It also provides the main functions to
control the process.
                </para>
                <para>
                    All Unix / Linux uses the file
<command>OTRS_HOME/bin/otrs.Scheduler.pl</command>.
                </para>
                <example>
                    <title>Example To Start The OTRS Scheduler</title>
                    <para>
                        <screen>
                            shell> OTRS_HOME/bin/otrs.Scheduler.pl -a start
                        </screen>
                    </para>
                </example>
                <itemizedlist mark="round">
                    <title>Available Options</title>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>
                            <command>-a </command> action.
                        </para>
                        <itemizedlist mark="round">
                            <title>Possible Values</title>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>
                                    <command>start</command>- to start the Scheduler process.
                                </para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>
                                    <command>stop</command>- to stop the Scheduler process.
                                </para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>
                                    <command>status</command>- to query Scheduler process status.
                                </para>
                            </listitem>
                        </itemizedlist>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>
                            <command>-f </command> to force the start or stop of the Scheduler process.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
                <example>
                    <title>Example To Force Stop The OTRS Scheduler</title>
                    <para>
                        <screen>
                            shell> OTRS_HOME/bin/otrs.Scheduler.pl -a stop -f 1
                        </screen>
                    </para>
                </example>
                <note>
                    <para>
                        Force stop the Scheduler is used remove the process ID from the database
when scheduler is not running and the process is still registered.
                    </para>
                    <para>
                        Force start the Scheduler is used to start the Scheduler process if the
scheduler is not running and the process is registered.
                    </para>
                    <para>
                        Force start or stop are only necessary if the start of the process is needed
to be done before the process update time expires. Otherwise an expired
entry in the database is discarded by normal start.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </section>
        </section>

       <section id="scheduler-cli-windows">
            <title>Windows</title>
            <section id="scheduler-cli-windows-scm">
                <title>Scheduler Service Installer</title>
                <para>
                    The integration of the services into the MS Windows Operating System is done
via the Windows Service Control Manager (SCM). In order to make the OTRS
Scheduler process to be controlled by the SCM is necessary to register this
service
                </para>
                <para>
                    OTRS provides the script
<command>OTRS_HOME/bin/otrs.Scheduler4WinInstaller.pl</command> to register
or unregister the OTRS Scheduler into the SCM.
                </para>
                <example>
                    <title>Example To Register The OTRS Scheduler Into the Widows SCM</title>
                    <para>
                        <screen>
                            shell> OTRS_HOME/bin/otrs.Scheduler4WinInstaller.pl -a install
                        </screen>
                    </para>
                </example>
                <itemizedlist mark="round">
                    <title>Available Options</title>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>
                            <command>-a </command> action.
                        </para>
                        <itemizedlist mark="round">
                            <title>Possible Values</title>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>
                                    <command>install</command>- to install the Scheduler process into the
Windows SCM.
                                </para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>
                                    <command>remove</command>- to remove the Scheduler process from the Windows
SCM.
                                </para>
                            </listitem>
                        </itemizedlist>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
                <para>
                    After installing into the Widows SCM the OTRS Scheduler process can be used
as any other service in Windows. It can be started, stopped and restarted
and can be configured to be started manually or automatic.
                </para>
                <note>
                    <para>
                        To learn more about Windows Services and the Windows SCM please read the
Windows documentation, and Microsoft online help.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </section>
            <section id="scheduler-cli-linux-service">
                <title>Scheduler Service File</title>
                <para>
                    This is the part of the Scheduler that stays running in the background
checking for tasks to execute. It also provides the main functions to
control the process.
                </para>
                <para>
                    Windows Operating System uses the file
<command>OTRS_HOME/bin/otrs.Scheduler4Win.pl</command>.
                </para>
                <example>
                    <title>Example To Start The OTRS Scheduler</title>
                    <para>
                        <screen>
                            shell> OTRS_HOME/bin/otrs.Scheduler4Win.pl -a start
                        </screen>
                    </para>
                </example>
                <itemizedlist mark="round">
                    <title>Available Options</title>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>
                            <command>-a </command> action.
                        </para>
                        <itemizedlist mark="round">
                            <title>Possible Values</title>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>
                                    <command>start</command>- to start the Scheduler process.
                                </para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>
                                    <command>stop</command>- to stop the Scheduler process.
                                </para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>
                                    <command>status</command>- to query Scheduler process status.
                                </para>
                            </listitem>
                        </itemizedlist>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>
                            <command>-f </command> to force the start or stop of the Scheduler process.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
                <example>
                    <title>Example To Force Stop The OTRS Scheduler</title>
                    <para>
                        <screen>
                            shell> OTRS_HOME/bin/otrs.Scheduler4Win.pl -a stop -f 1
                        </screen>
                    </para>
                </example>
                <note>
                    <para>
                        Force stopping the Scheduler is used to remove the process ID from the
database when scheduler is not running and the process is still registered.
                    </para>
                    <para>
                        Force starting the Scheduler is used to start the Scheduler process if the
scheduler is not running and the process is still registered.
                    </para>
                    <para>
                        Force start or stop are only necessary if starting the process is needed to
be done before the process update time expires. Otherwise an expired entry
in the database would be discarded by a normal start.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </section>
        </section>
    </section>
</chapter>
