<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
  "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">


<!-- $Id: stats.xml,v 1.3 2011-01-20 16:03:37 mg Exp $ -->
<chapter id="statistic-module">
<title>Stats module</title>

<para>
Stats and reports are essential for companies.  On the basis of stats,
information can be evaluated and rated, and eventually informed decisions
can be made.
</para>

<para>
A stats module should meet a multitude of requirements:
</para>

<para>
<itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
        <para>
        Various OTRS modules are to be evaluated.
        </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
        <para>
        Consideration of the user permission settings of the respective
installation.
        </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
        <para>
        Generation of complex statistics.
        </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
        <para>
        Easy and fast configuration of stats.
        </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
        <para>
        High performance.
        </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
        <para>
        Support of a large number of output variants.
        </para>
    </listitem>
</itemizedlist>
</para>

<para>
The OTRS stats module tries to satisfy all these requirements. The core
feature is a GUI, which allows to configure stats with the click of a mouse.
</para>

<para>
Statistical elements, i.e. files which supplement the functionalities of the
stats module for specific requirements, can be integrated to model complex
stats.
</para>

<para>
All requirements concerning the evaluation of personal data have been
considered. It is, for instance, not possible to directly evaluate the
activities of individual agents in the standard configuration.
</para>

<para>
The stats module enables OTRS users to make a quick and easy evaluation of
the activities on their system.
</para>

<section id="stats-usage" >
<title>Handling of the module by the agent</title>

<para>
As soon as the stats module has been installed and configured successfully
by the OTRS admin, the navigation bar of every agent with read and/or write
rights displays the additional module link "Statistics", which has various
action links, as shown in the Figure 19.1.
</para>

<para>
<screenshot>
<screeninfo>The stats module</screeninfo> <graphic
fileref="screenshots/stats-menu.png" scale="40" srccredit="stats-menu -
Screenshot" /></screenshot>
</para>

<para>
    <emphasis>Figure 19.1. Action lists of the statistics.</emphasis>
</para>

<para>
The different options provided in the statistics menu are:
</para>

<para>
<itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
        <para>
            <emphasis>Overview</emphasis>.  Automatically shown if the module link
"Statistics" is chosen.
        </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
        <para>
            <emphasis>New</emphasis>. Requires rw rights.
        </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
        <para>
            <emphasis>Import</emphasis>. Requires rw rights.
        </para>
    </listitem>
</itemizedlist>
</para>

<section id="stats-overview" >
<title>Overview</title>

<para>
A list of all pre-configured stats the agent can use (see Figure 19.2
below).
</para>

<para>
The easiest way to access the overview is to select the "Statistics" link
and then the action link "Overview" in the navigation bar. The stats
overview is called up automatically when the module link "Statistics" in the
navigation bar is chosen.
</para>

<para>
<screenshot>
<screeninfo>Overview of the standard statistics</screeninfo> <graphic
fileref="screenshots/stats-overview.png" scale="40"
srccredit="stats-overview - Screenshot" /></screenshot>
</para>

<para>
    <emphasis>Figure 19.2. Overview of the standard statistics.</emphasis>
</para>

<para>
The following information is provided about the stats listed in the
overview:
</para>

<para>
<itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
        <para>
            <emphasis>Stat#</emphasis>. Unique statistic number.
        </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
        <para>
            <emphasis>Title</emphasis>. Title of the statistic.
        </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
        <para>
            <emphasis>Object</emphasis>. Object used for generating the statistic.  In
the case of a static statistic, no object is displayed as no dynamic object
is used for its generation.
        </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
        <para>
            <emphasis>Description</emphasis>. Excerpt of the statistic's description.
        </para>
    </listitem>
</itemizedlist>
</para>

<para>
Below the list of statistics, there is a results display, which provides
information about the number of accessible stats. If the overview covers
more than one page, the agent can browse through the different pages.
</para>

<para>
The agents can sort the stats ascending or descending, according to their
needs, just by clicking the desired sorting key field of the headline.
</para>

<para>
To generate a statistic, the right one is chosen by clicking the link with
the stat number, which leads to the "View" user interface.
</para>

<para>
A few sample stats are imported when the stats module is used for the first
time.
</para>

</section>

<section id="stats-viewing-generating">
<title>Generate and view stats</title>

<para>
The view user interface is supposed to provide the agent with an overview of
the stat's pre-configuration (see Figure 19.3 below).
</para>

<para>
<screenshot id="stats-view-screenshot" >
<screeninfo>Stat view</screeninfo> <graphic
fileref="screenshots/stats-view.png" scale="40" srccredit="stats-view -
Screenshot" /></screenshot>
</para>

<para>
    <emphasis>Figure 19.3. Viewing a specific statistic.</emphasis>
</para>

<para>
The agents can perform configurations within the range of the
pre-configuration. The originator of a stat configuration can determine the
degree to which the stat generation can be influenced. The most extreme
examples of this would be agents who can't effect any changes or can change
all attributes, respectively.
</para>

<para>
The page shows the following:
</para>

<para>
<itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
        <para>
        Possible actions:
        </para>

        <para>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    <emphasis>Go to overview</emphasis>.  Link back to the starting point.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    <emphasis>Edit</emphasis>.  Edit the current stat (rw rights required).
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    <emphasis>Delete</emphasis>.  Delete the current stat (rw rights required).
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    <emphasis>Export config</emphasis>.  Export a stat configuration, via file
download (rw rights required).
                </para>

                <para>
                    Usage: export and import functions allow for the convenient creation and
testing of stats on test systems and subsequent easy integration into the
production system.
                </para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
        <para>
        The stat details:
        </para>
        <para>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    <emphasis>Stat#</emphasis>.  The number of the statistic.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    <emphasis>Title</emphasis>.  The title of the statistic.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    <emphasis>Object</emphasis>.  Object used for generating the stat.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    <emphasis>Description</emphasis>.  Provides more detailed information about
the intention of the stat.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    <emphasis>Format</emphasis>.  Stat output format. Depending on the
configuration, any of the following output formats can be chosen:
                </para>
                <para>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>
                        CSV.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>
                        Print.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>
                        Graph-lines.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>
                        Graph-bars.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>
                        Graph-hbars.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>
                        Graph-points.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>
                        Graph-lines-points.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>
                        Graph-area.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>
                        Graph-pie.
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    <emphasis>Graphsize</emphasis>.  Size (in pixels) which the graphic / chart
may have.  This option is only given when the stat pre-configuration allows
it for a chart. All generally usable graphic sizes are configured by the
OTRS admin in the SysConfig. The agent can then pre-select all relevant
formats, while configuring the stats.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    <emphasis>Sum rows</emphasis>.  Indicates whether the stat is amended by a
column, whose cells state the sums of the respective rows.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    <emphasis>Sum columns</emphasis>.  Indicates whether the stat is amended by
a row, whose cells state the sum of the respective columns.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    <emphasis>Cache</emphasis>.  Indicates whether the generated stats are
cached in the file system.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    <emphasis>Valid</emphasis>.  This is set to "invalid" if a pre-configured
statistic is still being created or must not be used temporarily for certain
reasons. Also the "Start" button in the bottom right of the block is then no
longer displayed. The stat can no longer be generated.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    <emphasis>Created</emphasis>.  Creation time of the stat.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    <emphasis>Created by</emphasis>.  Agent who created the stat.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    <emphasis>Changed</emphasis>.  Time of the last stat's modification.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    <emphasis>Changed by</emphasis>.  Agent who altered the stat.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    <emphasis>X-axis</emphasis>.  Using this function, the agent can exchange
the x and y axes (only when activated by the OTRS administrator).
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                The general information is followed by information about the stat
itself. There are two different stat views:
                </para>
                <para>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>
                            <emphasis>Static stat view</emphasis>.  Complex stats cannot be generated
dynamically, that is the reason why static stat generators can be integrated
into the stat module (see Figure 19.4 below).  They were developed
specifically for the particular evaluation.  The various job definitions
result in different views.
                        </para>
                        <para>
                        <screenshot>
<screeninfo>Static stat view</screeninfo> <graphic
fileref="screenshots/stats-view-static.png" scale="40"
srccredit="stats-view-static - Screenshot" /></screenshot>
                        </para>
                        <para>
                            <emphasis>Figure 19.4. Viewing a static statistic.</emphasis>
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>
                            <emphasis>Dinamic stat view</emphasis> (see Figure 19.3 above).  They can be
displayed in two different ways:
                        </para>
                        <para>
                        <itemizedlist>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>
                                    <emphasis>Unchangeable settings</emphasis>.  The originator of the stat has
no permission for modifying this fields.
                                </para>
                            </listitem>
                            <listitem>
                                <para>
                                    <emphasis>Changeable settings</emphasis>.  The pre-configuration of such
stats can be changed by the agent.
                                </para>
                            </listitem>
                        </itemizedlist>
                        </para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
                </para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        </para>
    </listitem>
</itemizedlist>
</para>

<para>
Pressing the "Start" button (at the bottom of the screen) is the last simple
step to generate a stat. There are two possible reasons for this button to
not be displayed:
</para>

<para>
<orderedlist numeration="arabic" >
    <listitem>
        <para>
        The stat was set to invalid and thus, deactivated.
        </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
        <para>
        The stat was not configured neatly and is, therefore, not yet executable. In
this case, the necessary information can be found in the OTRS notification
section (below the navigation bar).
        </para>
    </listitem>
</orderedlist>
</para>

<para>
If the settings on the view page are incorrect, this page is shown again
after the "Start" button was pushed, and information about which input was
incorrect is provided in the notification section.
</para>
</section>

<section id="stats-modify-new">
<title>Edit - New</title>

<para>
Agents, who have write rights, can edit an existing stat configuration by
calling up the edit user interface of the stat module. There are two
possibilites for that:
</para>

<para>
<orderedlist numeration="arabic">
<listitem>
    <para>
    Via the "Edit" button in the stat view.
    </para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
    <para>
    Via the "New" link in the menu of the Statistics module in the navigation
bar.
    </para>
</listitem>
</orderedlist>
</para>

<para>
The stats are edited with a wizard in four steps:
</para>

<para>
<orderedlist numeration="arabic">
<listitem>
    <para>
    General specifications.
    </para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
    <para>
    Definition of the element for the X-axis.
    </para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
    <para>
    Specification of the value series.
    </para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
    <para>
    Definition of the restrictions to characterize the stat.
    </para>
</listitem>
</orderedlist>
</para>

<para>
Points 2 to 4 are only needed for the generation of dynamic stats. For a
static stat, only the general information (point 1) is required.
</para>

<para>
Information about how to handle the page is provided below the input forms,
on all input user interfaces of the stats module.
</para>

<para>
If incorrect data is entered nevertheless, the previously processed user
interface is displayed again and amended by information about the incorrect
input.  This information can be found in the OTRS notification section. The
next input user interface is only displayed after the form has been filled
out correctly.
</para>

<para>
<orderedlist numeration="arabic" >
<listitem>
    <para>
        <emphasis>General specifications</emphasis>.  It is the first page of the
wizard (see Figure 19.5 below).
    </para>

    <para>
    <screenshot>
<screeninfo>General specifications of the stat</screeninfo> <graphic
fileref="screenshots/stats-edit-general.png" scale="40"
srccredit="stats-edit-general - Screenshot" /></screenshot>
    </para>

    <para>
        <emphasis>Figure 19.5. Editing the general specifications of a
stat.</emphasis>
    </para>


    <para>
        In the screen showed in the Figure 19.5 there is a great number of common
specifications and settings can be edited:
    </para>

    <para>
    <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para>
                <emphasis>Title</emphasis>.  Should reflect the stat's purpose in a concise
manner.
            </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>
                <emphasis>Description</emphasis>.  More detailed information about the job
definition, type of configuration parameters, etc.
            </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>
                <emphasis>Dynamic object</emphasis>.  If the OTRS installation provides
various dynamic objects, one of them can be chosen.  The objects meet the
requirements of the particular modules.
            </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>
                <emphasis>Static file</emphasis>.  Usually this selection is not shown, as
only static files which are not yet assigned to any stats are displayed. If
"Static file" is displayed, however, it is important to tick the option
field and select a generation mode (dynamic with a dynamic object or static
with a file).  If a static file is selected, the input user interfaces 2-4
are not shown as the static file contains all required configurations.
            </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>
                <emphasis>Permission settings</emphasis>.  Facilitate a restriction of the
groups (and therefore, agents) who can later view and generate the
preconfigured stats. Thus the various stats can be allocated to the
different departments and work groups who need them. It is possible to
allocate one stat to various groups.
            </para>

            <para>
                Example 1: The "stats" group was selected. The stat is viewable for all
users having at least ro rights for the "stats" group. As the base
requirement for accessing the view mode of the stat module in the default
configuration is to have ro rights in the "stats" group, all users with
permission to create statistics can view it in this configuration.
            </para>

            <para>
                Example 2: A group named "sales" was selected. All users with ro rights for
the "sales" group can see the stat in the view mode and generate
it. However, the stat will not be shown to other users with permission to
generate stats.
            </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>
                <emphasis>Format</emphasis>.  Output format of the stat.  Depending on the
configuration, one or more of the following formats can be chosen:
            </para>

            <para>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        CSV.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        Print.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        graph-lines.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        graph-bars.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        graph-hbars.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        graph-points.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        graph-lines-points.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        graph-area.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        graph-pie.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
            </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>
                <emphasis>Graphsize</emphasis>.  Select the size (in pixels) the charts
should have. This selection is only necessary if a graphical output format
has been chosen under "Format".  All graphic sizes that can generally be
used are defined by the OTRS admin in SysConfig. When configuring the stat,
the agent can pre-select all relevant formats.
            </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>
                <emphasis>Sum rows</emphasis>.  Indicates whether the stat is amended by a
column, whose cells contain the sum of the respective row.
            </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>
                <emphasis>Sum columns</emphasis>.  Indicates whether the stat is amended by
a row, whose cells contain the sum of the respective column.
            </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>
                <emphasis>Cache</emphasis>.  Specifies if the generated stats should be
cached in the file system.  This saves computing power and time if the stat
is called up again, but it only should be used if the stat's content is no
longer changing.
            </para>

            <para>
                Caching is automatically prevented if the stat contains no time designation
values (new data is added continuously) or if a time designation value
points to the future.
            </para>

            <para>
                If a cached stat is edited, all cached data is deleted.
            </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>
                <emphasis>Valid</emphasis>.  It is set "invalid" if a pre-configured stat is
still being created or must not be used temporarily for certain
reasons. Also the "Start" button in the bottom right of the block is no
longer displayed. It is impossible to generate the stat.
            </para>
        </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    </para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
    <para>
        <emphasis>Definition of the element for the X-axis</emphasis>.  It is the
configuration of the element used for the depiction of the X-axis or, if
tables are used, of the column name chosen for the stat (see Figure 19.6).
    </para>

    <para>
    <screenshot>
<screeninfo>Definition of the element for the X-axis.</screeninfo> <graphic
fileref="screenshots/stats-edit-xaxis.png" scale="40"
srccredit="stats-edit-xaxis - Screenshot" /></screenshot>
    </para>

    <para>
        <emphasis>Figure 19.6. Definition of the element for the X-axis.</emphasis>
    </para>

    <para>
    First of all, an element is selected using the option field. Then two or
more attributes of the element must be selected. If no attributes are
selected, all attributes are used including those added after the
configuration of the stat.
    </para>

    <para>
    If the "Fixed" setting is disabled, the agent generating the stat can change
the attributes of the respective element in the "View" user interface.
    </para>

    <para>
    Time elements are different as time period and scale have to be stated.
Type and number of elements result from the used dynamic object and vary
depending on it.
    </para>

    <para>
    If all input is correct, the "Next" button leads to the "Value series"
form. It is also possible to go back to editing the "common statements"
section again.
    </para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
    <para>
        <emphasis>Specification of the value series</emphasis>.
    </para>

    <para>
    In the third step of the stat pre-configuration the value series are defined
(see Figure 19.7 below). They will lateron form the individual graphs of a
diagramm or the various series (tabular view).
    </para>

    <para>
    <screenshot>
<screeninfo>Definition of the value series</screeninfo> <graphic
fileref="screenshots/stats-edit-valueseries.png" scale="40"
srccredit="stats-edit-valueseries - Screenshot" /></screenshot>
    </para>

    <para>
        <emphasis>Figure 19.7. Definition of the value series.</emphasis>
    </para>

    <para>
    If an element is selected, each chosen attribute will correspond to a value
series (see the Example 19-1 below).
    </para>

    <para>
    <example id="stats-value-series-1">
    <title>Definition of a value series - one element</title>

    <para>
    Element Queue:
    </para>

    <para>
    <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para>
            Value series 1 = Raw
            </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>
            Value series 2 = Junk
            </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>
            ....
            </para>
        </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    </para>
    </example>
    </para>

    <para>
    If two elements are selected, each selected attribute of the first element
is combined with an attribute of the second element to form a value series
(see the Example 19-2 below).
    </para>

    <para>
    <example id="stats-value-series-2" >
    <title>Definition of a value series - two elements </title>

    <para>
    Element 1 queue and element 2 status:
    </para>

    <para>
    <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para>
            Value chain 1 = Raw - open
            </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>
            Value series 2 = Raw - successfully closed
            </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>
            Value series 3 = Junk - open
            </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>
            Value series 4 = Junk - successfully closed
            </para>
        </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    </para>
    </example>
    </para>

    <para>
    Selection of three or more elements does not make sense and is, therefore,
prevented by an error message.
    </para>

    <para>
    Additionally the same conditions apply to the selection of the attributes
and the "Fixed" checkbox as to the "X-axis" selection:
    </para>

    <para>
    <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
            <para>
            If no attributes of the element are selected, all attributes are used,
including those added after the configuration of the stat.
            </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
            <para>
            If the "Fixed" setting is disabled, the agent generating the stat can change
the attributes of the respective element.
            </para>
        </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    </para>
</listitem>
<listitem>
    <para>
        <emphasis>Definition of the restrictions to characterize the
stat</emphasis>.  It is the fourth and last step of the pre-configuration
(see Figure 19.8 below).  The restrictions facilitate to limit the results
and are comparable to entering data into a search window. In quite a few
cases, no restrictions at all must be set up.
    </para>

    <para>
    <screenshot>
<screeninfo>Definition of restrictions</screeninfo> <graphic
fileref="screenshots/stats-edit-restrictions.png" scale="40"
srccredit="stats-edit-restrictions - Screenshot" /></screenshot>
    </para>

    <para>
        <emphasis>Figure 19.8. Definition of restrictions.</emphasis>
    </para>

    <para>
    After all restrictions are set, the pre-configuration of the stat is
finished with the "Finish" button and the "View" user interface is called
up.
    </para>
</listitem>
</orderedlist>
</para>
</section>

<section id="stats-import">
<title>Import</title>

<para>
The import user interface (see Figure 19.9 below) can be accessed by chosing
"Import" in the navigation bar (rw rights required).
</para>

<para>
<screenshot>
<screeninfo>The import user interface</screeninfo> <graphic
fileref="screenshots/stats-import.png" scale="40" srccredit="stats-import -
Screenshot" /></screenshot>
</para>

<para>
    <emphasis>Figure 19.9. The import user interface.</emphasis>
</para>

<para>
Facilitates the import of stats and is, combined with the export function of
the module, a very handy functionality. Stats can be created and tested
conveniently on test systems and then imported into the production system.
</para>

<para>
The import is effected by an easy file upload. The "view" user interface of
the imported stat is opened automatically afterwards.
</para>
</section>

</section>

<section id="stats-managing-the-module">
<title>Administration of the stat module by the OTRS administrator</title>

<para>
This section provides information about the tasks and possibilities of the
OTRS administrator dealing with the statistics module.
</para>

<section id="stats-permissions" >
<title>Permission settings, groups and queues</title>

<para>
No new queues and/or groups are created when the stat module is installed.
</para>

<para>
The default configuration of the module registration gives all agents with
"stats" group permissions access to the stats module.
</para>

<para>
Access according to permission settings:
</para>

<para>
<itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
        <para>
            <emphasis>rw</emphasis>.  Allows configurating statistics.
        </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
        <para>
            <emphasis>ro</emphasis>.  Permits generating pre-configured statistics.
        </para>
    </listitem>
</itemizedlist>
</para>

<para>
The OTRS administrator decides whether agents with the permission to
generate pre-configured stats are allocated ro rights in the "stats" group,
or if their respective groups are added in the module registration in
SysConfig.
</para>
</section>

<section id="stats-sysconfig" >
<title>SysConfig</title>

<para>
SysConfig groups <link linkend="Framework:Core::Stats" >
Framework:Core::Stats </link> , <link linkend="Framework:Core::Stats::Graph"
> Framework:Core::Stats::Graph </link>and <link
linkend="Framework:Frontend::Agent::Stats" >
Framework:Frontend::Agent::Stats </link> contain all configuration
parameters for the basic set-up of the statistics module.  Moreover, the
configuration parameter <link
linkend="Framework:Frontend::Agent::ModuleRegistration:Frontend::Module_AgentStats"
> $Self-&gt;{'Frontend::Module'}-&gt;{'AgentStats'} </link> controls the
arrangement and registration of the modules and icons within the statistics
module.
</para>
</section>

</section>

<section id="stats-managing-the-stats-module-by-the-sysadmin" >
<title>Administration of the stats module by the system administrator</title>

<para>
Generally, no system administrator is needed for the operation,
configuration and maintenance of the statistics module. However, a little
background information for the system administrator is given at this point.
</para>

<note>
<para>
File paths refer to subdirectories of the OTRS home directory (in most
cases<filename>/opt/otrs</filename>).
</para>
</note>

<section id="stats-db-table" >
<title>Data base table</title>

<para>
All stat configurations are implemented and administrated in XML and,
therefore, stored in the database table "xml_storage". Other modules whose
content is presented in xml format use this table as well.
</para>

</section>

<section id="stats-filelist" >
<title>List of all files</title>

<para>
The following files are necessary for the stats module to work accurately:
</para>

<para>
<itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
        <para>
        <filename>Kernel/System/Stats.pm</filename>
        </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
        <para>
        <filename>Kernel/Modules/AgentStats.pm</filename>
        </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
        <para>
        <filename>Kernel/System/CSV.pm</filename>
        </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
        <para>
        <filename>Kernel/Output/HTML/Standard/AgentStatsOverview.dtl</filename>
        </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
        <para>
        <filename>Kernel/Output/HTML/Standard/AgentStatsDelete.dtl</filename>
        </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
        <para>
        <filename>Kernel/Output/HTML/Standard/AgentStatsEditSpecification.dtl</filename>
        </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
        <para>
        <filename>Kernel/Output/HTML/Standard/AgentStatsEditRestrictions.dtl</filename>
        </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
        <para>
        <filename>Kernel/Output/HTML/Standard/AgentStatsEditXaxis.dtl</filename>
        </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
        <para>
        <filename>Kernel/Output/HTML/Standard/AgentStatsEditValueSeries.dtl</filename>
        </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
        <para>
        <filename>Kernel/Output/HTML/Standard/AgentStatsImport.dtl</filename>
        </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
        <para>
        <filename>Kernel/Output/HTML/Standard/AgentStatsPrint.dtl</filename>
        </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
        <para>
        <filename>Kernel/Output/HTML/Standard/AgentStatsView.dtl</filename>
        </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
        <para>
        <filename>Kernel/System/Stats/Dynamic/Ticket.pm</filename>
        </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
        <para>
        <filename>bin/otrs.GenerateStats.pl</filename>
        </para>
    </listitem>
</itemizedlist>
</para>
</section>

<section id="stats-caching" >
<title>Caching</title>

<para>
Whether the results of a statistic are to be cached or not can be defined in
the pre-configuration. Cached statistic results are stored as files in the
<filename>var/tmp</filename>directory of the OTRS installation (in most
cases<filename>/opt/otrs/var/tmp</filename>).
</para>

<para>
Cached stats can be recognized by the "Stats" prefix.
</para>

<para>
If the data is lost, no major damage is caused. The next time the stat is
called up, the stats module will not find the file any more and thus, will
generate a new stat, which will probably take a little longer.
</para>
</section>

<section id="stats-mkstats" >
<title>otrs.GenerateStats.pl</title>

<para>
This file is saved in the <filename>bin/</filename>directory.  It
facilitates the generation of stats in the command line.
</para>

<para>
The command line call in the Script 19.1 is an exemplary.
</para>

<para>
<programlisting>
bin> perl otrs.GenerateStats.pl -n 10004 -o /output/dir
</programlisting>
</para>

<para>
    <emphasis>Script 19.1. Generating a stat via command line.</emphasis>
</para>

<para>
A stat from the stat configuration "Stat# 10004" is generated and saved as
csv in the <filename>/output/dir</filename>directory.
</para>

<para>
The generated stat can also be sent as an e-mail.  More information can be
called up with the command of the Script 19.2.
</para>

<para>
<programlisting>
bin> perl otrs.GenerateStats.pl --help
</programlisting>
</para>

<para>
    <emphasis>Script 19.2. Getting information about the otrs.GenerateStats.pl
file.</emphasis>
</para>

</section>

<section id="stats-cron" >
<title>Automated stat generation - Cronjob</title>

<para>
It obviously does not really make sense to generate stats manually in the
command line, as the stat module has a convenient graphical user
interface. However, generating stats manually does make sense when combined
with a Cronjob.
</para>

<para>
Imagine the following scenario: On every first day of the month the heads of
department want to receive a stat for the past month. By combining a cronjob
and command line call the stats can be sent to them automatically by e-mail.
</para>

</section>

<section id="stats-static" >
<title>Static stats</title>

<para>
The stats module facilitates the generation of static statistics. For every
static stat a file exists in which its content is precisely defined.
</para>

<para>
This way, very complex stats can be generated. The disadvantage is that they
are not particularly flexible.
</para>

<para>
The files are saved in the following directory
<filename>Kernel/System/Stats/Static/</filename>.
</para>
</section>

<section id="stats-using-old-stats" >
<title>Using old static stats</title>

<para>
Standard OTRS versions 1.3 and 2.0 already facilitated the generation of
stats.  Various stats for OTRS versions 1.3 and 2.0 which have been
specially developed to meet customers' requirements can be used in more
recent versions too.
</para>

<para>The files must merely be moved from the
<filename>Kernel/System/Stats/</filename> path to
<filename>Kernel/System/Stats/Static/</filename>. Additionally the package
name of the respective script must be amended by "::Static".
</para>

<para>
The following example shows how the first path is amended.
</para>

<para>
<programlisting>
    package Kernel::System::Stats::AccountedTime;
</programlisting>
</para>

<para>
<programlisting>
    package Kernel::System::Stats::Static::AccountedTime;
</programlisting>
</para>
</section>

<section id="stats-default-stats" >
<title>Default stats</title>

<para>"It is not always necessary to reinvent the wheel..."
</para>

<para>
The stats module provides various default stats. Stats which are interesting
for all OTRS users will in future be added to the default stats of the stats
module package. Default stats are saved in the stats module xml format in
the<filename>scripts/test/sample/</filename> directory.
</para>

</section>

</section>

</chapter>
